<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_memoirs_1_of_2_name"> 
		<text>Diary of a Stalker (part 1 of 2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_memoirs_1_of_2_desc">
		<text>Old, faded notebook, wrapped in some kind of cover, so that the pages do not go bad. Nevertheless, the diary is already so spoiled by time that only a part of the text can be parsed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"I have to start recording somewhere, I need to pour out my soul on paper and throw the burden off my shoulders. I hope to leave at least something after my death to those who read this diary. Even though he does not repeat my mistakes. I have almost no friends, and there are no friends in the Zone, and even more so. All these traders look at me like an outcast. This bearded guy on Zatone smiles a sarcastic smile every time he sees me, and a Hawaiian trader constantly mocks me with an unabashed kind. Damn all these bastards, I just need from time to time a little ammunition, food and water from them. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]I decided to write down everything that happened that night so that at least someone would know what I had to go through, so that at least someone could understand why I prefer to always be alone. I came here on my own, but soon I met a newcomer. It turned out that he was very fond of the local mineral rocks. He had a hobby from the Big Earth - to collect stones, and the more he was attracted by the local artifacts - strange stones that flooded the Zone. He, of course, later collected many artifacts, but at the cost of everything was a huge tumor formed in his stomach. Frequent vomiting, diarrhea, constant stress ... He looked like a pregnant woman, but instead of a child in his stomach developed a huge malignant tumor. He even called her after his first pet. Of course, I did not mind. I liked him, we almost became friends. We never contacted the bandits, did not just attack the mutants, we just wander around the anomalies, choosing the most interesting stone formations, and sometimes, when particularly lucky, there were also artifacts ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon cleaning (+ 2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_memoirs_2_of_2_name">
		<text>Diary of a Stalker (part 2 of 2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_memoirs_2_of_2_desc">
		<text>Old, faded notebook, wrapped in some kind of cover, so that the pages do not go bad. Nevertheless, the diary is already so spoiled by time that only a part of the text can be parsed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Once the conversation went about one anomaly, as it turned out, located deep in the cave or a crack in the ground, I do not know what to call. There should have been a huge number of artifacts, but no one wanted to go there with us for some reason. "Panties and fools", - we then thought. Why did not anyone want to get rich and then live an easy life? Then a sudden burst of courage rolled over us, we immediately gathered and went straight to the cave. We did not even have time to look into the cave, as some dark shadow flew over us. I stumbled, hit my head and fainted. After a while I came to myself and heard someone moaning. "Animals", as I thought initially, but then suddenly realized that I was lying and moaning in front of my friend. His skin was torn all over his body, in his bleeding wounds could see all the muscles. He crawled from the cave himself, in consciousness, dragging his guts with him ... It was a miracle that he did not die on the spot. I did not understand anything, I took out my pistol and started shooting towards that cave. I had 20 cartridges for the gun, when I had 7 cartridges, something grabbed my arm. I continued to fire, frantically pressing the trigger. After a moment, the grip weakened, but I kept pulling the trigger even when my ammo ran out. Then I did not even understand what I had just done with my friend. I did not even have the courage to take his things, I just ran. As after that, I could talk with someone or make new acquaintances, when the Zone at any time can repeat its evil joke. It's better to be alone. Friendship has its price and risk. It is not necessary to have a particularly warm friendship, because all this can be lost in a moment. Yes, I realized this from my own experience, I stuffed a bump on my head, which will not let me forget it ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_manual_1_of_2_name">
		<text>Interrogation methods: the basics (part 1 of 2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_manual_1_of_2_desc">
		<text>Training leaflets with a large emblem of "Freedom" in the upper right corner and a small drawing of a pistol and a man on his knees. It is called "Interrogation methods: the basics" and is written in a casual slang grouping. : \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"I should not even mention this, because it's all obvious and so. But in fact, I will share with you, but do not crouch to the right and left, or you will not understand. Throw this leaflet, burn it or give it to someone you trust. You do not want everyone to know about this? After all, you can be yourself once, on the spot of the interrogated one, right? Do you have a cache? So keep these sheets to yourself and do not say later that you were not warned. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Everyone has their own cache. Even the poorest, unfortunate bandit living in the Zone has a stash of a couple of soup-picks in it and a few bullets. Here everything works according to such laws. You collect some money, sell a few artifacts, parts of mutants, rob the dead, but as a rule still warm bodies, buy food and weapons. Even when the shit flies directly to the wind in your face, you are left with a smirk on your face, because you have a trump card in your sleeve that can save your skin. Such are the strict laws of the Zone, no one will help you here ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_manual_2_of_2_name">
		<text>Interrogation methods: the basics (part 2 of 2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_manual_2_of_2_desc">
		<text>Training leaflets with a large emblem of "Freedom" in the upper right corner and a small drawing of a pistol and a man on his knees. It is called "Interrogation methods: the basics" and is written in a casual slang grouping. : \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"But now we will not talk about help from outside and about the relations of stalkers. If you want to get important information about the whereabouts of someone else's hiding place - start with the choice of the victim. When you think of everything, choose a quiet place where there is no one - shoot straight at the hands and feet, deliver as much pain as possible until they realize that you are their closest friend at the moment. And then they will throw the weapon and kneel before you. Talk to them firmly and convincingly, but do not kill, after all in the district and so many mutants - they will finish this job for you. Do not make the Zone worse.. Say that you will go away, scare them as hard as possible, make them understand that the end is already near. They usually understand this and surrender ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stalker_letter_1_of_2_name">
		<text>Memoir (part 1 of 2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stalker_letter_1_of_2_desc">
		<text>A couple of pages torn from someone's memoirs. The manuscript is in blue ink, which is almost blurred from the influence of the environment, which makes the text almost unreadable. author unknown. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"I still feel the warmth of that anomaly in my back. It burns even when I just sit on Skadovsk, in a safe place, away from dangers and from all fucking heating devices. You do not even know what I'm going through every time, approaching these fucking anomalies. Hell, my back burns even more, now it's my anomaly detector. After getting into a burning or acid anomaly with simple burns, you will not get off. It's like you took the part of the Zone forever inside of you. "Under the sign of the Zone," so I call it. Horror, no physical law acts in the Zone. I just do not know what to expect from the local anomalies. I can easily overcome a dozen bloodsuckers on a dark night, but each time I just get lost at the sight of an anomaly ... Is that possible? This in general, can not be a reality at all! I do not cease to think that this whole Zone is a single, unearthly nightmare that is repeated over and over again ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stalker_letter_2_of_2_name">
		<text>Memoir (part 2 of 2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stalker_letter_2_of_2_desc">
		<text>A couple of pages torn from someone's memoirs. The manuscript is in blue ink, which is almost blurred from the influence of the environment, which makes the text almost unreadable. author unknown. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Every time I think about it, my back trembles with pain and turns into a single red ball. I for the last 4 months and did not come close to these anomalies, I make a living killing mutants. But on this you will not last long, and the back still reacts, as if she has her own mind. Sometimes I feel sorry that I have not left this burning hell. Maybe it would have been more beneficial for me if I had become food to those boars. Although no ... Boars are stupid creatures. But if they attack the same Skadovsk, it will fall in a few days. They will not be stopped by bullets. Boars are generally useless creatures, their meat is terrible, even an experienced cook can not make it edible. Sometimes I choose to wander around Zaton, my back can barely endure a backpack. I go there, because it always seems to me that I left something there, that calls me from time to time. Because of these terrible pains in the back, I have to sleep on my stomach or on my side. I do not like sleeping on my side, I do not sleep well. The zone changes us without asking permission ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecologist_report_1_of_3_name">
		<text>Information on "zombified humans", report 39B amend.2 (part 1 of 3)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecologist_report_1_of_3_desc">
		<text>Text typed on a typewriter with reference to belonging to the Environmental Study Group, judging by the stamps and emblems. It is classified as strictly confidential and signed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Arkady Tsvetkovsky \n %c[0,170,170,170]Junior researcher of the laboratory and research bunker RX12 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Extracted information about walking dead , report 39B Amendment. 2 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Date: 19. 03. 2014 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Folder: 34 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Page: 1 of 3 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Zombie" - this is the term used by the local population when it comes to the samples of half-living creatures , which can hardly be called reasonable. Scientific evidence has shown that their brain does not conduct any thought processes and the neurological activity of the brain structure is practically absent, which confirms the death of brain cells to a critical level. However, field trials have proven that, for reasons unknown to science, their necrotic brain is capable of giving out impulses for simple mechanical reactions (something reminiscent of instincts, but with a significant difference in the logic of behavior). According to one version, this is due to the result of endless neurochemical reactions in the body that cause the body to move in a certain way in response to certain specific stimuli. When they are threatened by something, they demonstrate extremely aggressive behavior, so it is better to approach them with great caution. The tests showed that their physiology is so changed that the tissues are able to independently maintain a neural connection, t. e. even separated from the body parts can function independently without getting any nutrients for energy production. One of the most successful of such experiments is the maintenance of the ability of the liver and heart for 3 months without binding and connections with other organs and blood circulation. Further analyzes will be able to suggest molecular and subatomic characteristics. \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]research paper \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecologist_report_2_of_3_name">
		<text>Information on "zombified humans", report 39B amend.2 (part 2 of 3)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecologist_report_2_of_3_desc">
		<text>Text typed on a typewriter with reference to belonging to the Environmental Study Group, judging by the stamps and emblems. It is classified as strictly confidential and signed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Arkady Tsvetkovsky \n %c[0,170,170,170]Junior researcher of the laboratory and research bunker RX12 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Extracted information about walking dead , report 39B Amendment. 2 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Date: 19. 03. 2014 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Folder: 34 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Page: 2 of 3 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]The results we obtained will help to explain the riddle of the fact that, being repeatedly injured in the limb, in the pelvic region, peripheral organs and other areas, they are able to function endlessly, without undergoing special difficulties. Moving them is usually difficult, there is no question of doing anything, but the reflexes of handling weapons and pulling the trigger remained unchanged. Quite possibly, this also applies to the use of other simple tools and technological devices. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]You should not use the terms "kill" and "destroy" when dealing with deactivated samples. This is more rational from a psychological point of view, because the term "decontamination" is more neutral than "destruction", thus you can avoid stress on the psyche and suppress a sense of repentance. The decontamination of the sample requires the interruption of the connections of the brain to the musculoskeletal apparatus, which is preferable to a ballistic trauma in the region of the brain or spinal cord. Each member of the scientific team should bear in mind that their limbs remain functional even after the deactivation of the sample, therefore additional safety measures should be taken. More effective is the removal of the vertebrae or brainstem by surgical intervention. \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]research paper \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecologist_report_3_of_3_name">
		<text>Information on "zombified humans", report 39B amend.2 (part 3 of 3)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecologist_report_3_of_3_desc">
		<text>Text typed on a typewriter with reference to belonging to the Environmental Study Group, judging by the stamps and emblems. It is classified as strictly confidential and signed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Arkady Tsvetkovsky \n %c[0,170,170,170]Junior researcher of the laboratory and research bunker RX12 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Extracted information about walking dead , report 39B Amendment. 2 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Date: 19. 03. 2014 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Folder: 34 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Page: 3 of 3 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]In extremely rare cases, the behavior of some "zombie" individuals resembles the behavior of more intelligent animals: they throw weapons or refuse to manifest aggression in general. These samples are of the greatest importance for research, therefore it is undesirable to deactivate them. The capture of individuals and further analysis in laboratories is of paramount importance. The most interested party in this kind of research is neuropsychologists in connection with the potential of brain stem research and its transplantation. Theoretically, this could help patients in the late stages of Alzheimer's disease and other complex diseases. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]If possible, avoid damage to the kidneys and heart during decontamination. These bodies have a huge potential for research in the field of transplantation to other viable organisms. Collecting organs from dead "zombies" is also possible, but caution is needed, as local stalkers can have emotional connections with some specimens. If a meeting with stalkers is inevitable, then you can take two options to avoid a military encounter. First, when working in a group with a novice stalker, one should not cut out the eyes of the sample - it is elementary inhumanely. Secondly, when working in a group with a veteran stalker, it is better to motivate him with something, since they restrain emotions more restrainedly. Moreover, when working with the local human population, one can also draw some conclusions on psychological examinations. \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]research paper \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_prayer_1_of_3_name">
		<text>Prayer for "Monolith" (part 1 of 3)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_prayer_1_of_3_desc">
		<text>A document without a specific name, containing several paragraphs under each other. Frequent references to the Monolith indicate the religious character of the written text. The document is well preserved, which shows the care in the compilation and careful attitude in the future. The text of the prayer reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]We pray to you!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Our only light in the dark \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Hope thou inspires us into our hearts! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We go forward on the infidels to you! \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]O Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Forgive our sins!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Show us our destiny!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Give us the power to reach our goals! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Give hope to crush your enemies! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Ozari your light with us! \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We beg of you! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We are your descendants! \n %c[0,170,170,170]O Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Our only hope for redemption!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Your name is in our hearts! "\n \n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1% )</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_prayer_2_of_3_name">
		<text>Prayer for "Monolith" (part 2 of 3)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_prayer_2_of_3_desc">
		<text>A document without a specific name, containing several paragraphs each under the other. Frequent references to the Monolith indicate the religious character of the written text. The document is well preserved, which shows the care in the compilation and careful attitude in the future. The text of the prayer reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Warriors of the monolith, stop!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith, light us the way!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Take our souls, our minds \n %c[0,170,170,170]And cleanse them! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Spare them of doubt and hesitation! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith, you are our hope! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We are your soldiers forever! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We want to give our lives for you \n %c[0,170,170,170]We want to give souls to you \n %c[0,170,170,170]We want to reunite with you! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith, we remove everything from your path! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Take our flesh! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Take our blood! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Take our souls! \n %c[0,1 70,170,170]And revive them again!\n %c[0.170,170,170]You live in us, oh, the Monolith. "\n \n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_prayer_3_of_3_name">
		<text>Prayer for "Monolith" (part 3 of 3)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_prayer_3_of_3_desc">
		<text>A document without a specific name, containing several paragraphs each under the other. Frequent references to the Monolith indicate the religious character of the written text. The document is well preserved, which shows the care in the compilation and careful attitude in the future. The text of the prayer reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]You are our destiny.\n %c[0,140,140,140]And we are all brothers.\n %c[0,140,140,140]We are brothers of the light of the Monolith. \n %c[0,140,140,140]We will give up our lives for our cause. \n %c[0,140,140,140]We will perish in the name of yours. \n %c[0,140,140,140]We will die under Your Light. \n %c[0,140,140,140]Death is only the beginning.\n %c[0,140,140,140]We go with your name on your lips, O Monolith! "\n \n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140 ]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolithian_thoughts_name">
		<text>Diary of a Monolithian</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolithian_thoughts_desc">
		<text>Handwritten sheet of paper. At the beginning of the text, the style of writing is extremely chaotic and untidy, as if the person writing this suffered from a severe mental disorder. The most interesting is that the following text becomes clearer, more vividly narrated by the end of the text of the diary is almost perfect. The note says: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"As far as I remember now, there was a darkness around me, I could not see anything. Nothing ... Even time. But suddenly a light appeared before me! The light is so bright, so cozy ... I wanted to touch it, I wanted to feel it. I understood, I realized that he was trying to help me, trying to save me. I knew ... \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]And after I touched the light, I forgot about everything. There was no past life - behind me was pitch darkness. The only light source was in front of me. His name was Monolith. He saved me, and I am infinitely grateful to him for it. Sometimes in front of me there are faces, faces from the past ... A woman and a child ... My family? I'm dressed in a white overall ... Maybe I was a scientist ... What a strange word ... Radar ... NO! There there is darkness?! She wants me to die! I will not let myself be killed! No, there is no turning back! Only forward, only to the light! To the light! For the Monolith! ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_to_outside_name">
		<text>Natalie's letter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_to_outside_desc">
		<text>A letter written by one of the stalkers to someone outside the Exclusion Zone, most likely a wife or mistress. The fact that the letter fell into your hands proves that it will never reach its intended recipient. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Hello, Natalie! \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]How are you? Like children? Tell Sashka that if he does not obey, I will spank him well when I get home.. What about me? Well, I do not think you'll understand me now.. But listen: The zone ... This place ... Unique. Only here I can feel connected with other people. Only here I see people as they really are. There are no masks, only a harsh truth. I'll tell you everything more colorful later, when I meet. I've earned good money here! We can finally buy you the necklace that you so long wanted. Yes, and thank you for writing me, do not forget me. Your letters really help me and raise my spirits even in the harshest times. When I think about you, the world becomes much easier. See you soon. Tell the children hello from me!\n \n %c[0.170,170,170]With a lot of love, your Michael. Your brave stalker". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_military_stalker_name">
		<text>Note by a military Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_military_stalker_desc">
		<text>A note found among the garbage. It is difficult to determine what it was written for, most likely someone was killing time, passing the tiring dark night, and then just forgot to throw their works into the fire. The text of the note reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Oh yeah. I'm a military stalker. It's straight from a series of something incredible! The best equipment. The most urgent tasks. The best weapon. Best of all! Finally, we managed to establish a truce between the military and stalkers. We must not shoot at each other! We are all Slavs, that's why we all have to stick together. Well, except marauders, they just want to shoot a bullet right between their eyes! Although I am new to the whole team, but I feel that I have become a real man - strong and courageous, and it's great. "\n \n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[ 0.140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_mercenary_name">
		<text>Note by a mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_mercenary_desc">
		<text>A note written by one of the mercenaries. It looks like he decided to write down some thoughts about his activities in the Zone. His intentions are incomprehensible. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Well, in general, what I see here does not represent anything special. We are all the same mercenaries, we are still the same soldiers of fortune. Nevertheless, we can spontaneously choose what we do, and what we should not do. Sometimes we do not even accept applications for work, because it is too "dirty" even for us. If a client wants to kill several good people who honestly earn their living by shedding sweat and blood - forget about this bastard, in the Zone, such problems can be solved without us, the same marauders and bandits - bastards are missing! But when you need to protect someone - this is another matter! So, if you need someone to kill, - address the rags. They are not so legible in murders. We are others. Keep this in mind the next time you poke your money in our face ". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_military_log_name">
		<text>Report on operation MSRC / 04/05/2014 18:36:21</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_military_log_desc">
		<text>The printed part of the transmission of radio signals between the military units located in the Zone. The fact that this document was found among the crew of the SKAT indicates that it should have been involved in underground fraud in order to obtain surveillance data. It indicates: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]«- HQ, this is MSSRC 1-03. We obtained photos from the research institute, as well as 240 photographs of the abnormal swamp, about 1400 photographs of the central base. When should we return?\n %c[0,170,170,170]- MSRC 1-03, this is HQ. Return is not possible at this time. There are some problems in military warehouses. MSRC 4-07 requests help. Once again, however, their SOS signal is very strong for now, we hope that they are still alive. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- This is HQ. Send the helicopter. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Not at all. Now there is too much anomalous activity at the Research Institute "Agroprom", too dangerous. Move to Yantar, our MI-24 will take you from there. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Roger. Is there any information about the next release?\n %c[0,170,170,170]- So exactly. Sakharov says that there are still two days before the next activity. But still hurry, their information should not be based on, unreliable. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- I understand you. We are advancing, tell Bird to be at Yantar at 7 o'clock. MSRC 1-03, end of communication. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Wait, 1-03. And what about the N-2 tunnel? Have you found anything there?\n %c[0,170,170,170]- So exactly. We found in it a new anomaly. It looks like some kind of teleporter. Should be of interest to those eggheads on Yantar, our electronics died out when we approached it for measuring psi fields. I can not understand where did such strong electronic waves come from. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Roger, MSRC 1-03. Good luck on the way to Amber. The helicopter will be by 7 o'clock. HQ, end of communication ». \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]military item \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_stalker_letter_3_name">
		<text>Letter to Nikolai</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_letter_stalker_letter_3_desc">
		<text>A handwritten letter addressed to Nikolai. Most likely part of the correspondence between two stalkers. Although the correspondence in the Zone is conducted mainly with the help of the CCP, many stalkers prefer traditional letters, especially on personal issues. These letters are then sent to the couriers who deliver them to the Zone. Most often the letter reaches the addressee in a few days - the probability of interception of such a message is much lower than that of the PDA. The courier profession is widely valued among stalkers. The letter says: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Nikolai, \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]I just returned from the walk to the center of the Zone. Oh, it was just hell! "Monolith" and the warriors try to wipe each other from the face of the earth. There are moments of calm when it seems that they have concluded a ceasefire agreement, but in fact there is no agreement. Constant chaos and destruction, I had no choice but to get out of there. I was almost killed by freaking fanatics, but it's generally my fault, I just lost my vigilance. Anyway, I came to Pripyat, I plan to stay here for a while. So we will have to postpone our mission previously discussed until it is safer. I really do not sleep after I came here, but I feel very good. Keep in touch. \n\n %c[0.170,170,170]Take care of yourself, Ryuk". \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]personal belongings \n %c[255,238,153,26]• %c[0,140,140,140]usable for: %c[0,170,170,170]weapon maintenance (+ 1%)</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_dok_1_name">
		<text>Folder with documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dok_1_desc">
		<text>Technical documentation containing information about the experiments, their results, observations of the experimental and other. Obtained in abandoned laboratories, the network of which is scattered throughout the Zone. The data available in the documents do not represent a benefit for an ordinary digger, but are a valuable source of information for traders and scientists. \n\nMost often, the data contained in documents is encrypted, which prevents them from being used by an ordinary person, but there are often specimens written in ordinary handwritten font - such documents stalkers scan using a PDA, leaving a digital copy of the document. \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]secret document \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]valuable \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]informative</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dok_2_name">
		<text>Sheet of paper with records</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dok_2_desc">
		<text>A crumpled sheet of paper with large yellow divorces from some liquid. Judging by the content, it is part of the old laboratory documentation. Such scraps can be found in abandoned laboratories, the network of which is scattered throughout the Zone. Overhand a lot of strange notes and signatures are written. The status of the document is unlikely to allow him to get good money for him, but enough for a jar of samogon.\n \n %c[0,140,140,140]CHARACTERISTICS: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]secret document \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]informative</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_box_lab_1_name">
		<text>Box of scientific equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_box_lab_1_desc">
		<text>Sturdy box with scientific equipment, in large quantities taken out of the network of abandoned laboratories within the Exclusion Zone. The equipment for stalkers does not represent practical value, but it can be sold for a large amount to scientists or other interested parties, for the purpose of which it is pulled out from laboratories. \n\n %c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES: \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]high quality \n %c[0,153,255,255]• %c[0,140,140,140]valuable</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
