<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>


	<string id="encyclopedia_survival"> 
		<text>Survival</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_equipement">
		<text>Equipment</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_equipement_text">
		<text>Knives are divided into classes. The simplest is not to cut mutants with a thick hide, such as a wild boar. Knives have the property of deteriorating from cutting carcasses and combat use. The new ones are inexpensive, and the kits for sharpening them are cheaper. \n\nThe belt is designed for quick access to cartridges and projectiles, with the ability to fasten modules, some parts of mutants and containers with artifacts. Each class of armor initially has limitations on the number of belt slots: jackets, raincoats and lightweight overalls are equipped with 4 slots; medium overalls, heavy assault overalls and heavy armored suits have 5 slots each; scientific suits with a system of closed breathing - all 7 slots, the exception is the "SEVA" overall with 5 slots. Technicians are ready to make a fastening for a new slot on the belt if they have the necessary set of tools. \n\nAmmunition. Regular cartridges are a rare and expensive consumable in the Zone. Acquired from reputable traders and military, rather rare in ordinary stalkers. Appreciate the fact that slightly affect the wear of weapons. The old cartridges come across on a regular basis, are cheaper, but their use has a bad effect on weapon wear. The bullets of such cartridges have the same damaging properties as in conventional cartridges.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_radiation">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_radiation_text">
		<text>Being in the radiation contamination zone without proper protection, the transfer of the radioactive artifact outside the container, as well as the use of products with a radiation background exceeding the norm, inflict damage on the body, which in the future can lead to a fatal outcome. To remove the effect of radiation exposure, anti-radiation drugs, scientific first-aid kits, survival kits and alcohol-containing liquids are used. Radiation has the property of accumulating in the body, but a low level of radiation is harmless. To monitor the exposure dose of radiation received by the device (and to those who use it) a dosimeter is used.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_hunting">
		<text>Hunting</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_hunting_text">
		<text>You can disassemble mutants not only for the sake of selling trophies, but also for food. A portable oven or a multivark and the problem of hunger will no longer be the most terrible. Just know the coal. However, nothing is given for nothing. Meat, cooked even in the best oven, is radioactive dangerous, and fuel takes a precious place in the backpack. Simplify the hunt will help a special hunting kit, which will enable more often cut pieces and meat mutants.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_energy">
		<text>Battery charge</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_energy_text">
		<text>Almost all electronics consume energy and the more it is wound up, the faster the batteries sit down. The PDA almost does not discharge the battery, the detectors of the anomalies "eat" depending on the power and radius of detection of artifacts, the headlamp consumes a charge moderately, and the NVP will last only a couple of hours. "Eternal" only a dosimeter and a hand torch, but except as a pistol or a cold steel with him do not arm themselves. Replenish the energy of the universal charger is possible with the help of batteries or charging it with technicians.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_repair">
		<text>Repairs</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_repair_text">
		<text>In a barn, with a leaky gas mask, a wedging trunk and a penny in his pocket, what to do? Repair yourself. Find or buy repair kits designed for each type of weapon and suit with a helmet. Kits make equipment operational. Conventional industrial tools such as hammers, cloth and shovels are used as auxiliary materials for repairs, as this will slightly increase its efficiency, but it is not worthwhile to start the state of equipment, otherwise you will have to say goodbye to your favorite trunk or lay out a considerable amount of equipment for its repair. \n\nWeapons, due to even a small amount of work experience in conditions of CEOs, can lose their previous battle due to damage to various mechanisms. Repair at once all faults will take only the technician. Damage to one mechanism of weapons is better to correct yourself with the help of straps. For repair of each type of malfunction the concrete set fits: breakage - rem. set, deformation - a set of tools, pollution - cleaning agents.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_craft">
		<text>Creating Items</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_craft_text">
		<text>Tool kits for rough and fine work allow you to make various useful things - from bandage to detector - from improvised materials that can be found in long-abandoned places. This can significantly save money spent on purchasing equipment or repairing it. Each set corresponds to its own list of created items.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_cooking">
		<text>Cooking food</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_cooking_text">
		<text>In the Zone is not rich with organic food. Meat mutants make up most of the stalker's diet. Eating it raw means getting a significant dose of radioactive particles. The preparation of mined meat not only reduces the amount of radioactive particles in it, but also increases the saturation of such food. In Zone conditions, you can prepare food yourself with the help of special portable stoves. Different types of furnaces are suitable for different types of meat, the same applies to fuel for them.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_containers">
		<text>Containers</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_containers_text">
		<text>To carry radioactive artifacts you need a special container that will protect you from harmful radiation. Containers are divided into several types.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_anomalies">
		<text>Abnormal zones</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_anomalies_text">
		<text>One of the dangers encountered in the path of stalkers are the anomalous zones - small areas in which the physical laws. Entry into such zones almost always leads to death or to severe injuries, the strength of the damage depends on the concentration of the anomaly. After the ejection, the abnormal formations produce various kinds of objects with unique properties - artifacts, followed by hunt stalkers. The dimensions of most anomalies do not exceed a few square meters. At the same time, there are very large anomalies - archeanomalies, as a rule, combining the properties of several smaller. Small anomalies occur both singly and in groups that can be quite large and are then called "anomalous fields". It is noted that anomalies arise after ejection and can change their location. Anomalies react to bolts, which are the main means of detecting them. In this case, some anomalies can be "discharged" bolt bolt, while others react only to large objects. Research groups in the Zone managed to develop detectors that determine almost all types of anomalous formations, but such a detector will cost a pretty penny.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_weight">
		<text>Transportable weight</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_weight_text">
		<text>Man is not a truck, and can not carry a ton on him. The more it carries, the more fatigue and the faster it loses its strength. The speed of movement also depends on the weight of the equipment. In the end, if things are too much, it will be difficult to move.</text>
	</string>
	

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae">
		<text>Characters</text>
	</string>


	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_comms">
		<text>Groupings</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_comms_text">
		<text>Military \nSoldiers who have passed special service training after the service experience in the Zone, or stalkers who signed a contract with the army. Provided with a large number of auxiliary equipment, well armed and equipped. They are mainly used to study the causes and consequences of a disaster, and also are engaged in mapping the Zone. They mostly walk in groups of five. Ordinary stalkers to themselves are not allowed - they immediately open fire. \n\nKhorunzhy walked and felt Melekhov's heavy glance on the back of his head.. And though the major told the young starlet that Khorunzhiy of his own, from military stalkers, he still did not trust him. Or, perhaps, they met earlier, back when Khorunzhim was a free walker to the Zone? Stalker even looked back, once again looking at the lieutenant's face. Yes, no, like, did not meet. \n... \n\nBandits \nRepresentatives of the criminal world who came to the Zone for various reasons: to earn on the sale of artifacts, hide from the law, buy or sell weapons. In the Zone there is a lot of such an element level from punks to serious criminals. Most of them are united in gangs. Although there is still no single gangster organization in the Zone, they are very annoying to ordinary stalkers. \n\nHe flew at them just as they were rummaging through his partner's pockets. Three sat at the backpack of the victim and shared the prey, one more swarmed in his pockets. The blood struck the stalker in the head, blinding him, and he opened fire to defeat. The ammunition is the currency of the Zone, but he did not spare it, lavishly handing out gifts to murderers and marauders. \n... \n\nSingles \nStalkers exploring the Zone alone. Such a majority, as membership in the group selects precious time, thereby reducing earnings; In addition, some are simply by nature inclined to loneliness and independence. \n\nBasically, singles die in the Zone, can not be here alone. But in any rule there are exceptions. The eel was just such an exception. He had already stalkered for two years, but he did not join any of the clans, preferring to be the master of himself. At the same time, it could not be overtaken by bandits, monsters, special forces, or the Zone itself. \n... \n\n"Monolith" \nOdious grouping, located in the center of the Zone and not allowing anyone. "Monolith" shows an intense hostility towards all other stalkers, both loners and representatives of various groups. They are few-sided, do not make any contacts or compromises, are distinguished by fanatical adherence to what is in the center of the Zone. It is not known what they believe this "something", but their worship has already become practically a cult-religious rite, mandatory for all members of the grouping. But, surprisingly, this commitment is not in the form of an order, but is voluntarily accepted by all monoliths. The remaining stalkers prefer not to deal with these "religious fanatics", as they are commonly called. They believe the monoliths are limited and fixated on their fanaticality, but their resistance to attempts of the others to penetrate to the center of the Zone speaks of strength, experience and skill, which is somewhat divergent from the opinion of fanaticism and zombie. The availability of first-class weapons from monoliths based on the latest technological developments, heavy uniforms and other technical means suggests the existence of an unknown source of financing. \n\nMonoliths were freaks even before they had a "completely roof". They all talked about aliens, the exclusivity of the Zone, the experiments of the aliens and, of course, their beloved Monolith. And they even believed, in spite of the fact that there were no living witnesses. Of course, balabolov, who told that they saw the Monolith on their own, had enough. But who will believe Sanya Red or Govorun, who did not even reach the Agroprom? And now the monoliths have completely disappeared from the reels. They have even stopped talking to anyone. Just start shmalyat on anyone they see. One word - fanatics. \n... \n\n"Debt" \nA paramilitary group characterized by strict discipline: its members actually live by statute. Only representatives of the "Debt" do not trade in the unique creations of the Zone with the outside world: according to rumors, all artifacts found by these people are surrendered to scientists. Every debtor considers his main goal to protect the world from the impact of the Zone. Most grouping operations are associated with the extermination of monsters, so the raids "Debt" often rid ordinary stalkers of many pressing problems. For a long time and furiously he fights with the group "Freedom". \n\nGuys in camouflage with images of shields on patches not just sunbathed in the vicinity of the camp "Freedom". They sat quietly, hiding behind trees and ruins and making no noise. Even when "goals" appeared in the field of vision, they waited. Only letting their enemies in closer, opened fire to defeat. That day, none of the "Fremen" did not leave them. The last one was killed by the Harness, who was driven to the second floor of the ruined house. He fired back for a long time, preventing the debtors from approaching. Then Shmelev ordered pelted him with grenades. The tourniquet was still alive when they approached him. The right arm was torn off, and a splinter fell into the stomach. Shmelev had to spend on him one more cartridge. \n... \n\n"Freedom" \nAnarchists and daredevils who declared themselves fighters for freedom on the territory of the Zone, and therefore constantly conflicting with military stalkers and the group "Debt". Svobodovtsy believe that information about what is happening in the Zone can not be hidden from humanity, thus challenging the monopoly of government organizations to own local secrets and miracles. \n\nFrom the Fremen, I learned that the Zone originated as a result of military tests of a secret weapon. One stalker named Lukaevy from "Freedom" assured me that he knows this for sure. Like, the information is accurate and verified. I do not know if this is so, but everything really converges - both the incomprehensible nature of the catastrophe, and the military's interest in the Zone from the very first day of its appearance, and their dislike of ordinary stalkers, and the desire to get to the center - to where, according to Lukavoy's assurances, until now is the most secret weapon. \n... \n\nMercenaries \nPeople who can do any job for money. Know the Zone and its offsprings are worse than the ordinary stalker, and often die where the green beginner would notice the danger. But as far as war with people is concerned, they know the point: professionals in their field, they will quickly deal with any stalker and even can completely eliminate a small grouping. \n\nBlue suits flashed everywhere. They drove him, like a pack of wolves the intended victim. Poplar realized it was too late. He kept looking back, shooting back, when suddenly a dark figure suddenly appeared in front of him and a faint shot sounded. Stalker fell, clutching a wound wound in the side. The persecutors ran up and lined up in a semicircle. The one that shot, went to the wounded man and put the barrel. \n- "For what?" croaked Poplar. - "Nothing personal. We were paid, "said a voice from behind the mask. After the answer, a shot sounded. Control. \n... \n\nScientists \nResearchers of the Nature of the Zone and Its Generations. With a good attitude on their part, a lucky stalker can sell well the scientists found in the Khabar Zone without an intermediary dealer. \n\nI used to see him from time to time in the research camp - I used to give up a hack. Normal was a man. Healthy, pumped up - and do not say that of eggheads. The price was good for the artifacts, for a life with him it was always possible to talk ... and so absurdly got into trouble. Near the "carousel" something was out there with its instruments when these jackals started shooting. He was thrown into an anomaly, untwisted. When we finished the fight, only the scraps of his spacesuit near the anomaly and left. \n... \n\n"Clear Sky" \nResearchers of the Zone, a little-known clan, lost somewhere in the marshes. Nobody knows for sure what their numbers are, what they do and what goals they pursue. But those rare stalkers that came from the marshes tell about the guys in camouflage sky-blue. \n\nSkif rose from his knee and lowered the barrel - strangers were much larger. He was surprised by the coloring of their camouflage - blue, with white inserts, like the sky outside the Zone. For the marshes it was, to put it mildly, a unmasking robe. "Fighters of them, of course, like a bullet shit," thought the stalker to himself, "but I also got scared, these handsome men let me in so close".</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_leaders">
		<text>Heads of groupings</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_leaders_text">
		<text>Man remains a man even in such terrible conditions as in the Zone. These people rallied groups of like-minded people and pursued their goals.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_traders">
		<text>Merchants</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_traders_text">
		<text>The main suppliers of everything and everything in the Zone, thanks to traders, you can buy various things necessary for survival. The assortment often depends on the belongings of things, for example, war accessories, cartridges, food, various junk, equipment and weapons, but also from belonging to a grouping. It is worth remembering that each trader wants to recoup his costs for the order and delivery of goods, so the prices "as in the store" should not be counted. But if one or another merchant is benevolent, then it is possible to count on a discount. Also worth noting is the dependence of the value of goods on a person's relationship to a particular grouping. On average, the assortment of the merchants is updated once a week, for some - every 3 days. The assortment of secondary things is not stable. With the improvement of relations, traders expand the range, some increase the stability of the appearance of goods. The trader will not offer his best equipment and weapons for sale with an insufficient reputation among the group to which he belongs.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_medics">
		<text>Physicians</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_medics_text">
		<text>Dear people in the Zone, on their account hundreds of lives saved. Working as a doctor in the Zone is really difficult, they have to cure such terrible wounds that you will not find on the "big earth", one burn from the burning down of what it costs. Sometimes it is worth it to visit and check health, since no monetary currency is worth living a person. Also, doctors can buy medicines.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_techs">
		<text>Techniques</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_techs_text">
		<text>Technicians repair equipment and weapons, saving stalkers a chance to survive. Many returned alive from raids, as they did not forget about repairing and improving their equipment. In the relatively safe habitats of stalkers, it is sometimes worth visiting machinery. There are cases when the cost of repairing a particular thing is several times greater than the cost of a trader. Often, such a cost is affected due to the state of things, or the relationship of a person to the grouping of technology. But do not forget about the rarity of good weapons in the Zone, sometimes it's better to spend money on repairs than to find a new one.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_reputation">
		<text>Reputation</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_survival_reputation_text">
		<text>Reputation gives an idea of ​​how a player interacts with other stalkers. Assistance always involves improving relations, in the stalker community, and improving the reputation in general. Reputation is similar to rank, but differs in that it is not linear - there is the possibility of both increase and decrease - and is related to relationships with other stalkers, and not with activity in the game. The simplest ways to enhance reputation are to perform tasks, provide first aid to the wounded and kill the enemies of the player's grouping. With the increase in reputation, the members of the group become more loyal: the traders offer a larger assortment, discounts, and members of the group can be taken in team work. The simple ways to lose reputation are failures or refusals of tasks and the killing of neutral or friendly stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_surrender">
		<text>Interrogation</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_personae_surrender_text">
		<text>With some probability, a wounded man can kneel and lay his hands behind his head, then you can interrogate him. Tell about the location of the hiding place or give it back to the CCP, or maybe send ... It's necessary to avoid the wounded fanatics who explode for the glory of their idol, just to avoid being captured.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants">
		<text>Mutants</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_rat">
		<text>Rat</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_rat_text">
		<text>A rat is a small and harmless creature. Facing people, usually, the rats panic. They move in packs, chaotically. \n\nWhen meeting with rodents like rats, you should not shoot in white light, while the flock is on the move, so as not to exhaust ammunition for nothing. The best way is to shoot with single shots. With rats, there is nothing special to take, their small carcasses will go only to be eaten on their own.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tushkano">
		<text>Tushkan</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tushkano_text">
		<text>Tushkan is a small schooling rodent. Dexterous, pesky, but alone does not pose a danger. The flocks of the tushkans are more numerous than the rat. Problems with their detection do not arise in principle, because they differ the most noisy per unit time character - incessant roar, pelvis movements and sniffing. Noticing the person, immediately cut the distance for the bite. They move, usually, strictly in a straight line. More often, tuscany can be found in industrial complexes, utility rooms and near roads. \n\nDoes it make sense to hunt for the tushkans - a controversial issue. They have a large head, for which they are valued, although it is relatively cheap. Hunting for the tushkan is simple and straightforward - to provoke a near-sacrifice, to let it get closer and slaughter. Skirmishes with carcasses are fleeting.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_cat">
		<text>Cat Baiyun</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_cat_text">
		<text>Kot-banyun - a feral descendant of domestic cats and cats, this chernobylets now - a frequenter of small groves and open spaces, but is rare. Likes to arrange "lezhki" along the roads and not far from the camps. Bored cats usually like to lie down under a tree, so those who are sensitive to the ear and eye stalkers of this beast will notice easily. Like other mutants of the Zone, the cat-bayun is aggressive towards humans. Noticing a stranger, the cat angrily hisses and rushes to the victim. The peculiarity of the mutant is that it is incredibly fast and uses its speed with the mind - begins to circle around the alleged victim, and then suddenly rushes into the attack. Cats-bayuns do not disdain to walk in small flocks - for 2-6 individuals and react to any threat together. Vulnerability of the cat - in its physical weakness and low endurance. \n\nHunting for cats is justified, in spite of the fact that scientists do not buy cat tails much more than dogs, but blind dogs, unlike cats-bayuns, are not as aggressive. The tactics of hunting for cats are quite simple. The main thing - to concentrate and not to panic, when the beast begins to circle from different sides. The use of grenades is unreasonable: manual too much delay, and podstvolnye just a pity to spend. Any "little dog" with a cat will cope easily.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog">
		<text>The Blind Dog</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog_text">
		<text>The blind dog is the most common inhabitant of abnormal wastelands. By itself, the mutant is not so dangerous, but the pack is already some force, which is not worth underestimating. As you know, these dogs lead a semi-nomadic way of life, therefore, they can attack in an unexpected place. By nature, the dogs of this subspecies are rather cowardly, but, being in the pack, they gain impudence and impudence to attack even menacingly equipped people. It can also be noted that the collective mind of the pack reacts very sensitively to the loss of personnel - kill enough mutants, and the others, whining, will try to hide. Do not shy dogs, like many other mutants, attack other mutants, except those that are certainly stronger than themselves. Flocks often practice ambush in the bushes, while observing absolute radio silence. \n\nHunting for dogs pays off almost completely. Blind dogs are always in flocks. When attacking such a pack the main thing is not to panic, but coolly and methodically to shoot mutants, handing back. Often with a break in morale, the remaining dogs begin to suddenly toss between running and attacking.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_pseudodog">
		<text>Pseudo Dog</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_pseudodog_text">
		<text>Pseudo dogs are the first serious mutant. A wild dog who lived for a long time under irradiation and degenerated into a new species. The pseudo dog is very aggressive and cunning. He likes to sit quietly in ambush. Seeing the target, with a roar rushes into the attack. Has the beginnings of mental control. The main habitat is the north of the Zone. \n\nPseudo-dog and its variety - psi-dog is considered to be for beneficial purposes. The best way to eliminate the mutant is to sneak up unnoticeably and put a bullet in the temple. But this is not easy, the flair of these dogs hoo. If the dog has noticed a person before he has it, the key to defeating this creature is to reveal the living individual in time among the induced phantoms. The advantage is the use of folds of the terrain and retreat to the height, if the pack attacks. Farther or more correctly thrown grenade, or accurate dagger fire from an automatic weapon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_psydog">
		<text>Psi Dog</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_psydog_text">
		<text>Psi-dog is a mutant, dangerous even alone. The main danger is that the psi-dog attacks in a leap. Even more dangerous is that to ensure a successful attack and for its protection, the dog has the ability to create illusory phantoms. When confronted with a psi-dog, stalkers experience headaches and a violation of the visual spectrum. Upon seeing the victim, the mutant begins to project an order of indistinguishable phantoms from the original and sends them into battle, and he himself remains out of reach of the reciprocal fire of the stalker, or quietly circulates among the phantoms to inflict a fatal blow. In addition, the psi-dog is quite hardy for its size. Sometimes it seems that the psi-dog and stalkers are sworn enemies worthy of each other. Particularly skilled representatives often gather around themselves a flock of blind dogs and head it. Such packs represent a huge danger and are capable of attacking even small camps of stalkers, disorienting defenders with phantoms and winning by surprise. The main habitat is the north of the Zone. \n\nPseudo-dog and its variety - psi-dog is considered to be for beneficial purposes. The best way to eliminate a mutant is to sneak up unnoticeably and put a bullet in the temple. But this is not easy, the flair of these dogs hoo. If the dog has noticed a person before he has it, then the key to defeating this creature is to reveal the living individual in time among the induced phantoms. The advantage will be the use of folds of the terrain and retreat to the height if the flock attacks. Further or correctly thrown grenade, or accurate dagger fire from an automatic weapon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_flesh">
		<text>Flesh</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_flesh_text">
		<text>The flesh is a mutant that does not know, unless, quite a green newcomer. According to reports of scientists, as well as information circulating among stalkers, the flesh is a distorted descendant of an ordinary pig. This is a textbook mutant, often played by stalkers in local folklore, jokes and other stories, often voiced at campfires. This kind of sarcastic attention on the part of people was received by the flesh, first of all, thanks to its cowardly and petty character. In the Zone environment, the mutant is less common than other mutant mutants. Nevertheless, despite such a cheerful entourage, the flesh remains the same dangerous mutant, capable of other things being equal, to complicate the life of the stalker or even kill him. Suddenly attack or just finish off a seriously wounded person with powerful blows of pointed joints of the forepaws - such are the rotten habits of the flesh. Fight off the mutant is fairly easy, attacking the flesh is not fast, and moves noisily to the accompaniment of uterine grunting. \n\nTo fuck up the flesh definitely should. Extraction of the trophy - the eyes are often ordered by the large merchants of the Zone and scientists. Being a rather lazy creature, the flesh loves to arrange stays in shrubbery, sit back and rest among the ruins or near the ponds. Getting to the flesh unnoticed is quite easy in view of her idle lifestyle, and this should be used. Being caught unawares, the flesh for a while indulge in the mess before they understand what is happening and where the threat comes from. In these seconds, the overwhelming damage is usually applied. If the flesh is one, then on this everything, as a rule, also ends. In the case of a flock, a part of the surviving specimens, when they see a stalker, rush towards him. It must be borne in mind that a frightened mutant runs pretty fast and resolutely to stop attempts to escape. The best weapon against the flesh is shotguns and shotguns.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boar">
		<text>Boar</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boar_text">
		<text>The boar is one of the well-studied and highly known mutants of the Zone. Virtually unchanged under the influence of radiation. It is worth noting an increase in size, the emergence of an excessive number of outstretched teeth from the mouth, the eyes are often devoid of the iris. Mutant has a very aggressive character and obvious meanness. Noticing the victim, attacks indiscriminately at everything and everyone. The main danger of meeting with a wild boar is that, being overwhelmed by bloody rage, he completely loses all instincts of self-preservation and, even when mortally wounded, fights until the forces leave him. The boar tactics of combat are extremely simple - in the shortest possible time to reduce the distance with the victim, ram and gut it with their fangs. The mutant loves to lie quietly in the bushes and fasten, waiting for the sluggard victim. But do not engage in self-deception, believing the mutant to be a sluggish carcass - the alarmed boar is pretty fast and quick. The characteristic explosive grunting and trampling of hoofs will let the attentive stalker know about the approach of danger. \n\nBoar is a very good target for hunting. And you can often meet a wild boar even in the southern territories of the Zone. It is known that the boar is quite hard. Best choice - automatic / semi-automatic shotgun. Masters allow the mutant closer, but at the very last moment before the attack the boar sharply jump aside and shoot at the vulnerable side of the beast.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_zombie">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_zombie_text">
		<text>Zombies - rebel under the influence of anomalous energies Zones from the dead. Preserving scanty bits of memory and guided by the most primitive instincts, zombies lead their pseudo life in the Zone. There are zombies sedentary on a certain territory and vice versa - wandering around anomalous expanses with only their known goal. They can often be seen among the ruins of houses and in abandoned villages, but it happens that one can stumble upon the dead and in the forest more often, sewer collectors, communications, less often in open spaces. Apparently, this is due to the place where, while still a man, the zombie met its end. Usually, these rotting skeletons do not show aggression if they do not approach them. Having listened, one can make out in their incoherent murmurs accusations against the Zone and t. d. \n\nZombies are attacked in close combat, damage is inflicted by the average. Planned hunting for zombies is not justified, since the price of the hand is not high. Zombies are resistant to damage, spent ammunition is unlikely to pay off. Elimination - to attract the attention of a half-pipe, to allow for a distance convenient for shooting and to hit the head. You can save cartridges by finishing with cold weapons, just in the head, not letting the zombies rise.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_fracture">
		<text>Fracture</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_fracture_text">
		<text>Fracture is a perverted parody of a man. Once it was, judging by the robe, perhaps a resident of the villages, to which infected areas came in close or unknown test, such a lot was brought to the ChZO for the needs of a number of secret government and private laboratories. Breaks, perhaps, are people who have been in the Zone for a long time or who have fallen under the Ejection, but who managed to survive it somehow. The main ugliness and the most striking feature of the fracture is the hypertrophied hand, which the mutant carefully hides from extraneous looks under the clothes. Stalkers gave this name to a mutant for two reasons. The first - actually because of the appearance and a terrible hand, turned out at an unnatural angle. The second - the kills killed always have traces of the most powerful blows of the hand, literally breaking the bodies of the victims. The fractures are insidious and spiteful by nature of their nature. They disguise themselves as people and try to make contact with requests for food. With the appearance of a humanoid moving with the use of all four limbs. If there is nothing interesting in the vicinity, then the fracture sits on the ground with legs stretched out, and something mumbles. Seeing the stalker, immediately jumps up and rushes to the victim. \n\nEveryone can handle a break, but beginners should be very careful. Mutant is dangerous only at close range, but can kill a pair of lightning strokes of his hand. Shotguns, automatic weapons, grenades podstvolnye to help. Shoot the enemy from afar, not allowing yourself. An important point: at close range can grab the victim and beat, it is quite difficult to leave and better to take the fight.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_snork">
		<text>Snork</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_snork_text">
		<text>Snorkh - a man reincarnated by the Zone. It seems that the good part of the missing stalkers turn into snorkels under the impact of the ejection. These mutants are concerned only with a few basic instincts, the main ones of which are hunting and hunger. Taking away everything from human snorkels, Zona generously endowed them with physical strength, vitality and incredible dexterity. Moving the creature on all fours, often skipping. The strange attachment of snorkers to fragments of gas masks has so far not been explained. Stalkers believe that the sniffs subconsciously try to hide their disfigured face, even more confining to the beast within themselves. Someone tells tales that snorkels are stalkers who rebelled from their graves that they put on gas masks left on the cross to hide the rotten faces. If the mutant is in relative calm, then it is rather difficult to learn about its approach, because subconsciously the snork moves quietly and stealthily, is pressed to the ground. The most serious danger of a snark lies in his superhuman dexterity. He can make swift jumps up to 20 meters long. This is always unexpected, because the mutant does not need any running start or acceleration - it jumps from the spot, knocks the victim off its feet and stuns with blows. Snorka can be found in completely different areas of the Zone from impassable to relatively safe. \n\nHunting is good. The cost of trophies among the research fraternity is high. A mobile stalker, with well-developed coordination and refined reflexes, can easily cope with a snorkel. With the group will be harder. It is necessary to know the approximate distance with which the mutant makes a jump, and in time to dodge. After landing, the snark, grouped, makes a roll over the head to extinguish the impact of the fall. Here it can be shot at close range. It happens that the snark, having noticed the victim, will rise in full growth. Many open fire at this very moment, achieving greater accuracy of hitting. But the surest way - an accurate shot in the head. Usually the mutant moves sideways, therefore, aiming at it in the head, one has to make an amendment to it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_burer">
		<text>Burer</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_burer_text">
		<text>Burer - one of the legendary mutants of the Zone. Once a man, Burer is a master of telekinesis. Scraps of information obtained by veteran stalkers from secret laboratories scattered across the Zone, which have come to desolation, indicate that the burer is the result of a complex of experiments. Scientists, under the supervision of the military, tried to develop mental abilities among prisoners. And judging by what we now have to fight stalkers in the contaminated territories, they have achieved certain successes. It is not known under what conditions future bureauers managed to leave closed laboratories. Perhaps, the disaster of 2006 caused a series of emergency situations or the bureurs rebelled and destroyed their tormentors. To date, the situation is as follows: the descendants of the bureurs settled over abandoned underground complexes, destroyed laboratories and dungeons. This is due to the fact that these mutants suffer from an exceptional form of photophobia, that is, they do not tolerate light. They are characterized by kleptomania and gathering. The burgers are vile in character. Anyone who has penetrated their domain, mutants lure deeper, and then attack the whole number. By itself, the burer is not terrible, his powerful paranormal abilities are dangerous. By the power of thought these dwarfs can move objects in space, impart to them a strong acceleration and kill them with such an improvised shell. To protect against small arms, the burer is able to erect a mental shield around him, stopping bullets in contact. To meet a burer can be infrequent, because their habitat is limited to dungeons, but there are places where they can be seen on the surface. Experienced stalker on time notices a growing buzz in the ears - burer nearby. \n\nBurer is a serious and dangerous opponent, but the value of his brain among scientists is high. Even an experienced stalker will not easily overcome the burer, and the group can not cope with the master. There are two main tactics. The first is to destroy the mutant from afar with a well-aimed shot at the head. The second is to imperceptibly reduce the distance and use powerful weapons to quickly eliminate the enemy. In the second case, one must beware that the burer can by his will instantly weaken a person, making it an easy prey - knocking out weapons. On the other hand, at a short distance the burer starts to panic and toss, runs away or enters a melee.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_bloodsucker">
		<text>Bloodsucker</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_bloodsucker_text">
		<text>Bloodsucker is the sinister legend of the Zone. After scientists with the help of stalkers managed to get and study the sample of the mutant's body, the question of the origin of mummified human bodies in abnormal territories was answered logically. These are the victims of the bloodsucker. He is the perfect killer-predator in the environment of the Zone. She gave him the opportunity to change the chemical composition of his cells so that they begin to refract light in a special way, making the bloodsucker virtually invisible. It turns out a biological alternative to thermo-optical camouflage. Looks bloodsucker eerily. Similar to a flattened, hunched humanoid with long arms, ending in an impressive size with brushes and claws, it produces that still impression. As you know, the Zone generously gives one hand and the other severely takes away. For all the gifts the bloodsucker paid off with a look - a bald skull, terrible evil eyes, wide cheekbones, a complete absence of the lower jaw, whose place was occupied by long, wiggly, vile-looking tentacles. The main danger of the bloodsucker in his physical data: disguise, extraordinary strength, agility, speed and great endurance. He deals monstrous blows to opponents, killing or maiming with the intention of "preserving" food for future use. If the bloodsucker is sitting in an ambush, then sometimes he is given a breathless breathing or "slugging" of tentacles. The color of the skin of bloodsuckers depends on their habitat. \n\nHunting for the bloodsucker - the prerogative of professionals. But the extraction is worth it. The parts of the bloodsucker are simply a feast for eggheads, beating over special mutant enzymes, capable of instantly digesting proteins and coagulating blood. The most successful option of eliminating the bloodsucker is to calculate it "at rest" and without masking. An accurate shot in the temple of the mutant should close the question. But this is hard to do, because the bloodsucker is very perspicacious and observant, it is very rare to catch him unawares. Open battle is a big problem, you need an elevation. Determine the location of the enemy can be chugged while running. Over time, it becomes easier to distinguish the transparent contour of a disguised bloodsucker from the rest of the background. The main thing - in any case not to let the bloodsucker close.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_poltergeist">
		<text>Poltergeist</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_poltergeist_text">
		<text>Poltergeist - one of the most mysterious, secretive and unexplored mutants of the Zone. His habits resemble the epic brownies. Poltergeist loves to play with those who accidentally fell into his possession. Objects around start to soar in the air. The character of poltergeist is unpredictable. He can confine himself to leprosy, and may fall into a rage and attack with telekinesis rights. Raise a few boxes in the air, heavy metal objects, structures and bring them down on a man for a poltergeist -. As befits the legends, a poltergeist inhabits sinister, enjoying the most evil glory, especially loves the limited space of dungeons. Poltergeist has the image of a clot of light hovering above the ground, but experienced stalkers say that they met this creature in another view ... \n\nPoltergeist as an object of profit is not interesting. Cope with it is not easy, because it is difficult to determine its vulnerable place. But enough pairs of accurate bursts of ectoplasm. Unlike burer, poltergeist can use telekinetic attacks even through obstacles.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_controler">
		<text>Controller</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_controler_text">
		<text>The controller is a mutant of the Zone, which is to some extent feared by every stalker. Of the documents that NIICAZ supplied to a legendary stalker, it became known that the appearance of the controller is the result of experiments of the "X" laboratories for irradiating the experimental people with psi waves generated by the prototype of the Caymanov radiator. There is an analogy with the history of Bührer. The same kind of impact on the human body, then the escape of the experimental subjects during the insurrection or because of the events of 2006. Either way, the supervisors settled in many areas of contaminated areas. Physically, the controller is weak and does not pose a danger, moves slowly, but these mutant deficiencies mutate more than offset by astounding telepathic abilities. A creature can take control of almost any beast or person and, completely suppressing his will, manage it like a doll at a distance. It is rumored that especially handy inspectors "led" to the Zone from Perimeter the entire personnel of the entire checkpoint. Many argue that a person who has become a limp slave of a mutant, still retains self-awareness and reason until the inspector eats the unfortunate person alive or his devastating mental impact finally "dissolves" the person, turning a person into another zombie. For many, this is worse than any other death in the Zone. Lair its controller arranges in the dungeons, abandoned towns or villages, as well as in laboratories. Attacks the controller from afar, inflicting a mental blow that disorients the victim and destroys the synapses in the brain, but can immediately kill an unprepared stalker. It must be remembered that for such an attack the mutant needs to establish eye contact with the victim. In addition, the controller projects in some radius around himself a disastrous psi-aura that causes visual and auditory hallucinations, and eventually kills the brain of any being. \n\nScientists are always happy to pay good money for body parts and controller's organs, so it makes sense to get these trophies. Elimination of this mutant is work for a good shooter. If there is where to turn, then the destruction of the controller from the maximum possible range by sniper fire is the best option for punishing him. In an enclosed space, things are more complicated. Need psi-protection from psi-aura, and the destruction must be sudden and sure. It should be remembered that the controller can be found with a retinue in the form of snorkels and zombies.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_chimera">
		<text>Chimera</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_chimera_text">
		<text>Chimera is a real scourge of a stalker. Incredibly clever and insidious killer predator. Many stalkers agree that the chimera has a human self-awareness and almost the same intelligence. Scientists in informal conversations hold the view that the chimera is the result of a series of experiments ... Some argue that the ancestor of the chimaera is an ordinary cat. Mutant acts as a quadruped animal. Has a duplicated system of internal organs, the head is also two, one is underdeveloped. This allows the chimera to survive even after injuries that seemingly are incompatible with life and continue the fight. Seeing a man, the creature will pursue him until he kills. Chimera is very aggressive and attacks anyone with whom she can potentially cope. A mutant is dangerous in that it has practically no weaknesses or flaws. Strength, stamina, extreme dexterity, fast speed of movement, noiseless movement - all this is in the arsenal of chimera. She can also argue with a snorkel in the length of the jump. The arms of the mutant are of impressive size claws on the front paws. The lethal attack of the chimera is in her leap. Quickly retreats and starts running around, making sudden attacks, if the victim was able to evade the impact in the jump. Mutant can be found even in relatively safe areas. \n\nScientists are interested in parts of the chimera more than in the materials of other mutants, payment worthy. But three times think about deliberate hunting for this predator. Attention and concentration in the battle with the monster - the key to victory. When the chimera begins to circle around, you should move along with it like in a dance. It is necessary to confuse the mutant, making false attacks, to dodge and to guess his jumps. To hit the head with a powerful caliber, an underbarrel grenade launcher can save a life.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_giant">
		<text>Giant</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_giant_text">
		<text>Giant - a huge carcass weighing a couple of tons. A mutant known in stalker circles. The largest inhabitant of contaminated areas, does not differ in intelligence and ingenuity for all its colossal power and simply unimaginable endurance. There is an opinion that the progenitor of this monster is an ordinary chicken-broiler - very similar to the structure of their bodies and especially the legs. Because of its large dimensions, the giant is constantly in search of food and leads a nomadic way of life or settles down where there is regularly something to profit. The business card of the mutant is a thunderous roar, from which the ringing in the ears and the mighty footsteps, which makes the earth near shake and walk with staggering, that gives out its presence in open spaces. Giants are mostly single. \n\nHunting for a giant on one side is expensive, because the monster is tenacious and is rare, but on the other hand the cost of its body parts among scientists is high. When meeting with the giant, the main rule is to keep distance, use grenades or an underbarrel grenade launcher. Be ready to jump up when the giant hits the ground with a grip on the ground. This will avoid contusion from the shock wave. </text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents">
		<text>Documentation</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_memoirs_1_of_2">
		<text>Diary of a stalker, part 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_memoirs_1_of_2_text">
		<text>Old, faded notebook, wrapped in some kind of cover, so that the pages do not go bad. Nevertheless, the diary is already so spoiled by time that only a part of the text can be parsed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]I have to start recording somewhere, I need to pour out my soul on paper and throw the burden off my shoulders. I hope to leave at least something after my death to those who read this diary. Even though he does not repeat my mistakes. I have almost no friends, and there are no friends in the Zone, and even more so. All these traders look at me like an outcast. This bearded guy on Zatone smiles a sarcastic smile every time he sees me, and a Hawaiian trader constantly mocks me with an unabashed kind. Damn all these bastards, I just need from time to time a little ammunition, food and water from them. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]I decided to write down everything that happened that night so that at least someone would know what I had to go through, so that at least someone could understand why I prefer to always be alone. I came here on my own, but soon I met a newcomer. It turned out that he was very fond of the local mineral rocks. He had a hobby from the Big Earth - to collect stones, and the more he was attracted by the local artifacts - strange stones that flooded the Zone. He, of course, later collected many artifacts, but at the cost of everything was a huge tumor formed in his stomach. Frequent vomiting, diarrhea, constant stress ... He looked like a pregnant woman, but instead of a child in his stomach developed a huge malignant tumor. He even called her after his first pet. Of course, I did not mind. I liked him, we almost became friends. We never contacted the bandits, did not just attack the mutants, we just wander around the anomalies, choosing the most interesting stone formations, and sometimes, when particularly lucky, there were also artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_memoirs_2_of_2">
		<text>Diary of a stalker, p.2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_memoirs_2_of_2_text">
		<text>Old, faded notebook, wrapped in some kind of cover, so that the pages do not go bad. Nevertheless, the diary is already so spoiled by time that only a part of the text can be disassembled: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Once the conversation came about one anomaly, as it turned out, located deep in the cave or a crack in the ground, I do not know what to call. There should have been a huge number of artifacts, but no one wanted to go there with us for some reason. "Panties and fools", - we then thought. Why did not anyone want to get rich and then live an easy life? Then a sudden burst of courage rolled over us, we immediately gathered and went straight to the cave. We did not even have time to look into the cave, as some dark shadow flew over us. I stumbled, hit my head and fainted. After a while I came to myself and heard someone moaning. "Animals", as I thought initially, but then suddenly realized that I was lying and moaning in front of my friend. His skin was torn all over his body, in his bleeding wounds could see all the muscles. He crawled from the cave himself, in consciousness, dragging his guts with him ... It was a miracle that he did not die on the spot. I did not understand anything, I took out my pistol and started shooting towards that cave. I had 20 cartridges for the gun, when I had 7 cartridges, something grabbed my arm. I continued to fire, frantically pressing the trigger. After a moment, the grip weakened, but I kept pulling the trigger even when my ammo ran out. Then I did not even understand what I had just done with my friend. I did not even have the courage to take his things, I just ran. As after that, I could talk with someone or make new acquaintances, when the Zone at any time can repeat its evil joke. It's better to be alone. Friendship has its price and risk. It is not necessary to have a particularly warm friendship, because all this can be lost in a moment. Yes, I realized this from my own experience, I stuffed a bump on my head, which will not let me forget it.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_freedom_manual_1_of_2">
		<text>Conducting interrogations, part 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_freedom_manual_1_of_2_text">
		<text>Training leaflets with a large emblem of "Freedom" in the upper right corner and a small drawing of a pistol and a man on his knees. It is called "Interrogation Methods: Basics" and is written in a casual slang grouping. : \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]I should not even mention this, because it's all obvious and so. But in fact, I will share with you, but do not crouch to the right and left, or you will not understand. Throw this leaflet, burn it or give it to someone you trust. You do not want everyone to know about this? After all, you can be yourself once, on the spot of the interrogated one, right? Do you have a cache? So keep these sheets to yourself and do not say later that you were not warned. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Everyone has their own cache. Even the poorest, unfortunate bandit living in the Zone has a stash of a couple of soup-picks in it and a few bullets. Here everything works according to such laws. You collect some money, sell a few artifacts, parts of mutants, rob the dead, but as a rule still warm bodies, buy food and weapons. Even when the shit flies directly to the wind in your face, you are left with a smirk on your face, because you have a trump card in your sleeve that can save your skin. Such are the severe laws of the Zone, here no one will help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_freedom_manual_2_of_2">
		<text>Conducting interrogations, part 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_freedom_manual_2_of_2_text">
		<text>Training leaflets with a large emblem of "Freedom" in the upper right corner and a small drawing of a pistol and a man on his knees. It is called "Interrogation Methods: Basics" and is written in a casual slang grouping. : \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]But now we will not talk about help from outside and about the relations of stalkers. If you want to get important information about the whereabouts of someone else's hiding place - start with the choice of the victim. When you think of everything, choose a quiet place where there is no one - shoot straight at the hands and feet, deliver as much pain as possible until they realize that you are their closest friend at the moment. And then they will throw the weapon and kneel before you. Talk to them firmly and convincingly, but do not kill, after all in the district and so many mutants - they will finish this job for you. Do not make the Zone worse.. Say that you will go away, scare them as hard as possible, make them understand that the end is already near. They usually understand this and surrender.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_stalker_letter_1_of_2">
		<text>Memoirs, Part 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_stalker_letter_1_of_2_text">
		<text>A couple of pages torn from someone's memoirs. The manuscript is in blue ink, which is almost blurred from the influence of the environment, which makes the text almost unreadable. author unknown. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]I still feel the warmth of that anomaly on my back. It burns even when I just sit on Skadovsk, in a safe place, away from dangers and from all fucking heating devices. You do not even know what I'm going through every time, approaching these fucking anomalies. Hell, my back burns even more, now it's my anomaly detector. After getting into a burning or acid anomaly with simple burns, you will not get off. It's like you took the part of the Zone forever inside of you. "Under the sign of the Zone," so I call it. Horror, no physical law acts in the Zone. I just do not know what to expect from the local anomalies. I can easily overcome a dozen bloodsuckers on a dark night, but each time I just get lost at the sight of an anomaly ... Is that possible? This in general, can not be a reality at all! I do not cease to think that this entire Zone is a continuous single nightmare that is repeated time after time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_stalker_letter_2_of_2">
		<text>Memoirs, part 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_stalker_letter_2_of_2_text">
		<text>A couple of pages torn from someone's memoirs. The manuscript is in blue ink, which is almost blurred from the influence of the environment, which makes the text almost unreadable. author unknown. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Every time I think about it, my back trembles with pain and turns into a single red ball. I for the last 4 months and did not come close to these anomalies, I make a living killing mutants. But on this you will not last long, and the back still reacts, as if she has her own mind. Sometimes I feel sorry that I have not left this burning hell. Maybe it would have been more beneficial for me if I had become food to those boars. Although no ... Boars are stupid creatures. But if they attack the same Skadovsk, it will fall in a few days. They will not be stopped by bullets. Boars are generally useless creatures, their meat is terrible, even an experienced cook can not make it edible. Sometimes I choose to wander around Zaton, my back can barely endure a backpack. I go there, because it always seems to me that I left something there, that calls me from time to time. Because of these terrible pains in the back, I have to sleep on my stomach or on my side. I do not like sleeping on my side, I do not sleep well. The zone changes us without asking permission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_ecologist_report_1_of_3">
		<text>"On the zombified", Part 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_ecologist_report_1_of_3_text">
		<text>Text typed on a typewriter with reference to belonging to the Environmental Study Group, judging by the stamps and emblems. It is classified as strictly confidential and signed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Arkady Tsvetkovsky \n %c[0,170,170,170]Junior researcher of the laboratory and research bunker RX12 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Extracted information about walking dead , report 39B amendment. 2 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Date: 19. 03. 2014 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Folder: 34 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Page: 1 of 3 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]"Zombie" - this is the term used by the local population when it comes to the samples of half-living creatures , which can hardly be called reasonable. Scientific evidence has shown that their brain does not conduct any thought processes and the neurological activity of the brain structure is practically absent, which confirms the death of brain cells to a critical level. However, field trials have proven that, for reasons unknown to science, their necrotic brain is capable of giving out impulses for simple mechanical reactions (something reminiscent of instincts, but with a significant difference in the logic of behavior). According to one version, this is due to the result of endless neurochemical reactions in the body that cause the body to move in a certain way in response to certain specific stimuli. When they are threatened by something, they demonstrate extremely aggressive behavior, so it is better to approach them with great caution. The tests showed that their physiology is so changed that the tissues are able to independently maintain a neural connection, t. e. even separated from the body parts can function independently without getting any nutrients for energy production. One of the most successful of such experiments is the maintenance of the ability of the liver and heart for 3 months without binding and connections with other organs and blood circulation. Further analyzes will be able to suggest molecular and subatomic characteristics ".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_ecologist_report_2_of_3">
		<text>"On Zombified", Part 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_ecologist_report_2_of_3_text">
		<text>Text typed on a typewriter with reference to belonging to the Environmental Study Group, judging by the stamps and emblems. It is classified as strictly confidential and signed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Arkady Tsvetkovsky \n %c[0,170,170,170]Junior researcher of the laboratory and research bunker RX12 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Extracted information about walking dead , report 39B amendment. 2 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Date: 19. 03. 2014 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Folder: 34 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Page: 2 of 3 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]The results we obtained will help to explain the riddle of the fact that, being repeatedly injured in the limb, in the pelvic region, peripheral organs and other areas, they are able to function endlessly, without undergoing special difficulties. Moving them is usually difficult, there is no question of doing anything, but the reflexes of handling weapons and pulling the trigger remained unchanged. Quite possibly, this also applies to the use of other simple tools and technological devices. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]You should not use the terms "kill" and "destroy" when dealing with deactivated samples. This is more rational from a psychological point of view, because the term "decontamination" is more neutral than "destruction", thus you can avoid stress on the psyche and suppress a sense of repentance. The decontamination of the sample requires the interruption of the connections of the brain to the musculoskeletal apparatus, which is preferable to a ballistic trauma in the region of the brain or spinal cord. Each member of the scientific team should bear in mind that their limbs remain functional even after the deactivation of the sample, therefore additional safety measures should be taken. More effective is the removal of the vertebrae or brainstem by surgical intervention.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_ecologist_report_3_of_3">
		<text>"On Zombie", Part 3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_ecologist_report_3_of_3_text">
		<text>Text typed on a typewriter with reference to belonging to the Environmental Study Group, judging by the stamps and emblems. It is classified as strictly confidential and signed: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Arkady Tsvetkovsky \n %c[0,170,170,170]Junior researcher of the laboratory and research bunker RX12 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Extracted information about walking dead , report 39B amendment. 2 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Date: 19. 03. 2014 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Folder: 34 \n %c[0,170,170,170]Page: 3 of 3 \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]In extremely rare cases, the behavior of some "zombie" individuals resembles the behavior of more intelligent animals: they throw weapons or refuse to manifest aggression in general. These samples are of the greatest importance for research, therefore it is undesirable to deactivate them. The capture of individuals and further analysis in laboratories is of paramount importance. The most interested party in this kind of research is neuropsychologists in connection with the potential of brain stem research and its transplantation. Theoretically, this could help patients in the late stages of Alzheimer's disease and other complex diseases. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]If possible, avoid damage to the kidneys and heart during decontamination. These bodies have a huge potential for research in the field of transplantation to other viable organisms. Collecting organs from dead "zombies" is also possible, but caution is needed, as local stalkers can have emotional connections with some specimens. If a meeting with stalkers is inevitable, then you can take two options to avoid a military encounter. First, when working in a group with a novice stalker, one should not cut out the eyes of the sample - it is elementary inhumanely. Secondly, when working in a group with a veteran stalker, it is better to motivate him with something, since they restrain emotions more restrainedly. Moreover, when working with the local human population, one can also draw some conclusions on psychological examinations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolith_prayer_1_of_3">
		<text>Prayer to "Monolith", Part 1</text>
	</string>

	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolith_prayer_1_of_3_text">
		<text>A document without a specific name, containing several paragraphs under each other. Frequent references to the Monolith indicate the religious character of the written text. The document is well preserved, which shows the care in the compilation and careful attitude in the future. The text of the prayer reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0.170,170,170]We pray to you!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Our only light in darkness \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Hope thou inspire in our hearts! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We go forward on the infidels to you! \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]About , Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Forgive our sins!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Show us our destiny!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n  %c[0.170,170,170]Give us the power to reach our goals! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Give hope to crush your enemies! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Ozary your light! \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We beg of you! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith! \n %c[0,170,170,170]We are your descendants! \n %c[0,170,170,170 ]O Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Our only hope for redemption!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Your name is in our hearts!.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolith_prayer_2_of_3">
		<text>Prayer to "Monolith", Part 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolith_prayer_2_of_3_text">
		<text>A document without a specific name, containing several paragraphs each under the other. Frequent references to the Monolith indicate the religious character of the written text. The document is well preserved, which shows the care in the compilation and careful attitude in the future. The text of the prayer reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Warriors of the monolith, stop!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith, light our way!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Take our souls, our minds \n %c[0,170,170,170]And cleanse them!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Spare them of doubt and hesitation!\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith, you are our hope!\n %c[0,170,170,170]We are your soldiers forever!\n  %c[0.170,170,170]We want to give our lives for you \n %c[0,170,170,170]We want to give souls to you \n %c[0,170,170,170]We want to reunite with you! \n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith, we will eliminate all from your path! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Take our flesh! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Take our blood! \n %c[0.170,170,170]Take our souls! \n %c[0.170 , 170,170]And revive them again!\n %c[0,170,170,170]You live in us, oh, Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolith_prayer_3_of_3">
		<text>Prayer to "Monolith", p.3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolith_prayer_3_of_3_text">
		<text>A document without a specific name, containing several paragraphs each under the other. Frequent references to the Monolith indicate the religious character of the written text. The document is well preserved, which shows the care in the compilation and careful attitude in the future. The text of the prayer reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh, Monolith!\n %c[0,170,170,170]You are our destiny.\n %c[0,140,140,140]And we are all brothers.\n %c[0,140,140,140]We are brothers of light Monolith.\n %c[0,140,140,140]We will give up our lives for our cause.\n %c[0,140,140,140]We'll perish in your name.\n %c[0,140,140,140]We'll die under Your Light.\n %c[0,140,140,140]death is only the beginning. \n %c[0,140,140,140]We go with your name on your lips, O Monolith !.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolithian_thoughts">
		<text>Diary of "Monolith"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_monolithian_thoughts_text">
		<text>Handwritten sheet of paper. At the beginning of the text, the style of writing is extremely chaotic and untidy, as if the person writing this suffered from a severe mental disorder. The most interesting is that the following text becomes clearer, more vividly narrated by the end of the text of the diary is almost perfect. The note said: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]As far as I remember now, there was a darkness around me, I could not see anything. Nothing ... Even time. But suddenly a light appeared before me! The light is so bright, so cozy ... I wanted to touch it, I wanted to feel it. I understood, I realized that he was trying to help me, trying to save me. I knew ... \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]And after I touched the light, I forgot about everything. There was no past life - behind me was pitch darkness. The only light source was in front of me. His name was Monolith. He saved me, and I am infinitely grateful to him for it. Sometimes in front of me there are faces, faces from the past ... A woman and a child ... My family? I'm dressed in a white overall ... Maybe I was a scientist ... What a strange word ... Radar ... NO! There there is darkness?! She wants me to die! I will not let myself be killed! No, there is no turning back! Only forward, only to the light! To the light! For the Monolith!.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_to_outside">
		<text>Letter from Natalie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_to_outside_text">
		<text>A letter written by one of the stalkers to someone outside the Exclusion Zone, most likely a wife or mistress. The fact that the letter fell into your hands proves that it will never reach its intended recipient. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Hello, Natalie! \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]How are you? Like children? Tell Sashka that if he does not obey, I will spank him well when I get home.. What about me? Well, I do not think you'll understand me now.. But listen: The zone ... This place ... Unique. Only here I can feel connected with other people. Only here I see people as they really are. There are no masks, only a harsh truth. I'll tell you everything more colorful later, when I meet. I've earned good money here! We can finally buy you the necklace that you so long wanted. Yes, and thank you for writing me, do not forget me. Your letters really help me and raise my spirits even in the harshest times. When I think about you, the world becomes much easier. See you soon. Tell the children hello from me!\n \n %c[0.170,170,170]With a lot of love, your Michael. Your brave stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_military_stalker">
		<text>A note of a military stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_etter_military_stalker_text">
		<text>A note found among the garbage. It is difficult to determine what it was written for, most likely someone was killing time, passing the tiring dark night, and then just forgot to throw their works into the fire. The text of the note reads: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Oh yeah. I'm a military stalker. It's straight from a series of something incredible! The best equipment. The most urgent tasks. The best weapon. Best of all! Finally, we managed to establish a truce between the military and stalkers. We must not shoot at each other! We are all Slavs, that's why we all have to stick together. Well, except marauders, they just want to shoot a bullet right between their eyes! Although I am new to the whole team, but I feel that I have become a real man - strong and courageous, and it's great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_mercenary">
		<text>Note of the mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_mercenary_text">
		<text>A note written by one of the mercenaries. It seems that he decided to write down some thoughts about his activities in the Zone. His intentions are incomprehensible.\n \n %c[0,170,170,170]Well, in general, what I see here is nothing special. We are all the same mercenaries, we are still the same soldiers of luck. Nevertheless, we can spontaneously choose what we do, and what we should not do. Sometimes we do not even accept applications for work, because it is too "dirty" even for us. If a client wants to kill several good people who honestly earn their living by shedding sweat and blood - forget about this bastard, in the Zone, such problems can be solved without us, the same marauders and bandits - bastards are missing! But when you need to protect someone - this is another matter! So, if you need to kill someone, you should contact the rags. They are not so legible in murders. We are different. Keep this in mind the next time you poke your money in our face.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_military_log">
		<text>Information report / Operation MSRC</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_military_log_text">
		<text>The printed part of the transmission of radio signals between the military units located in the Zone. The fact that this document was found among the crew of the SKAT indicates that it should have been involved in underground fraud in order to obtain surveillance data. It says: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]- HQ, this is MSSRC 1-03. We obtained photos from the research institute, as well as 240 photographs of the abnormal swamp, about 1400 photographs of the central base. When should we return?\n %c[0,170,170,170]- MSRC 1-03, this is HQ. Return is not possible at this time. There are some problems in military warehouses. MSRC 4-07 requests help. Once again, however, their SOS signal is very strong for now, we hope that they are still alive. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- This is HQ. Send the helicopter. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Not at all. Now there is too much anomalous activity at the Research Institute "Agroprom", too dangerous. Move to Yantar, our MI-24 will take you from there. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Roger. Is there any information about the next release?\n %c[0,170,170,170]- So exactly. Sakharov says that there are still two days before the next activity. But still hurry, their information should not be based on, unreliable. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- I understand you. We are advancing, tell Bird to be at Yantar at 7 o'clock. MSRC 1-03, end of communication. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Wait, 1-03. And what about the N-2 tunnel? Have you found anything there?\n %c[0,170,170,170]- So exactly. We found in it a new anomaly. It looks like some kind of teleporter. Should be of interest to those eggheads on Yantar, our electronics died out when we approached it for measuring psi fields. I can not understand where did such strong electronic waves come from. \n %c[0,170,170,170]- Roger, MSRC 1-03. Good luck on the way to Amber. The helicopter will be by 7 o'clock. HQ, end of communication.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_stalker_letter_3">
		<text>Letter to Nikolai</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_documents_letter_stalker_letter_3_text">
		<text>A handwritten letter addressed to Nikolai. Most likely part of the correspondence between two stalkers. Although the correspondence in the Zone is conducted mainly with the help of the CCP, many stalkers prefer traditional letters, especially on personal issues. These letters are then sent to the couriers who deliver them to the Zone. Most often the letter reaches the addressee in a few days - the probability of interception of such a message is much lower than that of the PDA. The courier profession is widely valued among stalkers. The letter says: \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Nikolai, \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]I just returned from the walk to the center of the Zone. Oh, it was just hell! "Monolith" and the warriors try to wipe each other from the face of the earth. There are moments of calm when it seems that they have concluded a ceasefire agreement, but in fact there is no agreement. Constant chaos and destruction, I had no choice but to get out of there. I was almost killed by freaking fanatics, but it's generally my fault, I just lost my vigilance. Anyway, I came to Pripyat, I plan to stay here for a while. So we will have to postpone our mission previously discussed until it is safer. I really do not sleep after I came here, but I feel very good. Keep in touch. \n\n %c[0,170,170,170]Take Care of Yourself, Ryuk.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
