<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_name">
		<text>Knife Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_hint">
		<text>Damage from quick knife attacks is significantly increased.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_descr">
		<text>The arme blanche has always attracted you; its even, metallic gloss has a calming effect. Firearms are a convenient option, of course, but with a knife in your hand, you feel complete.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Knife Master achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_mech_name">
		<text>Mechanic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_mech_hint">
		<text>High skill of independent repairing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_mech_descr">
		<text>description st_perk_mech_descr</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_mech_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Mechanic achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_craft_name">
		<text>Craftsman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_craft_hint">
		<text>Number of items available for crafting increased.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_craft_descr">
		<text>As a child, you assembled a radio from old parts in your father’s toolbox. In your youth, you repaired your motorcycle with spare parts from a flea market. Now, you feel that you will find some use in the technical debris lying in the Exclusion Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_craft_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Craftsman achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_butcher_name">
		<text>Butcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_butcher_hint">
		<text>You extract items from your prey more rapidly and effectively with your knife.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_butcher_descr">
		<text>Your presence instils fear into the creatures of the Zone; to little surprise, because you are the last thing they see in their life in the vast majority of cases. Having learned how to deal with carcass of a mutant after an encounter, people begin to fear you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_butcher_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Butcher achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_name">
		<text>Strong Stomach</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_hint">
		<text>Less damage when consuming harmful food.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_descr">
		<text>Tasty, high-quality food in the Zone is a rarity, but you are able to consume and digest what any other person in their right mind wouldn’t even consider having a bite of.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Strong Stomach achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_name">
		<text>Lead Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_hint">
		<text>Reduced radiation from artifacts in your backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_descr">
		<text>The gifts of the Zone are alluring but extremely dangerous. Not so long ago, you acquired a special backpack, which should be able to neutralize some of their radiation. The time has come to put it to use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Lead Backpack achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_name">
		<text>Attentive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_hint">
		<text>Higher chance of finding additional items in stashes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_descr">
		<text>You have learned to notice the most insignificant details not only in the behavior of people, but also in the surrounding environment. During searches, not a single kopeck, bolt, or person manages hides from you…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Attentive achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_geologist_name">
		<text>Geologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_geologist_hint">
		<text>Higher chance of finding artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_geologist_descr">
		<text>Humming, hissing, spitting; no types of anomalies are capable of intimidating you any longer, and your urge for exploration encourages you to travel to areas filled with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_geologist_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Geologist achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_authority_name">
		<text>Authority</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_authority_hint">
		<text>Number of companions increased, interrogations are more effective, reputation is gained faster, additional opportunities in dialogues.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_authority_descr">
		<text>Whether through charm, a natural ability to socialize, or perhaps a subtle knowledge of human psychology; it does not matter. You easily win the hearts of any person, whether it be a greedy huckster or an outspoken psychopath.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_authority_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Authority achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_name">
		<text>Steady Hands</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_hint">
		<text>Recoil of small arms is significantly reduced.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_descr">
		<text>In whatever condition you find yourself in, whether it be in emotional shock, a wild hangover, or a small earthquake while traveling on public transport, your hand never falters. The grip on your weapon is strong enough to leave dents on the handguard and stock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_unlock">
		<text>You have unlocked the Steady Hands achievement.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
