<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_name">
		<text>Knife Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_hint">
		<text>Damage from quick knife hits is significantly increased.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_descr">
		<text>Cold weapons always attracted you; their smooth metallic shine calms you down. Of course, firearms are more comfortable, but with knife in your hands you feel more comprehensive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_knife_master_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Knife Master» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_mech_name">
		<text>Mechanic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_mech_hint">
		<text>High skill of independent repairing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_mech_descr">
		<text>description st_perk_mech_descr</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_mech_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Mechanic» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_craft_name">
		<text>Crafter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_craft_hint">
		<text>Number of items available for crafting increased.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_craft_descr">
		<text>At young age you made a radio from old parts in your fathers' box, in your youth you repaired your motorcycle using spare parts from flea markets, but now you feel that you will certainly find use of technical garbage in The Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_craft_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Crafter» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_butcher_name">
		<text>Butcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_butcher_hint">
		<text>More rapid and effective use of the knife when cutting prey.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_butcher_descr">
		<text>You cause fear to the mutants of the Zone, and not surprisingly. In most cases, you are the last thing they see before they die. Learning what you do to the body of the mutants after, people become even more afraid of you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_butcher_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Butcher» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_name">
		<text>Strong Stomach</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_hint">
		<text>Less harm to health when eating harmful food.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_descr">
		<text>Delicious and high-quality food in The Zone is a rarity, but you are able to consume and digest even what a stalker wouldn't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_strong_stomach_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Strong Stomach» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_name">
		<text>Lead Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_hint">
		<text>Reduced radiation of artifacts in your backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_descr">
		<text>Gifts of The Zone are attractive, but extremely dangerous. Not so long ago you got a special backpack, which should neutralize some of their radiation. It's time to try it out in business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_lead_backpack_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Lead Backpack» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_name">
		<text>Attentive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_hint">
		<text>Increased chance to find more things in caches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_descr">
		<text>You are accustomed to notice the most insignificant details not only in the behavior of people, but also in the surrounding environment, and even searching in a stash. Not one cent, nor a single bolt can hide from you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_thoroughness_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Attentive» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_geologist_name">
		<text>Geologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_geologist_hint">
		<text>Chance to find artifacts is increased.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_geologist_descr">
		<text>Humming, hissing and spitting - Anomalies are no longer able to scare you, and the urge for research has led to a detailed study of anomalous fields.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_geologist_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Geologist» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_authority_name">
		<text>Authority</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_authority_hint">
		<text>Number of companions increased, interrogations are more effective, reputation is gained faster, more opportunities in dialogues.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_authority_descr">
		<text>Whether it's a charm, an ability to talk or perhaps a subtle knowledge of human psychology - it does not matter what, but you easily win the hearts of many people, whether a greedy huckster or an outspoken psychopath.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_authority_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Authority» achievement.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_name">
		<text>Steady Hands</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_hint">
		<text>Recoil of small arms is significantly reduced.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_descr">
		<text>In whatever condition you are, whether it be an emotional shock, a wild hangover or a small earthquake while traveling on public transport - your hand will never falter. You keep your weapons so tight that you leave dents on the grip and buttstock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perk_steady_hands_unlock">
		<text>You unlocked the «Steady Hands» achievement.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
