<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<!--===========================================================
<
< TEXT  STRINGS FOR DIALOGS
<	CoC 1.4.21 - DoctorX Questlines 1.20
<
<	Modified by: DoctorX
<	Last revised: December 21, 2016
<
<===========================================================-->


<string_table>


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE MEET HONCHO DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- ACTOR:  Meets honcho after being sent by another honcho: -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_meet_honcho">
		<text>I've come to see you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR:  Accepts storyline task from honcho: -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_accept_task">
		<text>Very well.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- HONCHO:  Affirmation of task acceptance: -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_task_accepted">
		<text>Good luck stalker.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR:  Leaves honcho: -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_actor_exit">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE DEFAULT DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- DEFAULT END GAME TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_default_endgame">
		<text>You need to find the Wish Granter. It is located somewhere in Chernobyl NPP and will not be easy to get to. This is your only way out of here.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE LONER GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- SIDOROVICH STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_esc_m_trader_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>I want to find the Wish Granter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_esc_m_trader_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Sure easy, it's up in Chernobyl, the next bus leaves in twenty minutes, hehe… Listen stalker, there have been many people before you that have come here looking to find the Wish Granter, you know what they all have in common? They are all feeding the worms right now. The Wish Granter is just a legend, it doesn't exist. Even if it did exist do you know what your wish would be if you found it? That you never went looking for it in the first place. You want to get rich, is that it? You don't need to wish for your fortune. Someone like you can make plenty of money here in the Zone if you are smart. Here is what I will do for you; show me your PDA… Ah, there, I've loaded in a list of contacts, people here in the Zone who I know are looking to have work done. Go visit them when you are ready, some of them pay well. In the meantime, ask around camp, there is plenty of work here, heck, I even have some jobs I need done from time to time. It's an honest living, at least as honest as it gets here in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- SIDOROVICH STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_esc_m_trader_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Thank you stalker. Listen, I hear you came here looking to find the Wish Granter, yes? I have important news for you. The Wish Granter does exist, it is not merely a legend. If you are brave or foolish enough to go looking for it now may be your only chance. The Monolith are congregating in Pripyat leaving only a few to defend Chernobyl. Even still, it will not be easy to get to. The entire area is flooded with anomalies that will rip you to shreds, rad levels that will kill you standing, and psi fields that will turn your mind to soup. Make sure you are prepared. Good luck to you stalker.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE DUTY GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- PETRENKO STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>I want to join Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Excellent! You have built quite a reputation for yourself stalker, we could use someone like you. Very well, let's get right to business. I need someone who knows how to navigate the Zone. We have many friends in various areas throughout the Zone who need our assistance but not many of our soldiers are able to reach them. I will send you to them They will tell you what they need done. Welcome aboard.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- PETRENKO STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Good job. There is one other thing I need you to do, well, that needs to be done. You must find the Wish Granter. The Monolith are guarding it deep within Chernobyl NPP. It must be destroyed. Listen carefully, I know exactly what you must do. The Wish Granter grants wishes, right? That is its weakness. Find it and wish for it to be destroyed. Do not fall into the temptation to wish for your own selfish desires, this is for the greater good. Find the Wish Granter and wish it out of existence. This is what you must do. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE FREEDOM GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- LUKASH STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>You wanted to see me, bro?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Yes, I have a very important assignment for you. We can't expect to protect the Zone from exploitation if we stay holed up in these warehouses. I need you to travel the Zone and help spread our influence. I've loaded a list of contacts for you to meet with into your PDA. Visit them and see if there is anything you can do to for them. This will strengthen our local relations and increase our allies to help keep the Zone free, and could earn you some sweet cash in the process.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- LUKASH STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Thanks. Listen, you want to keep the Zone free, right? You're going about it the wrong way. Spreading good will one person at a time will do you no good. Everyone here is corrupt, they only care about their own needs. Even if you manage to change that opinion in someone, they will be dead soon, so what's the point? The solution is obvious. The Brain Scorcher has been disabled, and the path to the Wish Granter is open, but few people know that yet. If you can be the first to get there you can use it to wish for the Zone to protect itself. Find the Wish Granter, but avoid the temptation to use it for your own desires. It will not be easy, but if you truely want to preserve the Zone, this is what you must do. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE CLEAR SKY GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 14, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- COLD STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>I'm ready for my mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Good, good. You know how important this mission is. You cannot fail. I regret we can't tell you any more about it, but the secrecy of this mission must be so absolute that there are parts even you must not know about. Just do as we planned. Meet with the people we discussed, their contact information is stored in your PDA. When the time is right all will be revealed. You will know exactly what you must do. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- COLD STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Good work. You have done very well. Now is the time to fulfill your mission. The path to Chernobyl has been cleared. At the heart of the reactor lies the Monolith, the Wish Granter. Find it. Then you know what you must do.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE ECOLOGIST GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- SAKHAROV STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_yan_stalker_sakharov_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>You wanted to see me, boss?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_yan_stalker_sakharov_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Oh, yes, yes. Good! I'm glad you're here. I have an important assignment for you. I want you to travel the Zone and learn as much as you can. There is so much out there we haven't yet discovered. Consider it… exploratory research. I've provided you with a list of contacts who will take care of you along your journey. Visit them, they can provide you with work or food or shelter. Explore and be curious! Be bold and adventurous! I expect your research will vastly increase our understanding of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- SAKHAROV STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_yan_stalker_sakharov_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Thanks. So, tell me, you've traveled the Zone and seen all of its wonders. But you haven't yet studied the biggest prize, have you? I speak of course of the Wish Granter. You can reach it now, if you prepare yourself. It will not be easy. Lethal levels of radiation, psi fields, mutants, and Monolith snipers all await you. But if you truely desire to understand the Zone, you must travel to where it all began, the NPP itself. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE MERCENARY GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- DUSHMAN STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_cit_killers_merc_trader_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>So what can you tell me about our employer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_cit_killers_merc_trader_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Pff.. Who knows? No one seems to know much about him. All I know is his money is good and he's got a lot of it. But we gotta work to get it. This place is a living hell from what I've heard, a real life waking nightmare. Hell, with the shit I've already seen I believe it. Doesn't matter though, ain't nothing out there I can't kill. Anyway, enough bullshit. You've got your job to do and I got mine. You got your list of contacts to meet? Good. Stay frosty out there. Good luck.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- DUSHMAN STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_cit_killers_merc_trader_stalker_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Thank you. Listen, I have a message for you. It comes straight from your employer. It seems you have impressed him greatly. He has a special mission for you and only you. You must find the Wish Granter. Once you do you must utter the following phrase; "princeps magis opulentus". Do this exact thing and your prince will reward you handsomely.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE MILITARY GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 14, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- KUZNETSOV STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>Reporting for duty, sir.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Welcome to hell soldier. You must have pissed someone off pretty bad to pull this assignment. Well, listen to me and you'll stay alive. Keep your head on a swivel. Everyone and everything out here is trying to kill you. Stay low in a firefight and find good cover. Trust no one. Shoot first and ask questions later. Your tour of duty will take you all over the Zone, most of the time no one will be there to help you. Rely on your survival training. Meet with the contacts loaded into your PDA and they will give you your orders. Just complete your tour of duty and stay alive and you'll get to go home. You are dismissed.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- KUZNETSOV STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Thank you soldier. You have done well for me, now I will do something for you, although you may not want to hear it. You are expecting to rotate out of here soon, yes? I'm afraid your commanders have other ideas. The cordon has closed in and has been locked down, nothing and no one are able to get in or out of the Zone anymore, including the military. You've been left here to die, and even your corpse will be left for worm food. You can't even escape in a body bag. But all hope is not lost for you, if you are daring. There is only one way left for you to get out of here, and it lies in Chernobyl. Buried deep within the NPP is the Wish Granter. If you can find it, and if you survive, you can use it to wish your way out of here. It is your only hope soldier. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE BANDIT GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- SULTAN STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>You want me to work for you? What's in it for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>There are people here in the Zone who need things done for them. Some of these things cannot be done, shall we say; inside of regular channels. So they come to me. I arrange to take care of business for them and in return I expect them to pay me a very hefty sum. I will give you a list of these people. Go to them, do what they ask, and collect the payment. All I require is you give me 20 percent of what they pay when you are finished. Any money you make on the side while you're out there is your's to keep. Good deal, yes? It's more money than you would make pick-pocketing and looting stashes and sticking up rookies I guarantee. Just don't double-cross me, understand? I know everyone in this place and they can be very motivated to make examples of anyone who tries to rip me off. Now get out of my sight. I have some important business to attend to.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- SULTAN STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>Wadda you want? .. *hic* .. Oh, itz you .. *hic* .. I know you. Hey, didja do that thing I wanted for ya to do? Ahhh, I knew you wouldn't let me down buddy, you're always buddy .. *hic* .. Here, join me inna drink.. inna.. where'z my bottle? .. *hic* .. It'z a celelelebration! Cus I'm gonna be rizssh! .. *hic*</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE MONOLITH GAME DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- RABBIT STORYLINE START GAME 1 DIALOG -->
	<string id="drx_sl_pri_monolith_monolith_trader_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_0">
		<text>What can I do to serve the almighty Monolith?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drx_sl_pri_monolith_monolith_trader_stalker_game_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>There is much work to be done, my brother. The Zone must be purged of the infidels. We must keep control of the mutant population. Your brothers need food and weapons. You will report to your Monolith elders and we will give you your assignments. You must do your part. Praise the Monolith, and may the Monolith bless you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- RABBIT STORYLINE START GAME 1 END GAME 1 TEXT: -->
	<string id="drx_sl_pri_monolith_monolith_trader_stalker_start_game_1_endgame_1">
		<text>You have done well, and have proven your faith with the many deeds you have done. You have earned the privilege of meeting the almighty Monolith. Not many are blessed enough to look into the eyes of god. Prepare an offering and pledge your devotion to our lord. The journey into the Sarcophagus will not be easy, and you must go alone. But listen, if your faith is pure the Monolith will call to you and show you the way.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
	<!--
	<!-- DRX STORYLINE CHANGE FACTIONS DIALOG STRINGS
	<!--
	<!--	Created by DoctorX
	<!--	for DoctorX Questlines 1.6
	<!--	October 06, 2016
	<!--
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<!-- ACTOR:  Requests to change factions: -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_change_factions_request">
		<text>I want to change factions.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR:  Accepts change factions task from npc -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_accept_change_factions_task">
		<text>I'll do it.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- NPC:  Affirmation of task acceptance: -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_change_factions_task_accepted">
		<text>See me when it's done.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR:  Leaves npc: -->
	<string id="st_drx_sl_change_factions_actor_exit">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>

<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ACTOR: Requests to get army permission: -->
	<string id="st_get_army_permission_request">
		<text>I need a certificate for being present in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR: Accepts change factions task from npc -->
	<string id="st_accept_army_permission_task">
		<text>All right. Here's the money.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- NPC: Affirmation of task acceptance: -->
	<string id="st_accept_army_permission_task_accepted">
		<text>Just a moment… Here you go. Try not to miss the deadline.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR: Leaves npc: -->
	<string id="st_accept_army_permission_task_exit">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>



<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ACTOR: Requests to get bandit permission: -->
	<string id="st_get_bandit_permission_request">
		<text>I need a truce with the bandits.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR: Accepts change factions task from npc -->
	<string id="st_accept_bandit_permission_task">
		<text>Here's the money.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- NPC: Affirmation of task acceptance: -->
	<string id="st_accept_bandit_permission_task_accepted">
		<text>Just wait a moment and I'll send the information… Done. For three days, you’ll be left alone. You can go about your business in peace.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR: Leaves npc: -->
	<string id="st_accept_bandit_permission_task_exit">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>

<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ACTOR: Requests to get killer permission: -->
	<string id="st_get_killer_permission_request">
		<text>I need a truce with the mercenaries.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR: Accepts change factions task from npc -->
	<string id="st_accept_bandit_permission_task">
		<text>Here's the money.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- NPC: Affirmation of task acceptance: -->
	<string id="st_accept_bandit_permission_task_accepted">
		<text>Just wait a moment and I'll send the information… Done. For a week, you’ll be left alone. You can go about your business in peace.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ACTOR: Leaves npc: -->
	<string id="st_accept_bandit_permission_task_exit">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>


<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->


	<!-- General -->
	<string id="dm_universal_actor_start">
		<text>I want to ask you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_universal_actor_exit">
		<text>Never mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_universal_actor_agree">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_universal_actor_exit_thanks">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_universal_npc_start_1">
		<text>About what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_universal_npc_start_2">
		<text>Sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_universal_npc_start_3">
		<text>Go ahead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_universal_npc_start_4">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_1">
		<text>I already told you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_2">
		<text>I don't know much more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_3">
		<text>That's all I know. Ask someone else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_4">
		<text>God damn, man. You got a hard-on for me? Ask someone else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_5">
		<text>Not much more I can tell ya, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_6">
		<text>You can keep asking the same shit, but I got nothing more to say.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_7">
		<text>Drop the subject, dude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_8">
		<text>Some other time, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_9">
		<text>Drop by later and maybe I can tell you more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_no_more_10">
		<text>Eh. I ain't getting into much more depth. You have any other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_1">
		<text>Bro, if I had all the answers, I wouldn't be in this shit dump.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_2">
		<text>Good question. If you find out, share that info with me, will you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_3">
		<text>You are putting me on the spot here, man. I don't know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_4">
		<text>Hell if I know, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_5">
		<text>There's always something going on in the Zone, but nothing I would like to share with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_6">
		<text>I've nothing to tell you, man. Nobody tells me shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_7">
		<text>You're asking the wrong guy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_8">
		<text>I'd like to know that too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_9">
		<text>Sorry. I can't help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_do_not_know_10">
		<text>Sorry. Got nothing.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Greetings -->
	<string id="dm_hello_general_1">
		<text>How's it going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_general_2">
		<text>Hey, man. What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_general_3">
		<text>Hello. How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_1">
		<text>Hello, brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_2">
		<text>Greetings, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_3">
		<text>I'm good. What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_4">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_5">
		<text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_6">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_7">
		<text>So far, so good. You?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_8">
		<text>Been better days. What do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_9">
		<text>Good day!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_10">
		<text>Yeah, what is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_11">
		<text>Piss off, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_12">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_13">
		<text>Okay, just one damn question, but all I better see after is asses and elbows.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_hello_14">
		<text>What do you need, stalker?</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Help -->
	<string id="dm_help_1">
		<text>Help, please… I'm dying…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_2">
		<text>Help me out, bro… Oh, God, it hurts!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_3">
		<text>Friend, medkit… Give me a medkit…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_4">
		<text>Bro… Bro, save me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_5">
		<text>Friend, the first aid kit… The kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_6">
		<text>Stalker, help me… Give me a medkit…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_7">
		<text>I'm hurt… Help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_8">
		<text>Screw this place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_9">
		<text>Medkit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_10">
		<text>Help, dude!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_11">
		<text>Medkit! Quick!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_12">
		<text>Help! I'm dying!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_13">
		<text>I need first aid, guys! Hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_14">
		<text>I need a medkit! Help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_15">
		<text>Medic!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_16">
		<text>Hey, bro, can you share your first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_17">
		<text>Get me a damn doctor! Urgh, have you got a medkit? Please! I need it!</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Anomalies -->
	<string id="dm_anomalies_general_1">
		<text>What do you know about anomalies or artefacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_general_2">
		<text>You know anything about anomalies or artefacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_general_3">
		<text>What can you tell me about anomalies or artefacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_0">
		<text>I don't feel comfortable telling you anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_1">
		<text>Well, the Burner anomaly can be a bit difficult to see; even during daylight, there's only a faint haze. If you piss it off with one of your bolts, it'll shoot a tall pillar of flame into the air, so keep your distance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_2">
		<text>Comet anomalies are a lot like the Burner, both fire-y, only… this is a big floating ball of flame that flies about wherever you might find it. Best to duck and dive about when near those things… otherwise, you'll get your ass burnt off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_3">
		<text>Vortex's are some sorta floating thing that drag everything nearby towards it and start spinning it around. If you get caught up in that, you'll get splattered all over the place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_4">
		<text>Springboards are these floating gravity balls… but you touch them, and whoosh: it'll blow up right in your face. You'll find them everywhere, and you'll probably hear them humming to you before you see them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_5">
		<text>You should keep an eye out for Whirligigs; dirt and leaves blowing about are a pretty good sign there's one nearby. I saw a flesh get pulled in to one when I was at the Cordon… Started spinning around 'til it just tore itself apart from the force.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_6">
		<text>The Fruit Punch is a glowing puddle of green shit on the floor which will hiss and spit at you. Might be able to get a good artefact from it if you're brave enough to get up next to it, but it'll melt your face off if you get a little too comfy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_7">
		<text>Burnt Fuzz anomalies are usually found outdoors. They look like moss or vines, hanging down like curtains… Shoots these spores in your face if you run up and touch it, like some kinda defence mechanism.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_8">
		<text>Look out for green Gas anomalies floating and wandering over the ground. It's acidic, and if you end up taking a stroll into the stuff, it'll start trying to eat away at your legs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_9">
		<text>Keep your eyes peeled for Gas Cloud anomalies. If you see a flying ball of acid darting around, go around or under that thing, or you'll wind up looking like a flesh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_10">
		<text>You ever see those giant electrical puddles on the ground? Electros is what the scientists call them. Most of them will only go off if something goes over and introduces itself, but half the time, I swear, they explode even when there's nothing there. Some of them seem to disappear for a few seconds, too. If you can time it right, then you can walk right past them, no problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_11">
		<text>Few days ago, I came across this floating ball of electricity. I think the eggheads named them after that electricity guy… Tesla, or whatever his name was. Anyway, I was in this hallway and it was pacing up and down… no, flying up and down. Had to time it right and go bit by bit through the room, hiding behind old junk and letting it keep passing me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_12">
		<text>You know how that Forester guy over in the Red Forest says he got stuck in one of those Space anomalies? Said it was like an open field of grass… Endless with no way out. That was until he found a Compass artefact which showed him the exit, just like the rumours say they do. He says he got mugged by a bunch of bandits not long after and lost it, but personally, I think the old coot's just going senile.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_13">
		<text>Few years ago, Clear Sky went after a stalker headed for the power plant. We all know how that ended, but there was this merc with them: Scar. The few of the people that survived the mess say these anomalies started showing up all over the place that let him teleport closer to the guy he was after, like the Zone was helping him. Weird shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_14">
		<text>Ever seen any jagged rocks sticking out from the ground with a bunch of warped trees nearby? Me neither, but I've heard there's something like that over in the Red Forest. Apparently, those Symbiont anomalies are pretty good for artefacts; you can get all kinds of stuff out of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_15">
		<text>The scientists are scratching their heads over those Fault anomalies. They're these cracks, huge fractures in the ground; usually have a whole bunch of Comets and other anomalies underneath them. They've no idea if they're just anomaly fields or if there's something else to them. When was the last time you heard of an earthquake in this part of the world?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_16">
		<text>You don't always have to crawl through anomalies to find artefacts. Someone told me a story of how they found an artefact in an open field. A stalker's detector starts going crazy, so he figures it has a blown capacitor. He replaces it, it starts working, and lo and behold, an artefact practically falls into his hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_17">
		<text>Watch out for Whirligig and Vortex anomalies, man. Absolutely dangerous, even for an experienced stalker. It will snatch you up and violently shake you around like a rag doll. One time, I saw this dude get caught up in one. I thought I would be getting me a new pair of boots, but this sucker started running as fast as he could. I couldn't believe this shit. He dove right outta there before he was shredded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_18">
		<text>Ever heard of a Gravi? Looks like something a pseudodog would shit out, but it's metallic. Scientists are willing to pay well for these things. I wouldn't bother, though; anyone who touches one of those will be glowing for a month. There are similar artefacts called Goldfish. I'm sure you can guess what it looks like, 'cause it's even more rare. Better keep it to yourself if you find one, though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_19">
		<text>The first thing you should try to get your hands on is at least a Medusa. The more radiation-absorbing an artefact you can get, like a Wrenched or a Bubble, the safer you will be. I've already seen too many stalkers slowly dying of radiation without being able to reach a medic, or even too poor to buy themselves some anti-rads.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_20">
		<text>I can't figure out what the scientists make from the artefacts they buy from the Zone. All I know is cash for these seems to be limitless. And whatever if the thing is positive or not… The more powerful an artefact is, the more they pay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_21">
		<text>Have you ever heard of the Glass? It looks like a dirty and yet shiny glass ball. Man, this thing could stop bleeding from the worst wounds if you have something to cure its radiation. Don't sell it if you find one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_22">
		<text>I've heard of something called the Compass several times. It would appear that this artefact would be almost perfect, apart from the radiation it emits. It was rumoured that it protects against many of the risks of the Zone, but on top of that, it would seem that the wearer naturally finds some paths through the worst anomaly fields.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_23">
		<text>What more can I tell you other than the stories everybody hears here around campfires? If you want advice, just take care about everything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_24">
		<text>I often hear stories about some untouched, wonderful artefact fields that could make a poor, inexperienced stalker a rich man. My opinion is that all of these are traps. How can anyone logically think about getting into such anomaly mazes, just out of greed?… Especially knowing that the anomalies can move, and so, close any exits… If you think about it, the little shiny things that attract you to themselves are perfect in their roles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_25">
		<text>All I can say is to be really careful about the gear you choose and why. Don't expect to go for an artefact hunt with a heavy shielded exo. It can become like a pin with electric fields and will melt on you like hot chocolate in chemical ones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_26">
		<text>The hardest thing about artefact hunting is starting. If you can grab a protective artefact, you can then explore other anomalies of the same type easily; then sell your findings, get better gear, and so on. Plus, the more you cross them, the more you'll know how to do it. Just be really careful. From your beginner's hours to an experienced stalker, if you come to be one, the Zone always keep new traps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_27">
		<text>Be in good shape; that's the clever advice I can give to you. The Zone can be really harsh and outright exhaustive sometimes. You'll have better chances in surviving long trips and their inevitable hazards if your body is ready for it. It's true about anomalies, too; do you think you can cross a chemical field with a pack of mutants at your back, after a night of vodka abuse?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_28">
		<text>Many stalkers, particularly regular users of vodka, don't pay attention to the psychic dangers of the Zone… and so, they kick the bucket when they have to get out of a psi-field. It's a good thing to find some psi-protection; the Moonlight artefact can make the difference in decisive moments. Plus, it can be useful against a controller, for instance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_29">
		<text>Keep in mind that some people here don't bother to chase artefacts. They prefer to hunt humans… In other words, pay attention to the bandits. It's well known they have artefact orders for their black market. Don't let too many people know what artefacts you have, either.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_30">
		<text>Did you know that artefacts are almost indestructible? Sometimes it's better to shoot at the artefact to make it jump out of the anomaly, instead of just being sucked directly into it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_31">
		<text>I wish I had known the Zone that I've heard about: the one that was like a no man's land. How can we get rich these days, when, after every emission, a bunch of stalkers rush to every anomaly field to pick up their flowers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_32">
		<text>Why should I give you any advice, more so when it comes to the business many of us use for making money? Well, get a good detector and help yourself. The scientists will probably sell you what you're looking for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_33">
		<text>Many newcomers dream about 'the artefact that makes you rich'. Even if the Zone can be fruitful, it often takes a long time and a serious amount of money to get the gear that lets you head to the most dangerous and productive areas. Of course, you can be lucky… but knowing this place, I wouldn't count so much on that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_34">
		<text>You know where the dredge station is? It's been battered up by gravitational anomalies, but not too bad for an experienced stalker. Just keep throwing bolts as usual. There's also radiation, inside and out… It's like being next to a massive chunk of enriched uranium.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_35">
		<text>Sometimes you don't even have to jump into anomalies to scare up an artefact. I've been told of an artefact found out in the open field. This one stalker had a detector that started acting up, so he decided to change the batteries. As soon as he did, the detector shows a reading, and bam: an artefact basically drops in his hands. Lucky bastard, eh? That's the Zone for you: sometimes it punishes you, and sometimes it rewards you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_36">
		<text>The surest place is the acid swamp. It's full of gravitational anomalies, but those are easy to spot. Just keep your eye on the water surface and you can't go wrong. Gas anomalies are more of a pain, because there's basically no air to breathe. Getting squirted by one is no fun, believe me. That thing eats through a vest faster than sulphuric acid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_37">
		<text>There's an old substation here, also called the Iron Forest. You'll understand why when you see it. Some people claim to have found clusters of artefacts in that area after emissions. It's not all that dangerous: mainly electric anomalies and a bit of radiation… There are also a few poltergeists that will bury you in all kinds of crap if you don't hide in time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_38">
		<text>There are plenty of heat anomalies at the burnt farmstead up on the hill. People find fire artefacts there. Look in the houses: whichever's got the most anomalies in it after an emission, that's where the artefacts will be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_39">
		<text>There are probably lots of them in the caves under the burnt farmstead. If you walk on the hill with a detector, it won't stop beeping. Getting to them is easy enough: just jump in through the gap from above. Getting out is the hard part, what with all the anomalies down there. Mostly vortexes and acid. Some also claim to have seen something resembling a comet in that gap. A whole mix of dangers, to be sure, but that means the artefacts are probably mixed as well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_40">
		<text>Have you seen a Circus anomaly? It's a huge springboard anomaly with two comets going round and round… Quite a sight to behold. Behold it from a distance, though, because Circuses are hot as hell, with lots of heat anomalies. It's got plenty of artefacts, too, but they're guarded by a nasty fire poltergeist that tries to roast you up when you come near.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_41">
		<text>There's this place they call Scar, where the ground looks like it's been hacked with an axe. People have found artefacts there, but once you go in there, something weird starts to happen. That thing hits your brains so hard you almost forget how to breathe, let alone try to get your ass out of there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_42">
		<text>If you're interested in gravitational artefacts, look for them in the Fang anomaly. The place is easy to spot; anomalies have done a job on the terrain and taken half the hill clean off. A few caves opened up in the hill and were immediately settled by snorks, but thankfully, they rarely head outside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_43">
		<text>There's a spot in Zaton where heat anomalies emerged underwater. They call it 'Boiler' because there's steam and stuff coming out from the ground. If you think steam is nothing, think again. Seasoned stalkers say this kind of vapour anomaly hits you at least as hard as a regular heat anomaly… if not harder. The temperature may be a bit lower, but it grills you longer. As for artefacts, there are regular ones there; the fire kind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_44">
		<text>They say there's a nice spot in the quarry with lots of artefacts, though not scant on anomalies either. Down at the bottom, there are so many bubbles from gas anomalies… It hurts your eyes, even with a gas mask on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_45">
		<text>The Ash Heap is at the old graveyard near Kopachy. There are lots of heat anomalies, and also some zombies from time to time. People try to avoid the place, but they do find artefacts there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_46">
		<text>They say artefacts have been found in the parking lot. Still got vehicles from the first Chernobyl disaster; those babies give the rad counter heartburn. In addition, the lot is full of electrical anomalies as well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_47">
		<text>In the Putrid Grove, where trees are all warped from acid. People who've been there say it's full of gas anomalies. There's so much gas in the air that you can't see straight, but with enough experience, you can find the artefacts you're looking for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_48">
		<text>If you're after artefacts, go for the acid kind. The best place to get those is the Concrete Bath. You won't have a lot of competition: no one likes that place because of its proximity to the Jupiter building.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_49">
		<text>Not far from the Jupiter plant, a piece of the road fell through. They call this place Bitumen, because that's where the pavement melted. There are many anomalies in the gap: heat anomalies mixed with gravitational ones. And since it's two kinds of anomalies, the artefacts must be of a different kind, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_50">
		<text>There's a small harbour beyond the cement plant called Fen, which has turned into a terrible stinking marsh full of gas anomalies. It's not even really water any more… More like acid. People have found artefacts there before, but the place is also teeming with monsters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_51">
		<text>Look in the old cement plant; lots of anomalies, but it's worth it. Sure, there are spots where artefacts are easier to come by, but so's the competition. Here, your only competition consists of hamsters, and that's only if you go down in the basement.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_52">
		<text>You should look near the Oakpine. That's that thing growing between the hills, above the gas anomalies. Everyone's been calling it that since some geek identified the bark from that tree as both pine and oak. If you want to search for artefacts there, you'll need good chemical protection. Take lots of ammo, too, because those hills are home to packs and packs of dogs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_53">
		<text>I've heard from seasoned stalkers that artefacts sometimes move outside of anomalies. Your detector starts going 'peep', you take it out, but there's nothing there. That means a 'nomadic' artefact walked past you… but it's no use chasing it, because only the Zone decides who to reward it with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_54">
		<text>No one has looked for artefacts in Pripyat yet. Everyone I know has only been here a short while, so they stay cautious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_55">
		<text>I don't know if anyone knows the good spots. Pripyat is poorly explored so far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_56">
		<text>I'd look in the underground tunnels. They say there are tons of them underneath the city.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_anomalies_57">
		<text>Not much is known about these parts… Garry's stories, mostly. He says there's a place here where a huge grapevine grows out of an acid anomaly, as tall as a ten-story building. He might be pulling our leg, but I'd check out that vine for artefacts just in case.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Information -->
	<string id="dm_information_general_1">
		<text>What's new in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_general_2">
		<text>You know what's going on around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_general_3">
		<text>I'm looking for information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_0">
		<text>I don't have any information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_1">
		<text>The army set up a base in Agroprom; right in the middle of it. Place is packed with dogs and other mutants just running around with nothing stopping them. By itself, it ain't so special, but there's this huge subterranean underground full of anomalies sitting right below it. If it weren't for the soldiers, I'd be down there right now hauling a whole bunch of artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_2">
		<text>The Agroprom underground is sat underneath the research institute buildings. I hear different things about it all the time: one day I hear it's full of anomalies, perfect for artefact hunting, and next it's barren, nothing but mutants… Next I hear, the place is full of controllers and poltergeists. Me? I don't even know what to believe. Damned if I'll be going down there with all the jar-heads patrolling aboveground, though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_3">
		<text>You ever been to Rostok? You've got the 100 Rads and the arena just across the street from each other to keep you busy. A real shining star in the middle of the Earth's asshole, don't you think? Whole place used to be a giant factory complex, so Duty found it perfect to set up their base of operations there. I'm not complaining, though; they do a good job of keeping all the filth out. You won't see any bandits or mutants about the place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_4">
		<text>The Cordon is quieter than most other areas. Most stay at the Rookie village north of the actual military cordon until they have enough gear and experience to head deeper into the Zone. You'll find Nimble and Sidorovich there too, Nimble will help you get hold of really high-end gear, best of the best, while Sid sits down in his bunker where he'll sell you smuggled in goods; food, medical supplies, you get the idea.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_5">
		<text>The Darkscape connects the southern edge of the Dark Valley with the tunnel in the east of the Cordon. Full of forest, mutants, bandits, and anomalies, but somehow you'll always find a group of loners down there for whatever reason. I wouldn't stick too close to the road, either; you'll leave glowing from the radiation, or you'll get torn apart by a pack of dogs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_6">
		<text>The Dark Valley is a forbidding place, filled with rusting wrecks and crumbling buildings. There are a few anomalies nearby where you can try your luck artefact hunting… but the bandits occupy the factory in the north, so good luck not getting mugged afterwards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_7">
		<text>The Dead City is right between Yantar and Limansk with a whole gathering of mercs right in the middle. There's gotta be a huge stash of guns and meds in there somewhere… Where else do they keep all their shit? If you wanna get through the place without getting your ass beat, I heard you could sneak about through the sewers. Not much else I can tell you, bro.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_8">
		<text>You know they dumped all their ruined machines and vehicles after the disaster in Garbage, right? Loners and bandits are always trying to get the best loot, shooting at each other all the time while trying not to get chewed up by the mutants. There's a whole grouping of anomalies in the little vehicle graveyard, too. You're almost guaranteed an artefact if you get there right after an emission hits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_9">
		<text>Ever been to the Generators? They're found up north beyond the power plant. There are six of them in a ring formation with the old war lab not far south. Not much to look at besides a few old labs, but plenty of mutants to keep your gun busy while you're there, if that's your thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_10">
		<text>We occupy nearly all of the Deserted Hospital. Most of the paths through that lead further towards the Chernobyl NPP are fenced off by a machine gun emplacements or some other shit. No stalkers will be getting through there any time soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_11">
		<text>Jupiter is still unsettled, much like Zaton… and since they turned on the Brain Scorcher, it's almost impossible to get to there without putting your neck on the line. If you don't wanna get your brains scrambled, then your only path is through the Red Forest… Not that you'll make it through alive with mutants and anomalies hiding behind all the trees.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_12">
		<text>Thinking of travelling through the Jupiter underground? You'll need a suit with a closed cycle respiratory module due to the harsh conditions within, but it'll let you go right beneath Pripyat directly to the Outskirts so you can avoid all the cultists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_13">
		<text>Limansk is an empty place, full of derelict buildings and vehicles. I heard the mercs tried to push through it from the Dead City recently, although they didn't make it that far… Lost too many men to the anomalies and mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_14">
		<text>The Great Swamps are mostly a wet and irradiated hole in the ground, but you'll find a few abandoned buildings and settlements here and there, which are worth looting. There's also the Clear Sky base somewhere towards the south. Quite an isolated place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_15">
		<text>Ever heard about the army warehouses? Freedom set up their headquarters there after they got their ass handed to them by bandits a couple years back; claim they're protecting the Zone by defending the barrier there, which leads to Radar. Complete nonsense, if you ask me. If the bandits could tear 'em a new one you can be sure the Monolith would have already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_16">
		<text>The Monolith are holed up in Pripyat, from what I've heard. No way of getting through all of the anomalies and mutants with them shooting at you the whole time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_17">
		<text>You should consider checking out the Pripyat outskirts; plenty of anomalies to make you rich, and you won't even have to go through the plaza to get there, either. Just take the underground passage through Jupiter, which, by the way, is clear of any Monolithians.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_18">
		<text>Those bastards turned the Brain Scorcher back on when they took the Radar. There's no way to the other side of the Zone now, unless you feel like being fed to the local wildlife or being turned into one of those zombies like the ones you see in Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_19">
		<text>More and more stalkers have gotten themselves killed trying to get through the Red Forest since the takeover of the Radar. Forester can only do so much with their equipment to help, and I don't feel like sticking my balls in the frying pan for the sake of a few artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_20">
		<text>The Wild Territory used to be the site of a rather large manufacturing plant, but now the place is swarming with monsters and is full of anomalies. Only real reason to go through there is if you want to get to Rostok or if you're desperate for loot, and there are plenty of other safe routes to use instead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_21">
		<text>What would you wish for? What's the one thing you really want? If you help me find the Wish Granter, then maybe it will come true. I've heard it's buried under the power plant somewhere. Do you think that maybe that's what the Monolith are fighting to protect?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_22">
		<text>Yantar is morbid and sodden with death. Anyone who dares to go too far goes insane. Zombies and snorks are all over the place just waiting to introduce themselves to you. They keep spewing out of that factory, and half of the time when the scientists gun them down, they realise it's one of their own men who was shooting at them. It's real fucked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_23">
		<text>Hey, stalker, if you're ever up in Zaton, you should check out the Skadovsk; it's this old rusty ship run by this stalker calling himself Beard, or at least he likes to think he does. You can find somewhere to sleep, repair your gear, and sell all your loot. Owl's always interested in buying those extra PDAs off of your hands if they have any nice info on them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_24">
		<text>Hey, listen, have you caught word of a guy called the Black Digger? I heard that he used to be a really lucky fella. Got himself a nice amount of roubles and a plethora of nice items as well. Some say that he had a secret stash of his own hidden deep among piles of junk and other crap. I'd really like to find him some day and beat the info out of him, but it seems like his secret went together with him to the grave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_25">
		<text>It probably won't be long until either of us gets tasked with recovering information deep down in some derelict laboratory. X18 is manageable… X16 is tougher on your psyche, and has more humanoids to fill with an extra hole or two.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_26">
		<text>If you have a job that requires you to get to either Jupiter or the eastern part of Pripyat and its outskirts, use the underpass to make it past the Pripyat undetected; you won't have to deal with the fanatics aboveground. You'll most likely have to deal with just mutants and zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_27">
		<text>Be wary of machine gun nests scattered around certain strongholds and strategical locations. The gunner obviously can't hit you when you're facing his back, so sneaking up to him is a valid strategy as long as you don't screw up and make yourself known to everyone around him. Usually, everyone will be in enough of a panic to not take over the fallen gunner's position. Don't forget about grenades, as well: a well placed throw can be enough to take one out if you're in a pinch and can't move out of cover.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_28">
		<text>If you feel like taking a long stroll, or taking out an outpost on your way to the bandit base in the Dark Valley, then I suggest turning east in the Cordon and going that way until you reach the Darkscape. Sometimes a squad or two may also be on patrol there, but watch out for the mutants anyway. It's a relatively quiet place, but those mutant shits don't care where to breed. As for the outpost I mentioned earlier, it is located approximately in the middle, right where the road curves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_29">
		<text>Looking for some info, eh? I can tell you that as long as you remain under our protection, the mercenaries will not lay a finger on you. We are not worthy enough of being the target of their contractors, because the previous leaders have been taken out… They've perished, vanished, kissed their life goodbye, whatever you want to call it. No one is looking to step up to take leadership again, and besides, we'd bitch too much about this and that being wrong. The only person so far keeping a watch over a small area is Sultan, but his hand obviously doesn't extend far enough to reach every single bandit across the entire Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_30">
		<text>Are you feeling like taking someone's ripe life? The loners have always been a prime choice for that. We've been pissing them off since the dawn of time, and those jackasses have always deserved to be messed around with. Most aren't armed with great weaponry, but they do hate us enough to put up a nice fight, so you can get both decent equipment and combat practice from them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_31">
		<text>Hey, have you ever seen an orange midget making his way through dense reeds? I sure have, and those garbage bags stand out so well that you can spot a scientist a mile away without even needing to use your binoculars. Recently, I've noticed that they've been using colour variations that look less like the vomit inducing rubbish those scientists usually get issued.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_32">
		<text>The only things that have less brains in their heads than those mongrel loners are the members of the Monolith faction. It's amusing to hear tales about them and their actions; they seem like the Zone's version of retards who can think about only one thing and nothing else. Too bad that their stupidity makes them fear death less.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_33">
		<text>Man, I remember tales about how long ago, some guys sporting a scorpion on their patches kicked the shit out of some boys in blue pyjamas. Everyone here always jokes about them and their clothing because they were weaker than a blind baby bloodsucker crawling in its nest… Oh, wait, now that I remember, that does make sense… All the eggheads were terrible at holding guns in their hands. They just don't know how to live on what the Zone gives them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_34">
		<text>If only you knew what I'd give for a mutant wave large enough to overrun Rostok. Every single time when we try to get near it, we get kicked out of it by those fools in black and red. They've settled in there real well; even managed to set up a pair of PKMs to ward off intruders like us. They're armed pretty well, but their command structure… He-he, they're not the purest out of all in the Zone. Plenty of secret deals between us and Duty, but now they want everyone to keep their mouths shut, and they don't want to see our mugs close to theirs. God knows when they'll stop throwing a tantrum about their scarred pride.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_35">
		<text>Freedom used to boast about their strength and 'freedom in the Zone'. We showed them just what freedom can do out here and they had to move their sorry asses far away from us. These days, they'll want you to think otherwise, and that they switched bases because it's 'safer from the mutants' or that 'we can perform our duty of keeping the invaders at bay more easily'. Remember, pal: it's all bullshit. They just don't want to admit that we struck fear deep into their ranks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_36">
		<text>The army boys don't show up as much as they used to back in the day. Word has spread that their operations have gone down the gutter. I definitely wouldn't feel great being commanded by some wanker who just wants me to rip a mutant pack or a stalker group apart only for his own benefit. They have it tough, sure, but it looks like their failures have actually managed to knock some sense into their skulls.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_37">
		<text>The advent of artefacts and their in-depth studying sometimes leaves me wondering how much worse things can get. These things possess untold properties, some so devastating that their incorporation into weapons could surpass anything made so far. Just imagine what a bomb built upon the harnessed energy of various kinds of artefacts could do!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_38">
		<text>I find it ironic how Freedom is the faction that keeps talking about the need to let everyone make use of the Zone, while Duty are the ones who come to Yantar to protect us and give artefacts to our leading scientists in order to help them with finding new ways to extinguish the Zone's life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_39">
		<text>The bandits keep taking hostages to extort money and various valuables. They don't care about honesty and keeping their word, not to forget about the fact that they act like idiots and the lowest forms of life. They have it better when someone smarter comes along, although they've been keeping low for a while now, and no dedicated leader has stepped up yet to take control of every bandit establishment around the whole Zone. Right now, they're mostly sticking to small and organised groups scattered about, which makes it harder to instil confusion and panic amongst them when someone important draws their last breath.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_40">
		<text>Some places can look more foreboding than they really are. The Agroprom underground serves as an example to this, because right now, various parts of it are closed off, and the mutants don't have a lot of places to infest. I don't suggest going there unless you either want to dump your equipment or actually try to scavenge something from all the junk that's lying around. Stashing your loot in a backpack in a hard to reach place aboveground would be a better idea anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_41">
		<text>The Zone can be fascinating at times. Just watching the world below you when you're sitting atop a watchtower or another tall structure, with all the life running around, the wonderful formations the anomalies create, listening to the soothing music playing over at the 100 Rads while watching night taking over day's place… That's what I like about the Zone: it's fatal, but beautiful at the same time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_42">
		<text>If I'm still going to have to sit here and do nothing other than pellet some puny mutants with my weapon, then I'm going to have to reconsider my choice of joining Duty. Every day I get pushed around to do this and that, but what do I get? Barely anything. I've been here for long enough to be dispatched to far more dangerous areas, but it looks like a bunch of other guys have fallen into the same hole that I have. It's almost as if the top brass doesn't want to get down to really serious things and is just sitting safely in their bases until an opportunity comes so close that it can knock them out of their chairs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_43">
		<text>Freedom may seem like a bunch of lunatics and people who are lazily sitting on their asses, but they can be pretty slick when the need to be such comes to them. They've managed to spread misinformation about us before to reduce the faith of other stalkers in Duty. Besides that, they also keep on saying how protecting the barrier is their doing and how much better it makes them than us. Don't even think about believing their bullshit; they haven't been protecting the barrier that long, and they've never played a large enough role in it… until they came over to crash at the warehouses, that is. We'll get back at them for trying to create a larger figure of authority about this 'defending' at a later time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_44">
		<text>I've seen a lot of things in the Zone during my travels here, and most of it has come from the times when I wasn't a part of Duty. Hell, the military stalkers are probably the toughest you'll ever meet, bar the lunatics who keep pouring in from the north. Unlike the military forces who don't go that deep into the Zone or haven't been here long enough, they have received special training, or have experienced enough themselves; they possess equipment that easily outmatches that of most. They're fierce opponents in battle, sure, but if you're enough of a hotshot, you can try taking them out on your own… though I wouldn't suggest doing so even if our ties with military stalkers are far, far more loose than the ones with the regular soldiers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_45">
		<text>I'm sick of how everyone perceives us to be just a collective of potheads gathered around to do nothing other than praising the Zone and its creations. We really do try to spread useful information that we've acquired to those that need it, and we take hostile action when it's needed and when there's enough danger, unlike Duty, which likes to tell everyone otherwise while they're acting like a bunch of tough kids who do nothing other than beat up pathetic bandits and weak mutants when they're not just sitting at their base shooting up dogs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_46">
		<text>One of the figures that we consider to be rather important is Forester. He has a keen eye on finding various paths through the dense forest, but, alas, his old age has got the best of him… He can't help himself that much outside his safe haven any more. He provided valuable assistance to Scar, thus being able to provide help to Lebedev. Forester can still be found in the Red Forest… I believe that he'll remain there for the rest of his life until he withers away enough to remain as just a memory imprinted in our minds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_47">
		<text>A couple of years ago, we were led by Lebedev. Those were dog days, until a merc came along and helped us get our footing in the Swamps. But then, the whole Strelok thing got out of hand. Most of Clear Sky followed Lebedev and the merc north to sort it all out… Well, you know how that went. Anyway, we keep hearing about the death trucks in the Cordon, bringing back old friends. On the rare occasion, there are some signs of life, but it's like they've had a massive stroke or something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_48">
		<text>New in the Zone? Listen to yourself; you almost sound like one of those bastards out there. Information, huh… Ever heard of Major Kuznetsov? He was a real piece. After he replaced Major Khaletskiy for the trouble he was causing, Kuznetsov goes and does the same thing! It's always the high ranking officers that are corrupted. They get a little taste of power and control, and then start trying to make extra on the side through the criminals here in the Zone! I heard he met with a terrible fate when he crossed paths with that one guy… I can't recall his name, but they picked him up in Pripyat. Heard it was because he had some real important information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_49">
		<text>We've got more guys getting dropped in later in the month. Just waiting for the Zone to give us some quiet time so the pilots can make it in and out. Rumour has it there are some French, Finnish, and British operatives coming in this time… Should be interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_50">
		<text>Things may be rough out here, but it doesn't mean the research has stopped. We're managing with handmade gear, and now and again, we manage to grab equipment from the scientists. You'd be surprised at what we know about anti-coagulation from bloodsuckers and lens repair from flesh eyes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_51">
		<text>We're still losing friends to the Brain Scorcher. You hear about veterans who have taken drugs or put a bucket on their head… They endure the headaches and hallucinations and manage to actually grab some loot and artefacts and make it back to the camp in one piece. Of course, sometimes they can barely talk, or they're losing their marbles. But people see them celebrating or retiring, and they decide to do the same.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_52">
		<text>They say there's work at Yantar near the psi-field, if you're dumb enough. They need to test out drugs and suits in order to push forward and make for the north. Trouble is, there's no guarantee of you coming back. They say your head boils and your body doesn't work properly; you start to hallucinate or lose your speech. Your best friend might suddenly be your worst enemy. It's probably the most dangerous job out there right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_53">
		<text>The Brain Scorcher, man. There's a big race to find a way through it, whether it's by using a suit, or finding some sort of tunnel past the thick of it. Of course, everyone from the scientists to the military want to find a way past it, and whoever gets there first is going to get a treasure trove of artefacts, loot, and information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_54">
		<text>Man, I miss the old base back in the Dark Valley. The area was creepy as shit sometimes, but we had a pretty good camp back then. But as soon as the bandits started wandering round from the Garbage, it got harder and harder to keep a footing there. Duty would push, and the bandits would press, and then in the end, we'd be losing guys and outposts like water through a sieve. Still, at least we're set up here. We can go to sleep at night and only have to deal with the weird dreams… and possibly a hangover in the morning.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_55">
		<text>You tried any of the local cuisine yet? There's some pretty messed up wildlife out there, but you can make a pretty good meal out of the flesh and boars. I've even heard about some of these guys eating snork hands… I mean, isn't that cannibalism? Then there are bloodsucker tentacles or flesh eyes. It's like some of the veterans don't know about canned food.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_56">
		<text>So I went out on a job with one of the older guys the other day; they've been here for years, and you can see it. He was telling me about how his squad got stuck in a space anomaly. Yeah, it wasn't fatal like the Whirligigs or Burners, but it trapped them for days… Just stuck in the same patch of grass with no supplies or communications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_57">
		<text>There are some pretty rough patrols out there, and then some cosy ones. If you get the Great Swamps, then you'll usually have aerial support from a chopper, and the outposts we hold tend to be pretty comfortable for a wasteland. But the stalkers and bandits who reside there will sometimes make a push and try and grab some land. So long as you keep your head down, the chopper usually scatters them. The Darkscape is the road heading north-east from here up to the Dark Valley. It's pretty grim over there, with the bandits constantly trying to ambush anyone using the road, and the mutants really stirring up at night. Then there's Agroprom. Agroprom is a mixed bag. You've got our military facility to bunk up at in the evening, but if you have to go out on patrol, you'll be clashing with stalkers on your left and then getting attacked by mutants on your right. Moral of the story? Stick to the Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_58">
		<text>So when the Zone first… erm… erupted?… Anyway, we were constantly babysitting the scientists who were getting flown in. They'd have these tiny little bunkers full of science-y crap and then they'd tip toe outside in these stupid rubber suits. Meanwhile, we're all in fatigues, caked in mud with nowhere to sleep or take shelter in. Every night, the sky would be bright red, and any patrol caught out in the wilds would come back as zombies. We'd get picked off by bloodsuckers and blown apart by anomalies, and all the while, these eggheads were more concerned about their research and artefacts. In the end, we bailed. We moved to Agroprom and sent over minimal support from time to time. Now, the scientists realise they can't just rely on other people to take their bullets. They've got themselves armed with weapons, and their suits are starting to have thicker kevlar… and every night, I have a bunk and a bottle of vodka waiting for me. That's justice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_59">
		<text>I'm new here, but I've learnt a few things from the other guys. Always keep some bolts with you, preferably with string attached. We picked it up from the stalkers, originally. You throw the bolt ahead of you to check for anomalies. Sounds ridiculous, but in the Zone, it's a lifesaver.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_60">
		<text>Be sure to grab any medical supplies from the stalkers or bandits you fight. They may not be sterile, or ideal for trauma compared to army or scientific medkits, but they can save your buddy when he's downed. The friends you make in the Zone are the greatest friends you'll ever have; always have a medkit spare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_61">
		<text>We used to have a big problem with the renegades; outcasts who stumbled into the Swamps. We rallied together, and with help from Scar, we managed to kick their asses. Now the military have moved in, and they have themselves a chopper. Honestly, things seemed rough back then, but I really miss it. The military have really dug in deep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_62">
		<text>There's a real demand for tools in the Zone; more intricate gear for adjustments to weapons and suits. I found a set on some guy I shot a couple of months ago, but we had to stash them in a hurry. Not sure where they we hid them, but I'm sure a trader might have the coordinates if you do a few jobs for them.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- MISERY -->
	<string id="dm_information_63">
		<text>Sometimes I like to sit in the camp, chill out and just listen to the radio, you know? It's a reliable way to forget about all your problems and shit, even if for a second. Sometimes you need that little bit of escape and you gotta reach out to the outside world, otherwise the Zone will overwhelm you and you won't be able to carry on no longer. And the radio gets the job done real well. The tricky question is where the fuck the signal is coming from… Maybe there's this dude sitting by himself in a cosy shack on the fringes of the Zone who sends out a broadcast to keep people's spirit up? Or maybe we're being manipulated by the army? You know, subliminal messages and shit… I'd really like to know the story behind it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_64">
	 	<text>Why are you here, Stalker? Some pieces of shit are here out of curiosity or even just for the hell of it. Knifing those bastards usually makes me very happy, but most of the time I stick to the job. You see, I'm here for the job, whatever that might be. I'd rape a fucking flesh if I could get some money out of it. See, I don't care, I know what I'm here for, and none of these idealistic bastards could ever say that. So think about it. But don't think too much or you might end up in a ditch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_65">
		<text>I wonder what those freaking "animal rights" activists would say about the way we treat animals here. Fuck, are those things even "animals"? I call them hell spawns, and I usually shoot them in the face, because that's what you do to hell spawns, you don't protect them, feed them or, God forbid, nurture them. You fill 'em with lead and you move along before their friends arrive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_66">
		<text>You want excitement? Is this place too boring for you? Go say hello to a snork or a bloodsucker. If you're polite enough, they won't even get aggressive. It's weird, I had this one friend, he robbed people for a living, and he was dead set on doing this shit. I haven't seen him since but it sure is worth a try, don't you think? It's strange why not many people have tried this, it's bound to work, you don't even have to carry any weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_67">
		<text>My grandfather fought for the country, my father died for this piece of land and I'd be damned if I let this black hole eat my motherland away. The last thing my grandfather said before he succumbed to the crippling cancer was that I need to take care of my land. That is what I'm doing here, or rather was what I was supposed to be doing here. Things have changed now, I'm not even sure who I'm supposed to fight for. I had to put a bullet through the spine of a good friend of mine. The fool didn't "believe" in emissions, so when a psionic storm hit, he was out gathering flowers or doing some other stupid shit. Afterwards, he went insane and started shooting at everyone and everything. I had to take him down. The same guy that I shared food with, the same guy that saved my ass every time I fucked up. What am I supposed to tell his kids now? Fuck this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_68">
		<text>They say that I made a mistake coming here. They're a bunch of cowards. I'd rather be here than stuck behind some shitty desk. That's what would really finish me off, not a mutated puppy, but mindless, endless paperwork. Demons live inside those gigantic stacks of papers, not under Pripyat sewers. This is where I belong, and this place is where I can actually be myself. Camo suits me much better than any tie, and a rifle speaks in a much clearer voice than any "president" or "director".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_69">
		<text>Check the sky and the surroundings as often as you can. The moment you don't look, all hell will break loose, emissions will appear and mutants will bite your ass off. Fight sleepiness by taking caffeine, eating food, just do whatever you need to do to keep awake. I sleep for only two or three hours a day, and always with a shooter beside me. This is something you either do, or you don't, and if you don't, you'll be pushing up daisies in no time. Keep that in mind and get your shit together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_70">
		<text>People do drugs here, it's shit and it fucks them up real bad, but you do whatever you can to survive. If that means doing coke probably cut with detergent, then it's coke and detergent all the way. I've seen some guys that won't even touch the food unless they're high on some crap. I'd wager if they don't get their daily fix, they would rather starve to death than eat food that usually smells of dog piss. Junkies don't live long enough here though. If you get addicted, the first thing you start doing is thieving, later you join the bandits, but soon enough you start thieving from them, and that's when your life story ends and you get cut up like a pig or thrown into a snork hole. Don't fuck with the bandits, and don't fuck with drugs "too much."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_71">
		<text>When that cold sweat hits you after you haven't eaten for more than a day, that is exactly when your immune system goes on a fritz and you won't be able to hold a pencil steady, let alone a machine gun. People start hallucinating and walk into trouble or right off a cliff. Fill your belly at least once a day, and if you can't afford Beard's delicious delicacies, then eat some worm-infested meat that you cut out from a mutant. Worms are cheap when compared to, well… death. I've seen people outside survive whole months without food, but here it's another story. The Zone drains you. Drains your spirit, your willpower and your body. Don't hesitate to feast on snorks if you really have to. Cannibalism isn't exactly welcome, but if nobody sees you, it shouldn't really be a problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_72">
		<text>I've seen grown men turn into crying babies here. They just can't keep up and succumb to the pressure. Even athletes and people with superb physical condition drop like flies after a few squats here in the Zone. This place is a thief and a very nasty one at that - it takes away a part of your soul every day, and doesn't give it back. I could easily lift 30 kilos before I came here. Now I can barely lift a grenade when faced with a swarm of those tushkanos. It might be fear too, but whatever it is, it's like a heavy burden we all carry, we all share. Next time you want to drop a bandit when you have the upper hand, remember what I said about the burden, he is carrying it too, just like you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_73">
		<text>Next time you face a pack of dogs, try running directly towards them, it might actually save your ass from turning into dog food. We eat them, they eat us, it's a symbiotic thing. But yeah, feel free to try it out, but leave your weapons behind so you'll be able to run faster and be more intimidating. You might just leave them with me, I can keep them safe while you try this out for yourself. This shit works, but most Stalkers are fucking cowards and don't have the balls for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_74">
		<text>Get a good knife, best one of those that could shave boar's balls by looks alone. You know, quality brand knives. Get some oil on the knife, make it nice and shiny so that you can see your reflection in it. Then stab some poor fool in the throat, plunge the knife all the way to the hilt and wiggle it a bit. Soon enough, he will start bleeding out and losing consciousness, but - just a moment before he does - stare deep into his eyes. That way, your face, the face of his killer, will be the last thing he ever sees, he will take it to the grave, and the underworld will know about you. I've done this countless times, and I bet down under the ground they know my name and surname by now. When they know about you there, there is no reason to send their minions for you. I myself haven't seen a freaking bloodsucker for months now, they already know about me. This is why I will survive longer than those other cowards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_75">
		<text>I played the violin back home. Was one of the best, I even had the chance to meet the president twice. I knew the strings so well I could caress them in ways other violinists could only dream of. When I was recruited in the army, I thought I'd do my duty, go through a couple of years for my country, then get back to doing what I love. They sent me here, right after bootcamp, and I've been here ever since. Back home, they expect me to return to my previous glory and brilliance, but they don't know what happened here. It's this evil shit, the radiation or the Zone itself. It seeps into me each day, and my hands tremble, my bones hurt. I play some guitar once in a while, but that piece of rotten wood sounds like chimera claws ripping your guts. But that's the only way to keep my sanity. I feel that the guitar takes me back a bit closer to the beauty of before, the strings, the music, but at the same time it hurts me deeply knowing that I could never be that person again. If only I had a violin here, any would do, I could maybe once again take a whiff of the time before I died inside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_76">
		<text>Before all these scientists and mechanics came to the Zone, Stalkers used to carry artifacts on these makeshift belts with crude boxes attached to them. A whole generation of Stalkers are now sterile and slowly dying, their insides turning into liquid that they have to puke out once in a while. I don't know how they stay sane, how they don't just off themselves. If those simple boxes were damaged even a tiny bit, the radiation slowly entered their bodies, and that happened quite often. Now we have artifact containers that are quite durable. I've seen bullets deflecting of those contraptions, they make them as rough as those black boxes on airplanes. We have it easy now, think about the first wave of Stalkers that conquered the Zone, they were the true heroes. They didn't have any manuals nor the tools and couldn't enjoy the comfort of bases. Left completely on their own, they had to make up new ways to survive. Those boys were the pioneers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_77">
		<text>I had this buddy who fought off two chimeras. Just imagine, in front of him there were two hulking monstrosities of flesh and claws, filled with a fair share of human flesh and craving for more. He was right to be afraid. He had his back to a wall, down on his last 20 buckshots and a few bombs. He was a good aim, but that is not why he survived. He had a few of these stimpacks. I call them boosters, because they sure work fast. Whenever the chimeras struck him down and he thought he couldn't get up again, he would fix himself up with those things. Crafty fellow, that one. And you know, the human body is actually quite the resilient mother fucker. We aren't usually used to life-threatening situations and we don't have to fight off two-headed beasts to stay alive very often, but when we do, our body works wonders especially if you give it a tiny push. I don't know what long term consequences those chemical nightmares have, but if you cared about long term consequences, you wouldn't be prying around in the Zone in the first place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_78">
		<text>Shit ain't rosy outside either. My mom used to send me some cookies with sugar every few weeks and some letters telling me how they're doing. She always keeps a brave face, writing how everything is just dandy and that they are quite content, but I can see that the cookies have less and less sugar every month, and the handwriting is getting worse too. At first, she used clean white paper, but now it's this awful greasy paper probably found in some shit dumpster. I can't summon up courage to ask how they're really doing. I'm scared shitless of what they would say to me, even though I already know. I just don't want to read about it. The mental image of my folks being OK is what keeps me going around here, I don't care if it's false, I've got nothing else anymore. I send them whatever money I earn. Yesterday I sent them some that I made by selling off the last of my food rations. I'd be OK, I can always try my luck at the anomaly casino. Losing a bet there isn't the most healthy thing in the world but I'll take my chances.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_79">
		<text>I've got it, man, I've got the bug. They told me like it didn't mean shit to them, like reading a booklet about breeds of kittens. They told me I had AIDS and even told me to leave the room when I was still in shock. Fuck those people, you know? They study for so long to be perfect doctors, with a career and everything, but they end up being completely desensitized to everything. Like talking to a snork. The snork would've reacted in a more humane manner, this shit ain't right. And I have to pay heaps of money every month to get the anti-retrovirals. That shit does not come cheap, not even that knockoff Chinese shit that is only available in the Zone. I might be getting placebo pills for all I know, I still feel like crap. The Zone is the best I can do right now. And here I am, 3 years and counting. But I see you have your own shit to take care of, so just walk away like everyone does. Just leave me the fuck alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_80">
		<text>Money. Cash. Heaps of notes with as many zeros as possible. I can see your eyes light up like an emission. So I guess I have your attention now. But it's no walk in the park, and not everyone does it, and that is why it's so rewarding. I don't tell this shit like this to everyone, you know? But you look like the right guy, so listen up. Listen very carefully and try to remember every single word I tell you. What you should do to get filthy rich very quickly is: "WORK HARD AND DON'T WHINE ALL THE TIME". You lazy fucking bastard. Bugger off and go mind your own bloody business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_81">
		<text>The moment I took a single step inside the Zone was the first moment I felt really free. It was also the first moment I've ever realized that I didn't feel free back home. I thought I was fine working at the docks, bringing in some good money, joking around with friends. I had the average Joe's dream life. Some people think I must be insane for abandoning all that for the Zone. Some get really angry, one little shit even tried to shoot me. They don't know how to enjoy life, how to breathe in a new day, with new possibilities and new challenges. I know it's hard, but if you manage to survive here, even a single day, you've done more than any of the people back home would ever do. We've lost it, man, as humanity, we've been over-civilized, and have lost what it means to be alive. You are constantly reminded of it here, but back home you simply don't realize it. Just yesterday I was taking a dump in some bushes, like a real Stalker, and these bees just appeared. Angry little bitches. So I covered my face with my gasmask and started to run as fast as hell. I was so focused on running that I ran directly into a herd of hungry dogs. This is how my day started, and those 5 kilometers I ran were the daily reminder that I was alive and free.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_82">
		<text>There was this broad I knew, and I knew her well, if you know what I mean. But that bitch was just fucked up, she always kept tabs on me, checked where I was, kept calling me, leaving me strange messages. I told her this shit between us wouldn't work. She went fucking insane and started hitting me. See, I have nothing against hitting a woman, actually it's quite a relief of pent up frustration, especially with a psycho like that bitch. So I left her in front of the hospital. I think that was cool enough of me, right? I know some guys that would bury her corpse or chop her up so she could fit in the drains. I'm a good guy, you see, I take care of my bitches, but when they give me shit, that's it, I snap. Fuck, I'd really want to do her right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_83">
		<text>Don't wait for the siren before an emission. The sirens are always too late and if you're not close to any solid structure, you will get fried quite nicely. To stay alive and to avoid being fried, keep an eye towards the sky. If you see this odd cumulonimbus cloud formation, haul ass. And be quick about it. If a snork lair is your only option, go for it. You'd love those snorks compared to what the emission would do to you. So remember, when a thick vertical cloud formation appears in the sky looking as if God is puking his entrails from up above, that is when you say goodbye to all your heavy items, and sprint towards a safe spot. I had this one guy that wanted to have a tour around the Zone, he was some rich brat, constantly high on some shit and drunk. Well, that prick had the an opportunity to witness an incoming emission, and instead of taking cover like non-idiots like us, he stayed outside to admire the "beauty of the emission". His exact words. As I said, he was quite rich, so I picked up some nice loot from his scarred carcass and one torn picture of a cute girl. Shit, that photo is probably doing the rounds right now among the Stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_84">
		<text>This place isn't made for the likes of me. I'm not made for the likes of this place. I'm talking about the world, not the Zone. I've been having these clusterfuck migraines since I was little. My folks thought I was lying all the time and told me to "suck it up". Only when I started bleeding from my ears on a regular basis they started to take notice. It was all too late naturally, I was much older then, and I decided to pack my things and say hi to the Zone and goodbye to the outside world. And guess what? My migraines miraculously disappeared once I came here. I was overjoyed. For the first time ever I could feel this weight lifted off my shoulders, it felt very liberating. I could smell things, I could focus my eyes well and concentrate on the good things for a change. So I started really enjoying my life when I actually came to what many people call hell. Most were perplexed by my demeanor and I made some enemies along the way. You can't fit in over here unless you have that dreary, miserable outlook. They wouldn't accept me as one of them, neither Duty nor Freedom. I took it upon myself to find somewhere to live, further away from the pessimism of regular Stalkers. I stayed in this makeshift hut I built of metal parts, buried under some concrete slabs. I was quite content, and the place seemed to shield me from emissions quite well, but there was this familiar feeling coming back to me. It even made me feel a bit nostalgic, before I realized the migraines were coming back. Now they are worse than before, my ears burn up, I can't see well, and I can barely hold a gun because of those clusterfucks. I just want everything to end right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_85">
		<text>Holy shit, I can't take this anymore. The ladies, I really miss 'em. I had a ton of girls back home, they liked the muscular types, I liked the big-boobs type. We had an understanding. But here, I haven't even seen a female nipple! And I'm not touching those magazines Beard sells. They're all greasy and sticky, I don't want to know how they became that way. There were so many women in this place before 1986, before it became a radioactive desert. Parties, music. Communist music, but music nonetheless. Now I get turned on by their ghosts. I think about how many fish there were in the pond at Skadovsk or Yanov. I bet there was enough tail to last a lifetime. This is bullshit, I gotta get laid. Hey, on a completely unrelated matter, do you know where that herd of fleshes was killed recently? I'm actually going for a walk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_86">
		<text>Have you heard about that quick release system? That thing saved my ass when I ran into a massive herd of boars and fleshes. I took some very, very nice loot from what looked like a Duty graveyard. There were literally dozens of bodies along with all their equipment, guns, artifacts, I couldn't believe my eyes. I actually had to leave some artifacts behind, and I never do that, ever. But I was packed to the gills, and felt like a mule right before his back snapped. So it’s time to cash it in, I thought. While I was slowly walking towards the base, I was mumbling to myself: "not now, please not now, just not today, please", and then the low pitched roar of a boar cut my prayers in half. I started running away from the sound, but this air is not good enough for that. It was like made of 95% nitrogen, and each time I breathed in, I choked. So I had to make a decision, I had to leave the loot. When that backpack slammed to the ground like a fucking meteor, I sprang forward like a gazelle with grace and whatnot, the air had oxygen in it once again. Later I came back to the stash, some artifacts were missing, but there was also some blood and a nice chunk of what looked like human flesh near it. Someone tried to take a swipe at the backpack, but was probably hunted down by those boars. Maybe they were guarding it while I was gone. I have newfound respect for boars. Haven't eaten boar meat since.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_87">
		<text>Sometimes you'll find some real nice food. You could snack on some nuts, fairly good meat or clean bread. But there are other times, whenever those emissions hit hard and often, where restocking isn't so easy, so the choices are either to eat shit, or dine on some shit. The irradiated chops Beard sells at his place will fill your belly no prob, but you gotta take care of those radiated particles. Remember to wash them down with something clean, like water or something stronger. There was this fat bastard that chugged down some 20 pieces of this infested grilled shit. He was so fucked up later, other Stalkers had to feed him antirad pills, and he had to pay them back later. Even eating food is dangerous here, so watch what you stuff in your mouth and you should be "almost fine" most of the time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_88">
		<text>I'm an ex-military, trained by the best, conditioned to be a killing machine. I might look thin and scrawny, but underneath there are resilient and strong muscles. You wouldn't know what I'm talking about, I could break your neck before you could say "ouch". Just don't fuck with me and you'll be fine. I've rammed into so many boars with my fists, I don't waste ammo on those beasts. I punch them in their ugly muzzles until they just give up on life. I could show you if I wasn't so busy all the time. You should man up, do some push-ups, don't be such a chickenshit, huh? I'm sick of everyone asking for my help in taking down this chimera or sniping that controller from afar. I'd break this controller's neck, I don't snipe things like a coward. For me, it's only close and personal. Sadly, not everyone respects what I do. Some of those bitchy Stalkers would tell you that I'm making all this up. Don't you believe a word that comes out of their filthy lying mouths, they're simply jealous of my strength and prowess. Just don't tell them that I said this, OK?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_89">
		<text>What, you think you can just walk here and I'll start spilling my guts like a little baby? Everyone else might be doing it, just waiting for some poor sod to walk by and ask them how they're doing, but fuck you, friend, I'm doing swell, and I don't need anyone to hear my confessions. Now bugger off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_90">
		<text>Just leave me be, I've got too many rads today, ain't my day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_91">
		<text>I was once a lot like you, frightened, helpless and just an awfully pitiful sight. I fixed my attitude immediately after I was almost raped by those boar tusks. They cut you open just for the fun of it, I saw that happen to my buddy, he kind of took one for the team, I guess. I was so scared, I threw away my gun and ran towards cover like crazy. The first thing you have to do is get one of those armors, some thick stuff that would protect you from this awful environment. The more things you put between you and the freaks and monsters of the outside, the higher chances you'll have. There was this guy, he bought some modified exo, and just installed every single Kevlar piece he could find. He looked like a bloody Christmas tree and attracted a shitload of animals, but somehow he always got through. The cannon he was carrying sure helped increase his odds, but that exo with Kevlar works wonders here. I'm this close to getting one of those, if only I didn't have to feed the leeches back home.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_92">
		<text>Never trust those doctor fuckups. My granddad and grandma both got butchered by a surgeon. It was officially attributed to something else, but that doc was fucking drinking before the op. He reeked of booze and my granddad had to be operated right then and there. These Zone doctors aren't any better, they'd charge you and arm and a leg for fixing up a scratch, as if they've done a brain transplant twice. I take my chances and heal on my own. I'm just very careful not to get hurt, like obsessively careful, I don't drink and I don't take no drugs. But when I do get hurt, I just eat some good food, drink clean water and plop one of those emergency med kits. It usually is a bit cheaper, but most importantly if I fuck myself up, I'll have only myself to blame. I really don't want to end up like my grandparents, all cut up for no fucking reason.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_93">
		<text>I got one for you. NEVER STEAL FROM BASES. You can take anything you want everywhere else, whoever grabs it first, it's theirs. We aren't really fond of thieves around here. Even the bandits know to keep their hands off other people's shit. But if you're caught red-handed, you should feel lucky if you'll only hanged by your intestines on a tree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_94">
		<text>I have seen those chickenshits, too careful what they eat, go broke from buying all this imported delicacies. I have seen idiots throw up all the food they just bought, because they didn't really care about the rads. Both of those fuckers are wrong. You need to have balance, Zen and whatnot, you know? As Aristotle said… nevermind that. When you can spare the time, swallow some shitty meat boiled in shittier stuff, and when you need to be "on the go", imported is what you need. Remember this lesson, and maybe you'll even save enough to buy yourself some shooter that won't break down after three shots at some sucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_95">
		<text>Back in the military in my home country we used to stuff our feet into the shoes along with a cloth of some sort, no socks. Those things were comfy if you know how to wrap your foot well, but most people were shit at it, and they had bruises the size of tushkanos on their feet. Those pansies got shot first. They were always too careful. Smart doesn't always work, you know. But back to the wraps: they dried well, they lasted a lifetime, and most importantly, they could be used for other "non-approved" ways. Smart guys used to carry two pairs of them along. Whenever one pair gets wet, they replace it with another, their feet always in a perfect shape, you could eat with those feet if only the toes were longer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_96">
		<text>Sometimes it's not worth it. When you have heaps of loot, and dogs are after your ass, then it's time to drop some shit. Calculate what is worthwhile, if it's heavy and you won't need it too much, then you can casually leave a present for your attackers behind you. If it's small, light and expensive, then you don't part with it till you reach the base. I used to throw away things like that while running, and there would be a trail of useless junk behind me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_97">
		<text>I save everything, I have never sold anything to any of those greedy bastard traders in the Zone. I keep everything in secret stashes all over the Zone, and they are really hard to find. I hoard things, and these are not some useless things you can find anywhere. One day they may be of some use, and I will stick it up the assess of all those amateur psychologists that diagnose me with ailments they've read in old magazines.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_98">
		<text>Some people only react when threatened. When you really need some loot, try shooting your prey in the legs or hands. When they lose their wits because of the agony, or just get scared shitless, you should have a nice chat with them, ask them where their stash is. Some fools will tell you, and after that you can do with 'em whatever you want. I caught a bandit and cut his trigger finger, after some time I saw him firing with the other hand at some Stalkers. Should've cut his head, that rat bastard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_99">
		<text>The Zone has no mercy, ever. The Zone is living proof that God either does not exist, or doesn't give a fuck. Although He could be this mean bastard that wants to torture us, but that is almost beside the point. Don't expect anything good from anyone here. If I saw you with plenty loot, barely breathing and far from the base, I'd take a shot at you, do not think I won't. We are good buddies here, but outside it's a different matter. The Zone has its own rules, and we can only abide by them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_100">
		<text>Respect the people of the Zone and the Zone itself. Always have at least a grain of respect, because without it we are just like animals, howling and giving in to their urges. Respect is what brings people to the Zone and allows them to stay alive. It doesn't care what you did or how you came here, who you are or where you come from, the Zone will cut you down if you forget respect. I keep a reminder of it right here in my pocket, always. It's one of my toes. One of those gravity anomalies almost sucked me in, and threw a piece of my foot 20 meters away. Had to crawl to bring it back to base for the doctors to stitch it back. But it was a bit too late, and now I carry it here. If you don't want to keep a reminder like this, you should always remember about respect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_101">
		<text>I came here with only one thing in my bag and thanks to it I'm still here and not lying in a ditch somewhere, half eaten by mutants. My switchblade has been with my ever since boot camp. And I do take care of it, every time some gunk gets stuck into the mechanism, every time dirt and sand as much as touch my knife, I make sure to make it sparkly clean afterwards. It's my baby. I mean, it's common sense if you want things to last for life. And this cutter was made to accompany you all your life, if you take care of it. I cut meat, cut mutants, cut bandits and I even cut myself when I need some nasty insect larva removed. You can use it to open cans, open old locks, open up screws, open up someone's belly because they can't take a hint. Ammo you spend, grenades even more so, the knife stays with you forever, and it's a mark. It marks exactly what kind of a person you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_102">
		<text>You know why these fools carry around teeth with them? They think teeth of their enemies, especially golden teeth, carry the souls of their owners, so when shit hits the fan, you have someone to watch your back. These idiots don't realize how stupid they are, ghosts don't have eyes nor mouths, they can't even use weapons, for fuck's sake. How exactly are they going to watch their backs now, huh? Ah, sometimes people make me so mad I can't control myself and just put a bullet in their heads. After I'm done with them, I take their cherished golden teeth and sell them to whoever wants 'em, and I put some sand in 'em for good measure and so they won't tell enemies that someone is coming.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_103">
		<text>I have no friends, only some familiar faces. I know that guy, he sold me some food once, another one smiles like an idiot all the time. I don't even remember their names, they drop like flies so fast, it's not really worth it. And new ones come in by the hundreds, they're really like moths attracted by those fluorescent lights, just to be fried in an instant. That's a fitting description of the Zone, I think. Friends get you killed around here. What happens when he gets surrounded by snorks, and you have to "save" him because he's such a good friend? You die, right there and then. Instead of one, now there are two corpses. My only real friend is my gun, and if you have even a slightest interest in staying alive, then you should really cherish only your shooter and nothing else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_104">
		<text>My family is shit, or rather is in deep shit. I mean, it's really bad back home. No food, no money. I send them money in this gray box, but they say only half comes to them. Always someone takes the other half. When I find that fucker, I will rape his face with my knife.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_105">
		<text>Do not touch junk that is not your own. Whatever it is. What if it's bottled anthrax? Do not throw it out, unless you wanna die a horrible death. Even if you find a hundred thousand in cash, even if you think you could just break away from the Zone and live like a king for a few months, you will get hunted down like a bloody animal. You were dead the moment you took that cash. So , keep your hands to yourself and to the things you personally own, everything else should be invisible to you. I hate telling this to every freaking newbie out here. No manners, these morons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_106">
		<text>I've done it all, man, I've been here for so long. I've seen waves of pseudodogs flood bases, pseudogiants fighting between themselves, I've even seen controllers talk with people. Yeah, I've seen that. I smoked a ton of ganja before that, sure, but it was so that my head doesn't explode from the sound of those screeching auras those controllers emit. When you face them, whatever you do, just keep calm, and concentrate on either running away from the sound, or do the iron balls manoeuvre, that is run towards the sound and prepare to unload everything you have into their head. Would not recommend that one though. I've seen tough guys weep like little babies when they fail. Soon after they get mind snapped and they can't even be called people anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_107">
		<text>Naturally, I'm the perfect man for this place. I'd say that I've got exactly what it takes to make it here. I was swinging through a bunch of prisons throughout Eastern Europe before I found this hellhole. Some of them were of better standard than some grade A hotels. Jesus, there was room service in one of them, how the hell was I supposed to repent for my crimes when it was so good to be there? I managed to escape from the last one, I shived a guard, didn't care whether he had any family, kids, lover, I didn't give not one fuck about it. So I came here, at least the prison here is much, much larger. It almost feels like freedom, and that's who I joined immediately when I arrived. Duty has their connections with the law. Me and the law don't get along actually. Some of the pussies in Freedom tell me I'm a monster, but once the real monsters come, guess who's gonna save their asses? But my speciality is murder, I can cut up a man faster than a pig, so they use me against Duty whenever the situation calls for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_108">
		<text>In here, you side either with people or with the mutant beasts roaming the place. If you are a beast, you'll get hunted for sure, if you are civilized enough and act like a person, you might survive for a while. We stick together, and that is why there are human settlements in this hell's kitchen. If we don't stick together, the Zone would turn into a wasteland of unseen proportions in no time. Even if it's a bandit roach, keep him alive, shoot him in the foot and get his stash, but leave him be. There is barely any people here, and you going around wasting good folks is not in anyone's interest. I know you want to be Rambo and are trigger happy all the time, but you won't be Rambo for long here. Rambos don't survive in the Zone for long.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_109">
		<text>Those fucks think they have it better than us. It is them that are prisoners, prisoners of comfort, prisoners of taking the easier path. They wouldn't last here. Not one of them would make it one day, it's going either going to be the food, or the air, or the hellspawns walking like they own the God damn place. If the Zone gets bigger and engulfs the whole world, we will be the most experienced and at the top, not them. They'd be hiding in some greasy corner with bags of gold and useless money. Try nibbling on a piece of gold, it doesn't do shit. I love their condescending tone, every time some new guy comes in and speaks to us, he acts all high and mighty, it's like we are living in a gutter, and they've come here to enlighten us. There was once a Christian missionary or a Muslim prophet, some prick like that. He came with food and medicine, promising the salvation of our souls. And virgins. Lots of pure virgins when we go to heaven. Not one Stalker bought his bullshit. Natural selection weeds out the idiots, or rather the Zone does, and those that are left? They don't value bullshit very highly. The guy that wanted to enlighten us was enlightened himself when he stepped into a lightning anomaly. He actually did survive, but he was badly burned and went back home immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_110">
		<text>I heard about this guy that came to the Zone and refused to fire any weapons. He was a pacifist of some sort. Coward by my book, but that is irrelevant. Yeah, and he decided to stay here, make some money by helping the traders out, packing supplies, cleaning the beds, all those little things. At first, nobody respected him, they considered him a fool. After a while he started to grow on people, and they started to be dependent of him. He'd know who needs what, where and how. He actually sent money to that shitty country in Eastern Europe he came from. Imagine that, making money in the Zone without weapons? He is still a coward, but a crafty one indeed. He still has never left the base, and sends letters with cash back home. I think he has some family there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_111">
		<text>Trading works around here for one reason: "shitty crook traders get fucked very quickly". There was this one lad, had the appearance of a soldier, that one. He started selling trinkets that were supposed to be half-artifacts. People bought it for a while, carried them around as if some new fashion trend started in the Zone. That kid got some money this way, started selling his goods to more experienced Stalkers, but they don't buy bullshit as you might have learned by now. So they took the so called artifacts to the scientists, they did some research and guess what happened to the kid? He might still be hanging by his intestines from those cranes up in Zaton. They didn't kill him immediately, no. They just ripped him open like a bag of chips, and hanged him by his guts to be pecked by birds like Prometheus. That is the way they die. I bet a lot of people saw that, and a lot of hopeful crooks took note and downsized their businesses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_112">
		<text>I had that fucker as a landlord back in Kiev. He was a shitbag then, he's a shitbag now. He's even a worse shitbag now. I got into debt, did a little of those "games", had to try out my luck. I don't do that anymore, mostly because everything goes to the "landlord". He owns me, man, I've thought about putting a bullet through his head, but I'm not one of those people. It seems like I could never repay the debt I have, and I just go deeper and deeper. I think he's making money off me. At least my family back in Kiev has a roof over their heads. That is the least that I can do for them. He does take care of that part. I studied to become a technician, not a fucking hunter. Whenever I stab some poor flesh all I can think about is how disgusting this is, but this is how I keep my family safe back home. Should've accepted that job at the bank, what a fool I was back then. I had this superficial view on reality, and thought banks were just plain evil. You know, I thought banks were evil, but gambling isn't. I deserve rotting here in the Exclusion Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_113">
		<text>You should be a rock, able to withstand waves of shit and gore that the Zone hits you with. But every rock needs its base. Nobody survives without some help. Either the mutants get you, or - if you're one of those nimble motherfuckers - some illness or even greed will get to you. Eat Zone-produced food only once in a while. If you overdo it after a day or two, you'll throw up more than you eat, it's really not worth it. The cancer should put you off too, but who the hell survives in here long enough to be diagnosed with cancer or actually die from cancer? That shit takes a while to develop and slowly engulfs your major organs. So be resourceful and visit the bases once in a while. Unload, unwind and talk to some people, one of those people might drag your unconscious ass back to base when a controller says "hello".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_114">
		<text>They say keep your friends close and your enemies closer. I like to keep everyone as close as possible. I keep an eye open at all times. Try catching me off-guard, even when I'm sleeping. I'm always alert and ready to kick some ass. But traveling alone is fucked up. I only travel with other Zoners. They know their fair share of terror, and they can keep their wits when everything turns upside down and you can barely tell a difference between a person and a mutant. You know, I'd love to keep them mutants close, but they do bite, and they sure bite deep. There was this one guy that kept a pseudodog, not sure how he tamed him, but he is one badass mother fucker right there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_115">
		<text>It's called cumulonimbus cloud formation. 'round these parts it means it's high time to "get the fuck under cover." Those clouds resemble a nuclear explosion mushroom, but you'd pray it was a nuke if you actually get caught outside. Sometimes the emission just burns you until there is nothing but dust, sometimes electricity fries you like well-done bacon. But the psy storms are the worst. You can hear them speaking to you, and you must listen. The sound is so penetrating you'll think you've grown deaf. Some say psy storms are actually pent up psychic energy of controllers. So if you see this bizarre cumulonimbus cloud formation, stop whatever you're doing, and start working your way back to base. Emissions are the Zone's way to tell you: "you need a break."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_116">
		<text>I have these growths under my armpit and around my neck, doc says he can't do anything and when I ask him what it is, he just goes silent. Like a fucking light switch was turned off in his brain. Don't know what the hell that is, but I live with it. They are slowly getting bigger, I can't sleep on my back anymore. And the jacket I used to wear? I can barely zip it up. I might just be getting fat, I don't know, but who the hell gets fat in the Zone? I rub some imported vodka on my back and neck, and the feeling of tightness disappears for a while. Most think I'm a drunk because I reek of vodka all the time, and I go to bed with a vodka bottle. I've never drunk alcohol in my life, it's a religious thing so you probably wouldn't understand. Fuckit, I'll just head over to that other doc, he's always more helpful anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_117">
		<text>You know that old newbie that hangs around the Yanov station? He's still a newbie for a good fucking reason. He tried to take some loot from another friend without him noticing. I'd call this theft, but the newbie is a good guy, and I don't want to see him hanging on a tree. So he took the stuff from his friend, and ran towards some stash he had previously prepared. We knew what he was doing all along, but tracked him anyway because we wanted to find out how he deals with this. Strangely, he returned all the loot and apologised to his friend for his nasty behaviour. He's been at Yanov ever since, washing dishes, tending to crates, moving ammo boxes. That's what you get when you fuck with other people's loot. Well, not really, you get hanged by your intestines on a tree, but that's what you get when you return the liberated goods back to their original owner on your own volition, realizing the mistake you've made. He's a good guy that one, but we all have our moments of weakness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_118">
		<text>I had them in my sights, these mercs that were tormenting some Stalker by the rocks near Zaton plant. I could snipe them off in 4 seconds and it would've ended right there and then. I kept my cool though, and it really paid off because another dozen of mercs came afterwards. I didn't have enough bullets for all of them. I mean, I don't miss, I don't waste any bullets. I count every bullet by the price. If I shoot ten bullets, there will be at least ten corpses and I'd have to take "at least" that amount from their loot to break even. This is a good strategy for any visitor or long term Zoner here. When the mercs left, the guy was in so much pain I had to use one of my subsonic rounds with the suppressor not to attract unwanted attention. That was the only time I didn't calculate how much that bullet was worth. It probably meant everything to that tortured Stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_119">
		<text>Nobody knows what the hell makes that pecker sound. Some think it's mutants, the controllers. Other say it's the weather. Still others claim it is antennas used for secret communication. This is what the rumors say, but what we know is that the Zone amplifies the signal and spreads it over a wider area, affecting any electronic device capable of emitting sound. Some people go insane from it, running into a boar lair or an anomaly. Never fall asleep where the sound is loud, you won't wake up the same as before. It fucks with your subconscious, you wake up and hear those unintelligible numbers and word combinations that make no sense. I don't quite understand what that might be, and I don't really want to find out. I just keep a nice distance from those sounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_120">
		<text>If you see the Z's, all faceless and slow, don't just spray them with bullets. That's like wasting money on slots. You won't gain anything by doing this. They are tough little bitches, and you won't be doing any good if you shoot them in the legs or arms. You could easily unload a crate full of ammo in those things, and won't so much as blink if the bullets miss the sweet spot. Don't waste money like that, it's useless. Aim for their spine or go for the head, and they'll be gone fast. Take your time, breathe steadily and be sure to exploit their weaknesses. Now that you know this, maybe you'll have better chances and won't end up filled with bullet holes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_121">
		<text>Come, sit with me. Have a drink and relax. The Zone is unforgiving, but that doesn't mean Stalkers should be like that as well, right? We should enjoy these brief moments of peace because they may be our last. I knew this Stalker, he was always afraid, always kept an eye out for anything. Every little sound made him jump, wouldn't eat this, wouldn't drink that. Although he's survived until now, he's a wreck, he doesn't sleep, he doesn't leave the station, just too fucking scared of everything. If he took my advice and relaxed even a tiny bit, he'd be a different person now, but to each his own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_122">
		<text>There was this one time I had to battle two hulking chimeras and these were no normal chimeras. They had three heads, man, that was insane. Even if you took care of two heads, there was still one more left. But it was no problem for my skills, you know? I kicked their asses so hard they bled like stuck pigs. I've done a ton of those things, man, no biggie. I once went to Pripyat after hearing all the stories of how fucked up it was. I had to get there, check it out myself. There were thousands of tushkanos, 50 monolith squads at every step, for real. I took down plenty of them but I couldn't carry anymore loot, so I got back here. By the way, do you have any idea how to release the safety on this piece of shit pistol? I couldn't figure it out, it's a new gun for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_123">
		<text>I'm sure you're eager to explore and wouldn't to find some shiny artifacts, but what if I tell you that the true treasure of the Zone are definitely not the artifacts? And that's exactly what I'm telling you, and to get that true treasure you don't have to fire a single bullet. I know it sounds too good to be true, but that is not a good enough reason to dismiss it. What I need from you is only an initial sum of money, think of it as an investment. And get this, it's going to spit out a return, ten times what you invested. I found this guy that knows this other guy who set all this up. It's all legit, you could ask around, but that would just make other Stalkers want to cash in, and this deal might not be on the table for long if that happens. Think about it and bring in the dough when you're ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_124">
		<text>I don't really talk to strangers, and we are all strangers here. Most people feel comfortable spilling their life stories to anyone, but I'm not that kind of guy. I realize it's that feeling of fraternity - anyone who isn't shooting at you is automatically your brother, and sharing a cup of shroom tea with another Zoner makes him your best friend. See, I never get used to that attitude, I've always been left to tend to myself. And that's alright with me. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_125">
		<text>Who are you living for? What is the "idea" that keeps you alive when every single thing in the Zone wants you dead? Imagine a democratic poll where everything in the Zone could vote, everything: the emissions, the anomalies, bandits, mutants, cancer, tetanus, radiation, etc. The odds are we would all be dead if things worked that way. The Zone wants you dead, but it even doesn't need to vote to get what it wants. Quite terrifying, ain't it? Do you know what keeps me breathing? These kind of conversations. Not vodka, not cocaine, not even those wonderful porn mags Beard sells for a hefty fee, it's simple chats with simple people like you. Thank you for taking the time to have a nice chat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_126">
		<text>They sure put something in the imported tobacco that is being sold here, it reduces the effects of radiation and helps the body recover. Some fantastic shit the Ukrainian government came up with when they had to deal with the first Chernobyl explosion. So smoking one cig after eating some shitty cyst-infested meat from the Zone really works wonders. Unless you want to spend a whole day puking and get cancer in a few years. We are all sterile anyway, our balls can't handle the radiation, and those that aren't yet sterile have defective sperm. Imagine watching your beautiful wife give birth to a disgusting mutant, just because you spent a few months in the Zone back in when you were young. Everything has consequences, or at least that's what the doctors say.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_127">
		<text>Tag along with larger groups when you're not prepared for the horror of being alone. They won't mind unless you keep waving a shooter in their faces. That way you get the safety of numbers, you have more fun and you might learn a thing or two from their conversations. You could also learn by watching them in action. Their tactics, how they handle weapons, how they move. It's all important and essential if you want to stay alive. If not, you could join the ranks of zombies if that shit fancies you. Just walk to their lair or chill outside while a psy emission is raging. I wouldn't recommend any of these things though, but it's your call.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_128">
		<text>The scientists are good folk, they are timid like rabbits. They wouldn't blow directly on a flower, let alone kill someone. I salute them, they are so dedicated to their cause in spite of such harsh conditions. It's hard going on each day knowing that your bunker could be overwhelmed by the scum of the Zone, and you can't do anything about it. I'd rather have basic knowledge of gun handling, but these are educated people, people with a cause. I'm here because I need to sell artifacts. It helps with my terrible habit of collecting money. I've been doing that all my life, spending as little as possible, and I still ended up here. I seem to be saving in all the wrong ways, I guess. You have to think of some sort of system to make a decent living. Buy optimal amounts of food, spend the least amount of ammo, just the amount necessary for the job. By observing these simple rules you'll have much better chances not to end up like me. But I'm a dreamer, a dreamer that collects money just for the sake of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_129">
		<text>I came to the Zone with only one thing. I know you aren't supposed to take anything here if you want to bring it back, especially if it's alive and all, because of all the radiation. But it was the most precious thing I've ever had. It was a duckling. The cutest little yellow thing. Quacking like crazy all the time. I wanted to keep it inside so that it wouldn't attract attention. I had a plan on how to feed it and everything. It slept near my heart, where it was the warmest. I had it for 20 days, and when I came to the Zone, it didn't even survive a few hours. Normal animals don't last long here. Just those crows, and I'm not even sure they are normal at all. I've seen them scream like robots, and gouge out eyes of pseudogiants. They are vicious thieves too. If you have some trinkets, golden, silver, doesn't matter, they will take it if you stash them somewhere they can easily reach. Once this drunkard started shooting at the sky for no reason and he hit a crow by accident. How surprised he was when he saw that it was holding this golden watch in its beak. It reminded me of the duckling I had with me. I've seen my friends die dogs' deaths in the mud here, but thinking about that duckling just makes my heart break.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_130">
		<text>Nobody cares about us down here. It's as if we don't even exist. The first few days we were in the spotlight. Stalkers, the Zone. Afterwards, they started ignoring everything that's going on here. Mutants, artifacts, they all think it's some kind of a hoax. Sometimes even I wonder if these artifacts are any good. I mean, how could we know? I know the scientists are working their magic back in the bunkers, but how do I know that a specific artifact is good for this and not for another thing? It might just be old wives' tales, superstitious people making stuff up, so they could feel safer in this wasteland. That's probably not an option since even a seemingly harmless superstition can get you killed. I don't know, really, it's a bit too much for me. I know I believe in a loaded gun and a sharp knife. That's my God right there, cocked and ready to go. I pray to that God by cleaning it and doing basic maintenance, and it's very rewarding. Especially when it doesn't get stuck and does exactly what it's made for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_131">
		<text>I want to score big, just once. I've been here for a while now, why can't I get lucky? I follow the right people, carry the right equipment, but it's always either a shitty flesh or a boar if I'm extremely lucky. And this is not exactly profitable, to say the least. To down a boar I gotta use 4 bullets, and I make 3 and a half back when I sell the stuff I take from it. Fleshes are even worse, no one really wants to buy them. You'd better avoid them altogether and hunt for some bigger game. I heard that this one guy accidentally run into a pack of snorks. He chucked a grenade at them while running away. He didn't even look back to see what happened, he just noticed that after the noise from the explosion died down, and the whistling in his ear disappeared, he didn't hear the snorks no more. Now that's what I call scoring big. He took their feet and hands back to base, sold them at an excellent price. He went home with that money. Lucky bastard. If I waste a grenade at my boars, I would cut my own hand and sell it to the first trader that believes it's snork's to make up for the freaking 'nade.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_132">
		<text>Carrying a lot of equipment takes its toll on you. Exoskeletons are really cool, I know. But try running away from a pack of dogs with that suit on. It will drain you like a leech. There was some talk about boosters that enable you to run, but you still drain fast. I would go for light armor if I was you. You have more options that way, and the best tactic here is actually not getting shot at all. No armor repairs, no pain, no medicine. It's safe and secure. Although it's quite rare to see people manage to do this for a longer while, it is quite rewarding when you're successful. You always have the choice to either pack armor improvements like Kevlar, or put some hydration upgrades that make life much easier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_133">
		<text>Every time I see you around, I think to myself: "Now, that is a guy who knows where he is going." I just loop around in circles, doing the exact same things each day. Getting bitten by a tushkano is not even exciting anymore. It's as if life has lost any meaning for me. It's bereft of any essence, and I feel I've done my share of living. It's easy getting lost here, ending up in an anomaly. Quick and painless. I've always wanted a death like that. My father was tortured before those bandits tore his throat out along with major arteries. I learned very quickly what happens to a person with torn arteries. Murdering our own kind is just too much for me. I couldn't even manage to retaliate, to avenge my own father. I had the names and whereabouts of each and every one of those bastards that did that to him. But what's the point? We will all perish soon enough, I'd rather be dead on the spot than experience what my father went through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_134">
		<text>Once I get my hands on a good sniper, I'm off to better places. I might even visit some zombie nests. With a sniper I could off each and every one of those Z's without taking a single hit. But they don't come cheap, you'd have to pay that bastard Owl a hand and a leg for 'em. I need my hand for sniping, and my legs are very important for running around as you might already know. Maybe that Haitian or Hawaiian fella has some good deals. I never trust people that are all smiling and nice to me. There is always a catch behind those smiling mouths. I'm good with a sniper too, I used to train with the army. Not in the army, but with it, along with the army. It was an awkward situation, but I was better at sniping than some army grunts. Should've come here with more money, but it's hard to get anything outside and still harder inside. I do what I have to do, and right now, I have to get me a sniper.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_135">
		<text>One more and I'm done. This is the last one I'm doing, and I've done a whole bunch. I used to bring in simple artifacts and pseudo-artifacts. They weren't worth much, just enough to keep my belly filled with nasty shit that is barely edible. After I got my advanced detector, more expensive shit began to flow. Beard knew my name, I was popular at Yanov. It isn't easy, this artifact hunting. You can get burned, electrocuted, crushed, you name it. But it's gratifying. At least I don't have to put bullets in people's heads for a living. Not a nice job that one. But sometimes you just have to defend yourself. I had to do it once because some bandits tried to rob me while they were high as fuck on coke. All jittery and such, I had to put them down as fast as possible. Sold their coke too. I felt like a scumbag and a lowlife, but it had to be done. Now I know what routes the bandits have, and I try to not have face to face meets with them. They don't seem to mind, or and don't even notice me at all. And that's a perfect arrangement for me. But all that is in the past now, because this is my last run, and I'm going back to see my sweeties. I have two huskies, one is a big fucker, and the other has some health issues. Well, now that I have so much dough, it shouldn't be a problem. And even if it's not so easy, I can pay them with artifacts. That would wake the veterinarians up, I suppose.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_136">
		<text>Do you know what perpetuum mobile is? Of course you don't. I'm going to tell you now, and you better write this shit down. A scientist I used to know was researching this peculiar phenomenon that some lights were still functioning after years without a power source, without maintenance. It's like they were feeding on some source of energy, but it couldn't be determined what it was. They theorized that those objects had become stuck in the particular time when the Zone was created. They didn't even seem to age at all. Naturally, the military would want dibs on this technology, them and every company in the world. But these objects that could work seemingly indefinitely just died when disconnected or taken outside the Zone. They were classified as proto-artifacts, and for a while they were deemed uninteresting to science. How aloof of them. Claiming anything in here uninteresting. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_137">
		<text>Independent scientist groups have started popping up around the Zone lately. Folks that don't care for the strict regulations of the military, they even might be corporate scientists. Anyway, what they found was that the proto-artifact story was half right. What they found was that the Zone itself was saturated with magnetic fields of a very complex nature. Some electrical devices started charging themselves up without a plug, just by being in the Zone, and sometimes they overcharged, burning up in the process. Tesla worked on wireless energy transfer, or so they say. He would love to get his hands on any of these artifacts. I bet he would've been a good Stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_138">
		<text>You know that this is hell on earth, right? I mean, you've been here more than a minute, I presume? This shit is awful as it is, but it's even worse because it's like we are in the fucking stone age. Have you seen a functioning truck transporting goods? Have you seen a robot venturing into anomalies, fishing out artifacts while this pseudo-Stalker pushes buttons from a safe distance? You haven't, I know you haven't because I've never seen that myself. It just doesn't exist. Complex circuits fry up immediately here, and only smaller devices could withstand the harsh influence of the Zone. All the PDAs here have some form of magnetic shielding or barriers to resist the damaging magnetic forces. Simple mechanism fare much better here, but they too wear out much faster. Have you noticed how often you have to clean your shooter here? It's like any complex mechanism is a magnet for dust particles. Everything breaks down faster here, and the more complex it is, the quicker it becomes useless.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_139">
		<text>Every single device made to suck up the magnetic waves the Zone constantly emits fries up before anyone can do any solid measurements. You can't tame the Zone, you can't trick it into feeding you. Large scale engineering projects haven't been attempted because of that. It's like this place has its own mind, and it does whatever it wants. And "it" certainly doesn't want to help us. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_140">
		<text>Have you tried contacting the outside from here? Not possible, mobile phones will fry in your hand as soon as you dial the number. The Zone wants to protect its secrets, I guess. 3G, GPS, radio waves all get scrambled when directed from inside out or the other way round. Even cables for fuck's sake, they fry up too. It doesn't make any sense. Powerful military-grade radios manage to maintain contact for only a few moments before they turn off forever. This place is a quiet desert, and it's bound to stay like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_141">
		<text>During the noosphere rupture a while ago, when the Zone became the Zone, something quite strange happened to some electrical circuitry. For reasons unknown to science, resistance of some circuits has been reduced to almost 1,5 ??•m which is a range normally only present in the most powerful superconductors, those that are superchilled. This has made those circuits work practically for years without any applied voltage as electrons are moving through them in endless loops without losing any energy. As a result, some circuits became self-sustaining and perfectly preserved over the years, being able to propel whatever equipment was plugged into them at the moment of this massive emission. On the other hand, some circuits were completely blown out, and new circuits sometimes don't even work at all in here. This poses a problem for scientists, especially since they have to magnetically seal their complex mechanisms, which takes a lot of effort, time and is quite costly. If this wasn't the case, I bet you'd be seeing a lot more scientists than Stalkers around the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_142">
		<text>You don't wanna pass out or stop moving even for a second. If you do, you're dead meat. No Stalker, good guy or bad guy, will ever help you out if you can't take care of yourself. If you get shot, even if you have your bulletproof vest, that bitch hurts like a motherfucker. A few more hits and you'll be struggling to stay conscious from the pain. Do not let that happen. That's when things end for you. There was this wannabe Stalker, this newbie that just came out of the box, still full of beans, he thought if he invested in a good vest, some bullet-proof plates, he'd be unstoppable. He died somewhere after he ate a few bullets to his chest. The impact crushed his ribs and the ribs punctured his lungs. The pain was too much for him. He threw up his insides, and probably dehydrated right there. They found his body ripped apart by hungry doggies or something uglier. I don't want to tell the story of how they found your body, aight?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_143">
		<text>The human body is a very reliable machine. It can function almost flawlessly for decades, and it's one of the most complex systems in the known world. The Zone is a little bit different. Immune systems don't work as well as they normally do, coughs last longer, cancer is obviously rampant. It's as if you are immediately drained once you step inside the Zone. If you wanna stay here, you need a very strong spirit, either in alcoholic form or psychological one, preferably both. Some cowards won't stand one bite of those dogs, others can go through a lot of punishment. What is different is spirit, and sometimes drugs, but mostly spirit. You need to have strong and pre-defined goals to keep you going through the everyday shit. That is the difference between newbies, adepts and real Stalkers. Anyone can waltz in here, strutting with brand-new weapons and shiny armor, but when it gets awful, some folks break much easier than others, and it doesn't have anything to do with the weapons you have or the armor you wear. They do help, but what drives you inside is what determines if you live or die.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_144">
		<text>I used to refuse to carry a weapon. Anything that could hurt another living being was impure to me. But surviving doesn't come easy. I had to learn the hard way how important it is to have the necessary tools, especially in the Zone. When I first arrived here, people told me I wouldn't live to see another day. I still refused to buy a gun and I had my reasons. I spent 5 years in an Orthodox monastery, high in the mountains and near this little village. The people there have barely heard about World War II, let alone the Zone. Very peaceful people, calm, resilient. But they don't have to face the horrors that dwell here. I bet they would throw away their holy books along with their crosses the moment they see a controller staring them in the eye and meddling in their brain. Drilling deep. So I had to change my attitude. I wanted to live and sacrificing my faith seemed like a low price to pay. And that's how I grabbed my first weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_145">
		<text>You have to believe in something, man, and in here you quickly learn to believe in hosts of different gods if you don't wanna go nuts. You know what I'd like to see? A declared atheist run through a fire anomaly. He will start praying to make up for all the years he went on cynically laughing at "petty" religions. Sometimes the only thing you have is that kind of hope, and to take that away under the pretense of "reason" and "science" is just plain stupid. And you've already seen what atrocities the atheists have done throughout history. Millions of people dead. Where was their humanism then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_146">
		<text>I think this "one God" bullshit is just that - a pile of shit. I mean, it's just lazy to think that whoever created us would be just one person. I realize it's kinda complicated to be praying to many gods, so it was natural some people simplified the deal by introducing one true God. But at least they are not cowards not to believe in anything. It takes courage to be hoping for something as beautiful and transcendent as the Gods or even one God. Sometimes you have to keep your mind busy with things like that. If the only thing filling your mind was the horror of the Zone, you would never be able to have a good night's sleep or relax with a cup of coffee and enjoy good conversation. God is the only thing that separates you from the thick layer of shit of daily life here. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_147">
		<text>What kind of monster would God have to be to create so much suffering, such widespread poverty, destruction and cruelty? How is that a part of God's plan? How am I supposed to love, respect or worship something or someone as vicious as God? And religion? It's just a twisted combination of crazy and contradictory statements. Every single religion. Even the Buddhists have their fundamentalist fanatic killers. Nothing that claims to be fundamentally good could create so much bile and hatred. Whatever the initial intentions of Jesus and Mohammed and all the world's religious leaders were, however positive and constructive they were, have now become the absolute opposites of what they claimed to be. I'd say that is a massive failure right there. Just pray to yourself, you are your only god and it's only up to you to survive in this hellhole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_148">
		<text>It's hard to hold on to anything here. Memories of family, friends, some nice moments in the past are quickly erased and replaced by the dripping despair, oozing out of every pore of every man. I had convictions and a strict moral code before coming here. Now I see it's all shit, it's all fabrications by people who have a lot of free time on their hands. You think a two-headed chimera would hesitate even for a second before devouring your best friend in front of you? That is what you call a perfect creature - fast, deadly, efficient predator that fears no one and nothing. We have a lot to learn from the beasts, and they have absolutely nothing to learn from us. They are already the masters of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_149">
		<text>Some places, man. It's just not worth it unless you are some freaking motherfucker with a nuclear blaster rifle or godlike skills. There are areas that only the toughest of Stalkers with the best equipment dare to visit. This is not a zoo, those snorks over there are most definitely not to be fed unless you fancy a quick death, but even then, it's better to just off yourself right here, and let me take care of your things… er… I meant, I can arrange a proper burial for you. It's just that many shitskulls that simply came out of their momma's pussy want to be the hardest motherfucker out there, and jump right into the biggest clusterfucks in the Zone, without any equipment, without any experience, without nothing at all. You can do that in some "normal" places of the world, but the Zone? The Zone definitely is not "normal" by any standards. They probably heard some shit from friends, and want to play a hero. I have to tell you, those folks don't get to enjoy the Zone too long.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_150">
		<text>Don't go strolling where you don't belong, boy. If you haven't personally scanned and tested the ground, if you don't know every single crook and cranny, if you aren't acquainted with "that particular area", just stay off. Before going to the Iron Forest I spent 2 months just watching, just observing. Two whole bloody months. That's almost half your age. And that is why I'm alive and kicking today. I was patient. I mean, sure, that poltergeist fried my back so nice that I still get these reactions on my skin whenever FM signals are amplified. And sure, I had a controller take a look into my brain, but I survived. You know why? I've just told you, you worthless punk, I've just told you I spent 2 fucking months observing, thinking, wondering. Making a solid strategy before even thinking of doing anything. How are you going to survive in here if you have the attention span of an ADD Japanese hornet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_151">
		<text>If knives were our only weapon, we would be so dead right now. The mutants would roam the Zone, and it would've been rather quiet. These are no mammoths or elephants, man. The mutants are something else, something much more vicious than anything we've ever encountered outside. We are most definitely not made nor supposed to survive frontal attacks of those beasts. That's why we compensate for our lack of superhuman shit with the right tools. We just have to shoot 'em hard and shoot 'em where it hurts. A lot to remember, I know, but this is crucial if you want to save your ass from becoming a snack, or if you simply want to get some dough by selling mutant meat or organs. I mean, it's a lucrative business, but not a safe one. Look at artifact hunting. If you fuck it up, your life ends almost immediately, so you don't really suffer. Much, at least. But if you fuck it up with those beasts, you are looking at bleeding out in 2 or 3 minutes, best case scenario, and worst case, you'll eaten bit by bit, from bottom to top, in hours, sometimes days. Some Stalkers got real good moves that they've learned over the course of many years in the Zone, things that newbies just can't get at first try. It's muscle memory. If you survive a boar attack once, you will catch a glimpse of how you should move to avoid it. It doesn't seem like much, but some experienced Zoners could hold off 4 or 5 of those boars at the same time, no problemo. Still, I wouldn't like to be in their shoes. I'd rather be like Beard or Hawaiian.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_152">
		<text>No easy money here. Fools come here, think they'd get fat rich with a few artifacts and after a few hunting sessions. That's bullshit, my friend. You'll be lucky to survive. Not to say there is no way to make money, but you have to use everything mother nature provided you with: your intelligence, reflexes, spirit, everything you've got, synced to perfection, to be able to get a tiny piece of the cake. Not many of us return to the Great Land, they either die, or get stuck in this hellish cycle: get drunk, cure your hangover with mushroom tea, look for some artifacts or hunt some mutants to get the cycle going, and so the cycle begins anew. And you can't just decide to leave, going back costs money too. Everything's got a price on it, and either you buy it with cold cash, monster hides, weapons, favors or using your own fucking skin. As you can see, nothing is easy here, and this place is certainly not for everybody. It sure has its own way of showing this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_153">
		<text>Making money costs money. You just calculate how much your "investment" costs, and determine the risk and the return. What the hell did you think? This shit is all business and math. Nothing else to it. These sorry ass bitches walking around, looking like tough bastards, brandishing heavy weaponry, they are all mathematicians and businessmen. Some with PHDs and university diplomas. It's a hard place to live, and it's even a harder place to run a business. See, what I do is I calculate the price of the bullet, the price of repair and how much I have to spend if I wanna survive that specific "adventure". And if the return is big enough, I know what I'm doing next. Calculations like that you've got to make all the time. Do I shoot the boar that is chasing me, or keep my ammo for that raid on that bandit camp? Making money sure does cost money, sometimes more than you actually make. You make bad mistakes, you end up in the swamps. And that's all the philosophy there is to it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_154">
		<text>You want to make the big bucks, yes? Make the big bucks from artifacts, yes? Stupid boy, you need to cover yourself proper first. Put on a SEVA, eat pills that make you hold against that anom type, and those bolts aren't for hunting mutties. You could make a very simple, basic combination of anom protection, but then you have to be super-fast at going for that artifact, and some anom's are even too hard for any basic DIY combination you could make. They require professional equipment. Remember, the higher the risk, the more money you get… Sometimes. Other times you get nothing and you just spend all that you have. So don't be stupid, "Stalker", be smart, and alive, or just leave this place, we have enough corpses on the ground, and some even walking. Oh, I'm not from around here so sorry for my language.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_155">
		<text>Bandits are the scourge of this land. Awful, tricky weasels that will kill you and rob you, and sometimes they'll do even worse things to you. Some of them are ex-Stalkers, sure, but really, it's what they're doing now that matters. They have no morals, no codes, no underlying structure or rules. If you are just starting out here, and you see a squad of those bastards, you'd better keep off and away. Like some fiends, they can smell a chance to grab some nice loot. Sometimes they won't shoot. Sometimes they will rape you before you can say that you surrender. If you want to take on the sheriff's badge and get rid of that scum, you'd need to be equipped for the job. You can just start blasting, and expect to survive. You ambush them, study their movement patterns, their formations, their habits. If their squads were easy to take down, we wouldn't have people walking in groups. Sometimes a controller is easier to kill than a well-trained squad. Shoot the head, shoot to kill, and then move to the next target. Keep something between you and their bullets, some armor, get boar hides if you have to, and wipe them off. But you don't look like the fighting type, you've been listening to me rant for 10 minutes about this shit, when it's such an excellent opportunity to walk around outside and get some fresh air. Do it. Now. Get out of here. OUT!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_156">
		<text>Veteran Stalkers, regular Stalker, hell, almost every Zoner has adapted so well to the Zone over the years that killing them sometimes seems outright impossible. Not that I want to shoot any of them, but hear me out. I think that the Zone not only makes them harder on the outside, but also it has specifically worked its magic on the inside. A civilian that came here would whine and go into a shock after being shot in the leg. A Zoner will fix that shit up, he won't lose touch with the reality of situation and maybe even plan an escape route. Sometimes a veteran Stalker will get shot, but the bullet will be a lucky one for him, and it will miss all major arteries and vital organs, and it would seem like he's bulletproof. Not sure if veteran Stalkers have found the Oasis or some any form of healing artifacts or whatnot, but that will seem really strange to you only if you weren't here for long. I've seen a guy get shot in the head and pull through. There was one guy in Russia, I've forgotten his name, this giant pole was stuck into his brain, another had his head severed almost completely, and they both survived. Outside? It's a massive stroke of luck and a miracle. Here? Here, the rules bend and are bent. Bullets stray away, are deflected of invisible walls that later turn out to be an anomaly or a poltergeist pulling the strings of gravity. But if you fill the head with enough bullets, nobody can survive that. Even the Oasis wouldn't help those poor bastards. You'll find the place one day, too, I'm sure, but in the meantime, put on a metal baseball cap or something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_157">
		<text>A firefight is a hellish thing. Bullets zipping by all around you. Some bury deep into your flesh, some just zoom past you and hit something or someone else. It's chaos, pure and simple. Sometimes you can survive a bandit ambush from all sides, and sometimes one guy can get lucky and strike you down with one well-placed shot. And even if he doesn't kill you, he most certainly will damage your gear. Stuff is barely functioning as it is, and it sure ain't bulletproof, so it's going to get raped in a firefight. That's reality and that's how it works. Nothing you can do about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_158">
		<text>When you shoot a guy, you won't find everything he had on him, there's no way in hell that's gonna happen. The stress of the fight, the shock of killing someone, it all affects your senses. Sometimes you will find a pack of cigs he was smoking earlier, sometimes you won't find them. Maybe he wanted to hide the pack since it was his last, who knows. You won't get everything you think you deserve, the Zone is not about fairness after all, so cut it out with all that nonsense right know and grow some testicles. And yeah, if the guy you just shot drops like rock onto something or rolls down a cliff, his stuff will get mushed, broken, destroyed. So you won't have a chance at dipping in that butter jar at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_159">
		<text>No one has as much free time as you do, and Cardan is no exception. Don't assume he's just waiting for you to get your ass to his workshop and shove your sticky, shitty, wasted shooter on his desk. No, no, hell no. He's got his own shit to worry about apart from fixing all the weapons of the world. Sometimes it's just more worthwhile to fix the shit yourself. Clean the gun once in a while, lubricate it. Get a repair kit and use it when you really need it. But don't forget the eroding and destructive power of the Zone that will devour your soul as much as it will devour machinery. Cars don't last here, nor do helicopters or sophisticated machines. Keep it simple, keep it clean, keep it going, and you might see another day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_160">
		<text>I never sell any repair items, man, I just keep them in my box. I know it's good loot, Beard, Owl and Hawaiian love to buy 'em, but I think it's better to just use 'em for my weapons and armor. When you sell something to someone, you sell it cheaper than the price you can buy it for, and then when you buy repair items from someone else, you've got to pay again, and in the end you lose a lot of money. Do shit on your own, it's much more frugal and you get to save a lot. Stalkers don't know how to save here, and whine all the time that they don't have enough dough. What did you think when you came here, you motherfucking piece of dead rat? The Zone taxes you. Materials are hard to come by, weapons even harder. You don't just pay for that one shooter, but you pay for the whole infrastructure that supports the war machine that enables you to buy that one shooter. It's a simple economy, and you should be aware that everything here is expensive as doing everything has its risks and its costs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_161">
		<text>Have you noticed that the Zone just freezes sometimes? It stutters, and everything else stops for microseconds. We call this the Stutter. Some say it's an echo from the first Chernobyl explosion, coming back to remind us of the horror. Some say it is neurological, and our brains, under the influence of the Zone, have problems processing sensual information. And the latter has been proposed by those scientists in the bunker. They've studied the phenomenon and are still baffled by some aspects of it. I have a theory that the stutters are actually microemissions, happening so fast that they can't hurt anyone, but are annoying as hell, especially in the middle of a fight. If some genius Stalker comes up with a way to negate that effect for himself, he'll have a massive advantage over the rest of us. Alas, such Stalker has not yet appeared, and the Stutter always keeps us company. I really hope the Stutter doesn't cause any neurological damage, I don't want to leave this place retarded or something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_162">
		<text>Flashlight is a basic tool here. You can't shoot what you can't see, you can't walk where you can't see. Every Stalker usually carries a flashlight. It's a great tiny thing, mind you, no external batteries are required for it to work. But for more experienced or well-off Stalkers there are also headlamps that Owl has sometimes in stock. And they're great too, because they free up both of your hands. That comes in handy when you wanna shoot with a two-handed weapon or have to use both of your hands for some other "activity". But remember that headlamp needs to be equipped and uses battery power from the UPD. Night vision is another expensive story but I can't tell you shit about it. Just remember that the headlamp is automatically shut off when you are using the handheld flashlight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_163">
		<text>We know everyone, and everyone knows everyone here. We are like a small village. A newcomer comes up, he shines like a dying star. Everybody can notice newcomers right away, and we don't particularly trust them. I won't go into details as to why, mostly because you are a newcomer too, but it has something to do with earning respect and doing something useful for this little community we have here. Growing the mushrooms, hunting some monsters and chasing some bandits, these types of things. And if you do good, we might even help you when you're in a pinch. Some morons come waiving the latest and greatest of the outside world, and then get robbed before they can say 'hello' or 'how do you do'. They think equipment is what makes the difference here, and they couldn't be more wrong. 'cause it's not. It's experience and respect of the people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_164">
		<text>I've opened up a boar, yes. What's it to you? I wanted to find out why they weren't dying that easily when I unloaded everything I had into their heads. When I opened that fucker up, I noticed their brain and major organs moved to the back of their head. In short, they mutated and adapted superfast to us shooting their mugs. Their tissue is as hard as Kevlar, for fuck's sake. Not sure how this was possible since I didn't have a microscope, and even if I had one, I wouldn't know how to use it, but I have to tell you that my knife did not go through that shit at all. And I sharpen it every single day. I did notice though that their thighs, our favorite meal, are more soft, and if you shoot them enough they open up like a can of tuna. But strange beasts they are, maybe they'll get used to it and grow some extra-hard muscles there, and become masters of the Zone, banishing all Stalkers… Probably not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_165">
		<text>Who wants a shooter in their mouth? Not Stalkers, not bandits, not even your best friends. It is disrespectful and just plain annoying. I'd smack anyone who comes up to me with his shooter towards me, even if I'm selling him something. The trigger finger is a gentle thing, not to be trifled with. Sometimes the gun can shoot for seemingly no fucking reason, and what do you think would happen if it was my face in front of that shooter? You so eager to find out? I'm not, and I'll beat the ass of anyone who points the gun at me. Treat people with respect, and you won't get hurt. Well, bandits ain't people, so in their case it's a roll of the dice. Maybe they'll shoot you, maybe they won't, but you shouldn't feel too safe near 'em.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_166">
		<text>The better your shooter, the more modern and clean it is, the more you can upgrade it. Although worn or old weapons are usually initially cheaper, it's worth to invest in a better profile, instead of being greedy and buying a cheaper older version. Upgrades can really change your life and they increase your life expectancy too. If it wasn't for the full auto mode on my shotgun, I wouldn't be telling you this. I'd probably be some Zombie, drooling all over myself, and shooting anything that has brains I can eat. Damn, I'm very happy that I managed to get out of that shit bucket. This place is not much of an improvement, but I like the company much better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_167">
		<text>I've been here since the beginning, man. Ever since the Zone was wild and everyone was killing everyone to hold down a rusty piece of shit in the middle of nowhere. It was dog eat dog, kill or be killed… Some say it has never changed and it has always been like this. I just don't agree. There was a time when it was different, you know? More order. It's like God, right? You might be indifferent to him, and he may be a fucking cruel and spiteful being who only wishes to rape and destroy everything you hold dear, but there was some sort of logic to the madness… The Ten Commandments and shit… keep to this, and you'll probably be alright. The Zone used to be like this. You could sort of predict what was going to happen…. now it's all changed. Everything's gone to shit… you can't predict anything. Artifacts used to be visible to the naked eye, the Monolith kept to themselves… now that some crazy fucker turned the Scorcher off and everyone went north, all bets are off. There's no God left in this place, man. Only the Zone… and if that doesn't terrify you, you clearly haven't been here long enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_168">
		<text>I knew this guy once - name of Scar… craziest motherfucker I've ever seen. He had a deathwish. No matter how dangerous the mission was, no matter how unlikely it was he was going to come back alive, he took it… didn't have a care in the world. Can't imagine why someone would be like that… he must have been pretty screwed up in the head, right? But here's the crazy thing… It seems like nothing could finish that bastard off. He once got hit by two emissions in the space of a week, was out in the open, and survived both times. Can you fucking believe that? It's like the Zone saw his challenge and wanted to punish him for his arrogance. Ain't nothing for free in this world, man. Not even Death, if the Zone doesn't want you to have it. Some reckon he sold his soul to the Zone… God only knows what happened to him. He fell off the face of the world.. but someone like that doesn't go easy, you know? Wonder what he's up to now…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_169">
		<text>I know the Zone's a harsh place… but some people go way overboard. I was travelling with a Stalker the other day, and we heard some moans. Turns out a group of Loners got fucked by a bloodsucker. They managed to take it out, but they were hurting pretty bad, man…. And this guy, he pulls out his shooter, walks over to each of them and puts a bullet in their heads. Killing them in cold blood… How can people be like that? He said it was the merciful thing to do… But couldn't we have done something else? It wasn't that far from the camp… we could have dragged them there and tried to help, you know? Even if we wouldn't have been able to save all of them, one or two would make it. The Zone makes monsters out of people, Stalker… That's for fucking sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_170">
		<text>One thing I really can't stand is people who are cruel to animals. Yeah, there's my type in the Zone too. Don't get me wrong, I understand the laws of the Zone: it's kill or be killed, and if an animal is dead set on your life then you have to do what you have to do to survive… But I always avoid encounters with them whenever I can, and if I have to kill them, I try to be as humane as possible. Too much unnecessary suffering in the world, man, so let's not add more to it. See this shotgun? It's designed so that it takes down almost anything in one shot. Yup, just like Trapper's. My types usually join the hunters… for some reason. Guess they figure that culling certain animals is a necessary evil and it's better to do it efficiently and humanely without making them suffer, you know? I came across a group of bandits the other day. They had a dog and were cutting parts off it while it was still alive. Maybe it was a "monster", but still - it's a living being… If there hadn't been so many of them, or if I had a better gun, I wouldn't have hesitated to kill those bandit monsters myself. The Zone redefines the rules, that's a given, but you need to cling to what's left of morality inside of us… or else you become a monster yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_171">
		<text>The Zone changes people, mate. It's true… Everything you see, everything you do, has to benefit you in some way or you're not going to make it. You're forced to become this perfect economic actor: you gotta chose a course of action that will turn out to be the most profitable or else you'll end up dead. Maximum profit with least effort, that's the way your brain is gonna work after your cells get used to constant threat of death. And if you'll gain the most by slaughtering some guys that wouldn't harm a fly, so be it. They would be dead in no time anyway, but what if one of them has something of value to you? Survival of the fittest, man. Weaklings don't make it, the strong survive, so you better be sure you're one of the latter, an alpha, before you go starting any feuds, because if you're not you're in for a world of hurt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_172">
		<text>I never used to buy into that religious crap, you know? God is great, god is merciful, god is a vengeful and jealous fucker. How can he be all three? And at the same time? No one could answer this question for me, and so I didn't believe. Then I came into the Zone and my perspective changed completely… They say there's no atheists in foxholes, but you'd have to be a pretty hardline motherfucker to be one here too. You gotta see it with your own eyes, experience it first-hand, and you'll be reborn. There's things here that defy explanation. I guess you can look at it scientifically: evolution of mutants, chemical reactions in anomalies, and so on… But there's stuff here that science just can't explain. And exactly such a thing happened to me. A friend of mine died when we were kids. It was a stupid mistake… never should have happened. I guess I always blamed myself for his death, you know? We were into some pretty crazy shit… and it turns out that he was the one who suffered for it. I eventually got over it, as best I could, but you never truly get over something like that. The other day, I saw him. I swear to God, he was right there in front of me. He asked me why it happened. Why I didn't do anything. I damn near broke down and cried. He knew everything. What happened, how it was my fault, and how one day I will be judged. Then he was gone… craziest thing I've ever witnessed. So yeah, some might like to think the Zone is scientific wonderland, but I think otherwise… This is a cursed place, Stalker. Every day I walk through here, I can't help but think we're one day closer to the judgment day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_173">
		<text>Hey, watch your back around here. Some guys aren't like me. They're proper scum. Me? I live and let live. Provided you stay out of my way, I'll stay out of yours. Fuck with me, though, and you're going to regret it when you realize you ain't got any means of keeping your guts inside you. Yeah, ask anyone - they'll tell you not to fuck with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_174">
		<text>I used to be a guide back in the old days. It's a hard job - not only are you responsible for your own life, but the lives of others aswell. I speak English pretty well, so I would often take "tourists" into the Zone. Rich fuckers who wanted to see what the Zone was all about, without the hardship of actually living here. Got pretty famous for a while… People started a rumour that I knew the way to the Wish Granter. I didn't, but I didn't mind people thinking I did. A lot of business came my way. The thing is… in the Zone you really get to know people. You want to know a man's character? A week in the Zone will tell you everything you need to know about him.. and the people that came to me, wanting their desires granted… well, it would make me shudder. Empty men, with dead eyes… Nothing they do is ever for the benefit of anybody but themselves. Even if I did know the way to the Wish Granter, I don't think I'd take a damn soul - not all wishes are good, you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_175">
		<text>Why are you coming to me? I hope you're not seeking salvation. I have no right to promise you that all is going to end well, because it won't. I'm a priest… in word only now, it seems. I used to believe that God was merciful, that He was fair and just… but having seen the things I've seen how can I go on preaching? I came to the Zone in the hope of rekindling the faith in these lost souls, but it seems I've become lost myself. Nothing could prepare me for this place. I've worked in missions all around the world, and even in the darkest moments there's still some glimmer of faith - of hope. Here? Well, you could walk a thousand years in the Zone and not find a single person who's a true believer. The Zone beats it out of you, and laughs gleefully while it does.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_176">
		<text>Saw the freakiest fucking thing ever not too long ago. Me and the boys were on a raid, right… and we found this weird guy. He seemed pretty out of it. Didn't know what the fuck he was doing or saying. Like some sort of retard, I guess. Had no supplies, no gun, no ammo, no nothing, only his black trenchcoat. We were a bit too soft, felt sorry for him, and we decided to let him come with us. An extra guy might come in handy if shit goes down, right? Even if he's a wacko. At least that's what we thought. Went to sleep that night, and it was a gunshot that woke us up. My friend right beside me was screaming like a madman and aiming at something that was hovering over him. Looked like a person, but it was all out of whack… its arms were deformed or something. Guess it tried to kill my friend but he woke up just in time and managed to get a gunshot off, hit this thing in the shoulder and it ran off screaming. That dude we picked up? No sign of him, just his trenchcoat…. Yeah, some weird shit out there, let me tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_177">
		<text>I usually don't sleep in camps… Most of the time the "benefits" aren't worth it, you know? Sure, all this crowd may keep you safe from a mutant attack, but if some fucker steals your piece then you're fucked either way, right? A lot of thieving bastards out there. And I don't fancy having so many people around. Crowd mentality, you know? You can never be sure what's gonna happen next when there's a bunch of dim-witted morons posing as leaders and telling other idiots what to do. Some might say "safety in numbers", but fuck that, you know? I stick to the rule that it's your duty to keep yourself safe and not to rely on others to cover your ass. So I like to pick a nice sheltered spot out in the middle of nowhere… Sure, the occasional mutant might wake you up and you gotta stay on your toes at all times. Yeah, there's that. But mind that - in the end it's you versus the Zone, and not you and your friends versus the Zone. 'Cause your only friend is yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_178">
		<text>Free will, huh? I have read all sorts of wise books before I came here, but none of this shit applies in the Zone. Free will simply does not exist in this place. There isn't a single person in the Zone who is here out of choice. Virtually everyone I've talked to has the same background. Usually criminals hiding from the law, dodging the draft or just your average Joes that have to provide for their families. And the economic crisis in the Great Land has only made matters worse for everyone. The governments weren't able to stop it and ended up reintroducing slavery. So the only choice you've got is this: escape here or have your life ruined. And that's hardly a choice at all, you're only choosing between two brands of misfortune. And all the people, once they get here, realize that their life is pretty much over anyway - they have almost no chance of escaping and average life expectancy is so low that some of them don't even struggle at all. Some of them, more crafty ones, realize that at least they will be able to send their families some money so that they don't end up as commodities in the human trafficking market. The entire situation makes me sick…. Sorry, I don't feel like talking anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_179">
		<text>Hope is a dangerous thing to have in the Zone. There are those who will tell you it is all that keeps them moving, gives them the drive to go on - but I say it is the most dangerous thing of all. The Zone knows. Everything. Your desires, your wants, you dirty secrets… It knows everything. There's not a single thought in your head that the Zone doesn't know, and you can't hide anything from it. Forget privacy: you should assume that whatever you do, whatever you know, whatever you feel the Zone already knows. And you have to remember that the Zone despises feelings, all feelings, but hope, in any form, makes it especially angry. A friend of mine had a family back home. A beautiful wife and two daughters. He would tell me about them all the time, just couldn't stop yapping. I remember there was one thing he always carried with him - an album full of photos of his family. He kept telling me that "today was the day" he was going to make it. And it seemed that this day finally came. He got lucky, found an artifact nobody had ever seen before, took it to the scientists and it turned out they were willing to pay a shitload of money for it. Literally. They didn't have this much dough with them at the moment, so he had to wait for their next supply drop… So yeah, he made it. Then he suffered a bite to the leg. A dog. What started off as a routine infection suddenly got worse. The wound started to fester, maggots made it their home, flies were buzzing around. In no time all flesh in the leg was eaten away. No doctor could help him. Amputation didn't work, infection spread too fast for us to be able to contain it. And the smell, this god-awful smell, would stay with him till his last day. He died before he could get paid… I don't know what happened to the artifact. I wouldn't be surprised if the Zone reclaimed it. After that I wanted to contact his family… Let them know what really happened, but nobody had the slightest idea who he was or where he came from. No hope, Stalker… It will kill you. Trust me on this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_180">
		<text>It amazes me how there's so much talent in the Zone. Every place has its own bards and artists, and the Zone is no exception. But there are differences: in the Great Land poets, writers, musicians tend to be devalued. There's simply no need for them in a society where expert knowledge is the currency. And here a good story, good music, good read are respected, especially if they will increase your odds in the roulette against the Zone. You could even say that good storytelling shows how experienced you are: the better and more believable your tale, the more shit you must have gone through. But truly exceptional are those artists who managed to hit the softest spots in our hearts. I've seen veteran Stalkers moved to tears by a piece of music that reminds them of home - of a happier time. The Zone can be a harsh place, but despite that the human spirit still burns strongly. You can put us in chains, but still we'll sing and live on, no matter what the Zone throws at us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_information_181">
		<text>Fuck it, almost every guy I talk to shits his pants every time mercs are mentioned in a goddamn conversation. Boogeymen of the Zone, you could say. But not me, I'm not scared of 'em. See, they might have shit-hot equipment and training… but one thing they ain't got is Zone-smarts. This shit you only learn the hard way - through experience, through sweat and tears. Ain't no way standard military training allows you to predict when an emission is going to hit… But once you get into the Zone, survive a few of 'em, and you'll just know. A tingling behind your eyes, your teeth aching, some little sign that tells you all hell is about to break loose and you need to get your ass someplace safe. The mercs think they can take the Zone by force… Impossible, I tell ya. Want to see where that attitude will take you? Look at those military choppers - fucking ripped out of the sky like they were made of paper. The Zone is a cruel, hard bitch, and won't come down so easily. Especially since it is the absolute ruler and force is a currency it trades in. No use opposing it.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Jobs -->
	<string id="dm_job_general_1">
		<text>Anyone posting jobs around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_general_2">
		<text>I'm looking for work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_general_3">
		<text>Know where I can find work?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_0">
		<text>Sorry, I don't know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_1">
		<text>Spore is always looking for someone to do odd jobs every now and again. He is an information broker. Got the scoop on something big going down in the Zone? Spore will pay well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_2">
		<text>I heard Librarian has been seeking experienced hunters to clear out some mutants at different locations throughout the marshes. Seems to be less volunteers to go out hunting at night, so you'll have a better chance to get the job then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_3">
		<text>Sidorovich always has something that needs done. He usually pays well, but I wouldn't recommend any rookie take the jobs he offers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_4">
		<text>Wolf has been looking for help. He pays stalkers to hunt mutants in the local area to ensure the safety of the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_5">
		<text>Owl, who hangs out at the Skadovsk, is always looking to buy or sell information. I would go ask him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_6">
		<text>Sultan's seeking people with balls of steel for some shit. He hangs out back at base, in the throne room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_7">
		<text>Head toward the scientists' bunker. I'm sure they have something. They are always looking for mercs or stalkers to help them out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_8">
		<text>Olivius is the man to see if you are looking to do some odd jobs. He is a trader who stays at the Dark Valley camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_9">
		<text>Yeah, here's a job. From here, head west. Then keep going west. And when you've done that, don't come back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_job_10">
		<text>Sorry, man, I've got nothing for you. Just dig in and help us hold on to what we've got.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Tips -->
	<string id="dm_tips_general_1">
		<text>Know anything useful?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_general_2">
		<text>How do you manage to stay alive here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_general_3">
		<text>What kind of advice can you give about the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_0">
		<text>I really don't have any advice to give you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_1">
		<text>You shoot a guy in the face a couple times, and he's finished. It won't matter what he's wearing as long as it ain't an exo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_2">
		<text>Use a grenade or two to get a guy to shift his ass. He won't be hiding there much longer if he sees a pineapple roll up next to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_3">
		<text>If you have a fast enough trigger finger, you can fire off both barrels of a shotgun at the same time. Keep that in mind if you run into a bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_4">
		<text>Don't underestimate pistols, stalker. They're pretty handy if you ain't got much ammo left for your main shooter, and they'll waste anything with light armour.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_5">
		<text>If you're running a hit, you can waste the poor bastard without being seen using a sniper rifle; you'll be able to whack him from much further than with your other shooters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_6">
		<text>You ain't gonna be able to hit shit if you're running while shooting. Find some cover to hide behind and lean out to shoot; you'll be far more accurate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_7">
		<text>Keep your gear in good condition. You gun will jam and your suit will be full of holes if you don't see a technician every now and then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_8">
		<text>Last time I went to see a technician, he couldn't upgrade half my shit… Asked me to go out and fetch tools for him. What, am I his errand boy now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_9">
		<text>Ever met a guy who stood outside during an emission? Of course you haven't! Hide your ass whenever one hits unless you feel like having your brain boiled.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_10">
		<text>Almost lost my legs the other day. Planted a whole cluster of butterfly mines to cover my ass when scavenging and forgot about them on my way back. They'll go off no matter who planted 'em.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_11">
		<text>Just because the trader don't have a job for you doesn't mean none of us do. You can make some good money running errands for others. Might find some good loot in the meantime, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_12">
		<text>Keep hold of any meds you might find; you never know when they might be useful. Hercules is pretty good when you're hauling goods, and psi-block will help you against any controllers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_13">
		<text>Carry some spare ammo on you even if you don't think you need it. Nothing worse than having to fight off a horde of mutants with just your blade.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_14">
		<text>You tried artefact hunting? Get a detector and go near some anomalous area; if the thing starts bleeping at you, then there's one nearby. Though you'll need one of the expensive models to find the good shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_15">
		<text>Don't run face first straight into an anomaly. If you think there's one nearby, toss a few bolts at it. Rather the bolts than you, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_16">
		<text>If you ain't feeling too good, then try eating some food. Might not have the same affect as a medkit, but it'll perk you up enough to keep you going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_17">
		<text>Don't ignore your PDA. It'll keep track of your tasks and help you find your way around the Zone if you're lost or planning on going somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_18">
		<text>Holster that shooter if you're going to talk to someone. Nobody likes having the end of a barrel being waved in front of their face.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_19">
		<text>Make sure to pack energy drinks with you. They'll come in handy if you keep tiring out when carrying loot back to camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_20">
		<text>If your helmet has night vision, make sure to upgrade it. You'll be able to see further and clearer if you let a technician screw around with it for some cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_21">
		<text>You aren't defenceless if you're out artefact hunting. So what if you're carrying your detector? You can still hold a pistol in the other hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_22">
		<text>Plenty of places to sleep at if you need to pass the time. There's always a free bed at most camps, but you can take a sleeping bag out with you anywhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_23">
		<text>Artefacts aren't all good news; they'll kill you slowly with their radiation unless you're protected. Keep in mind that there are artefacts which can absorb radiation, too, though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_24">
		<text>Your knife ain't just a weapon for sneaking up on people with; you can bust open boxes, chests, and locks with it, too. Who knows, might find something cool inside…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_25">
		<text>If you keep finding yourself running out of breath, then stop carrying so much shit. You can stash it away somewhere in a backpack, or sell it to a trader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_26">
		<text>If you want meds, then go see a medic, and if you want booze, then go see barkeep; a lot of traders out here specialise in certain types of goods.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_27">
		<text>You won't find artefacts at the same place all the time; they all change about after an emission. Remember that next time you're near an anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_28">
		<text>The Zone has a life of its own, stalker. Just because there weren't any freaks about the last time you went some place doesn't mean they haven't moved in since.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_29">
		<text>If you ain't got nothin' to deal with radiation poisoning, then try to keep yourself alive until you can reach a medic. But then ask yourself: why aren't you carrying any vodka?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_30">
		<text>Run and jump if something looks too far away; your momentum will carry you farther. Easy way to get away from some muties, as they won't think to jump over shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_31">
		<text>Selling artefacts isn't the only way to make some cash: offloading unneeded equipment can be a profitable business, too. Keep in mind that traders aren't usually interested in items that are broke.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_32">
		<text>Crouch and sneak about if you don't wanna get seen or heard. Not ever battle is worth fighting, or maybe you just want to get the jump on someone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_33">
		<text>You can attach scopes and launchers to your shooter, y'know? There are just some things a technician just can't do. But you'll have to find the parts yourself…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_34">
		<text>There are different ways to take down different types of mutants; they all have their own weak spots. You can kick tushkanos and rats, too, y'know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_35">
		<text>Don't go hiding behind a door if some guy's shooting at you. Bullets don't care if there's anything between the two of you… It'll go straight through anything weak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_36">
		<text>Bandage yourself up if you get blasted or torn up by a mutant. The bleeding will cost you more in medkits than if you use a bandage to stop it before it gets too serious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_37">
		<text>If you're looking for tools for weapon modifications or suit upgrades, you should head to Sidorovich. He's been handing out stash coordinates along with cash for doing his jobs. You've got a better chance of finding equipment in stashes, rather than the body of some bandit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_tips_38">
		<text>Pay attention to radio chatter, because it's a damn good way to find out what's going on in the area. You'll be able to provide assistance to anyone in a gunfight or surrounded by mutants.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Wounded -->
	<string id="dm_wounded_general">
		<text>Help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_wounded_medkit">
		<text>Take a first aid kit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_wounded_sorry">
		<text>Sorry, I don't have a medkit.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_traveler_bye">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_what_are_you_doing">
		<text>What are you doing now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_where_are_you_going">
		<text>Where are you going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_can_i_go_with_you">
		<text>Can you take me with you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_stalker_actor_companion_yes">
		<text>Of course. The company is always more fun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_stalker_actor_companion_no">
		<text>No, sorry. I work better alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_actor_go_with_squad">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_take_me_to">
		<text>Could you take me somewhere? I'll pay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_stalker_where_do_you_want">
		<text>No problem. Where do you want to go? Take a pick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_actor_agree">
		<text>OK. Come on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_actor_refuse">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_stalker_i_cant_travel">
		<text>Not right now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_travel_start">
		<text>Äåëî îäíî åñòü</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_travel_end">
		<text>òóäà è íàïðàâëÿþñü.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_stalker_doing_nothing_1">
		<text>Oh, nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_doing_nothing_2">
		<text>Nothing. Just relaxing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_doing_nothing_3">
		<text>What does it look like? I'm being lazy…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_doing_nothing_4">
		<text>I'm trying to survive here, that's all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_chasing_squad_monster">
		<text>I'm hunting a mutant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_chasing_squad_bandit">
		<text>I'm on the trail of some bandit scum.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_chasing_squad_killer">
		<text>Tracking some mercenaries… Those guys are the bastards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_chasing_squad_monolith">
		<text>I'm on the trail of a squad of fanatics. They call themselves the 'Monolith'…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_chasing_squad_zombied">
		<text>We are chasing a zombie. Empty shells of once great stalkers. Poor wretches…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_travel_cost">
		<text>Good. It will cost you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_actor_dont_go_with_squad">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_traveler_actor_has_no_money">
		<text>I have no money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_freedom_doing_nothing_1">
		<text>I'm not doing anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_freedom_chasing_squad_monster">
		<text>I'm on the trail of some mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_freedom_chasing_squad_bandit">
		<text>I'm taking part in the local bandit chase.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_freedom_chasing_squad_killer">
		<text>I'm following a bunch of mercenaries. They'll pay for attacking us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_freedom_chasing_squad_monolith">
		<text>We are after some crackpots from the Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_freedom_chasing_squad_duty">
		<text>Duty is somewhere around here… Bastards can't be too far away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_duty_doing_nothing_1">
		<text>We are not doing anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_duty_chasing_squad_monster">
		<text>We are purging this area of mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_duty_chasing_squad_bandit">
		<text>I'm on a job, chasing a bandit detachment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_duty_chasing_squad_killer">
		<text>We were attacked by mercs. I won't rest until they are dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_duty_chasing_squad_monolith">
		<text>We are hunting down a squad of those Monolith freaks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_duty_chasing_squad_freedom">
		<text>We are cleaning out the rubbish that call themselves 'Freedom'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_searching_artefacts_1">
		<text>I'm searching for artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_searching_artefacts_2">
		<text>We're collecting mushrooms… What do you think we're doing idiot? We are looking for artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_stalker_searching_artefacts_3">
		<text>I am artefact hunting.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Technician -->
	<string id="st_mechanic_query_items">
		<text>Is any of my equipment ready for pick-up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mechanic_repair_done">
		<text>Yes. Here you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mechanic_repair_not_done">
		<text>Not yet. Check back later.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Surrender -->

	<string id="st_surrender_victim_1">
		<text>I give up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_2">
		<text>Have some mercy, mate!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_3">
		<text>Easy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_4">
		<text>That's enough! I'm unarmed.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="st_surrender_query_actor_1">
		<text>What's left to do with you now?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_actor_2">
		<text>Tell me one reason not to drop you on the spot.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_actor_3">
		<text>Convince me to let you live. I'll count to three.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_actor_4">
		<text>Time to die. Any last words?</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Nothing -->

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_1">
		<text>What can I tell you? I've got no money, so there's nothing I can offer you. I didn't have a good life when I made it into the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_2">
		<text>…To hell with it. Pull the trigger. I don't care anymore.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_3">
		<text>Please, don't shoot! I've got a wife; I've got children! They're the only reason I'm even in this place!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_4">
		<text>Have some mercy on me! Spare me! Please!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_5">
		<text>Our Father who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done…</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_6">
		<text>…Honey… My dear… forgive me. I won't be coming back…</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_7">
		<text>Spare me, mate. The cancer I've got is going to be the end of me either way… Don't take what I've got.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_8">
		<text>Have pity on me, mate! My nan won't survive if I don't get out of the Zone alive.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_9">
		<text>What do you want? Money? Weapons? Artefacts? If I had any of that, I wouldn't be under your barrel here, now, would I?!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_10">
		<text>I don't intend to beg for my life. If you're going to shoot, do it; that's your decision to live with.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_11">
		<text>Come on, bruv. We had a little quarrel, and so what? We're both grown men! Let's act civilised, eh?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_12">
		<text>Think you're tough? Bugger off, you muppet. Do you know the connections I've got? They're gonna hunt you down in the blink of an eye if you do anything to me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_13">
		<text>Get on with it and pull the bloody trigger. Better than wandering into an anomaly or ending up as dog food.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_14">
		<text>Easy, mate. Easy. Let's not get rough here. Say you shoot me; what will you get out of it anyway? Gonna take my rusty shooter or my patch for bragging rights? Come on! It ain't worth it…</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_query_victim_15">
		<text>No… no… no need for more violence! I beg you: don't kill me! I'm a fool… Just a stupid fool! W-why did I get into this?</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_surrender_end_1">
		<text>To hell with you. I won't be dirtying my hands any further. Let the Zone decide what to do with you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_end_2">
		<text>Convincing. Grab a bandage, get on your feet, and beat it while I'm still nice to you!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_end_3">
		<text>What were you saying? Nothing; that's what. Save your excuses for the next world.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="st_surrender_bounty">
		<text>I was promised a reward for taking your head. Any last words?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_actor_1">
		<text>You'll live.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_actor_2">
		<text>Good luck…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_actor_3">
		<text>Time to end you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_1">
		<text>Okay, okay, just don't kill me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_2">
		<text>Fuck! Okay!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_3">
		<text>Please, man! I will tell you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_4">
		<text>Please, don't kill me! Take my PDA! It has everything you need to know on it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_5">
		<text>Go fuck yourself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_6">
		<text>Thank you!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_default_bounty_1">
		<text>Okay, okay, just don't kill me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_default_bounty_2">
		<text>Fuck! Okay!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_default_bounty_3">
		<text>Please, man! I will tell you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_default_bounty_4">
		<text>Please, don't kill me! Take my PDA! It has everything you need to know on it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_default_bounty_5">
		<text>Go fuck yourself!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_esc_m_trader_bounty_1">
		<text>That bastard Sidorovich sent you, didn't he? What do you want? Cash?! Here, have my PDA and my money… Just let me live!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_esc_m_trader_bounty_2">
		<text>Do you even know why you were sent to kill me? Do you even give a shit? Sid can burn in hell!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_esc_m_trader_bounty_3">
		<text>Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_esc_m_trader_bounty_4">
		<text>Just put me out of my misery already! Do it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_esc_m_trader_bounty_5">
		<text>…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_bounty_1">
		<text>That bastard Sultan sent you, didn't he? What do you want? Cash?! Here, have my PDA and my money, just let me live!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_bounty_2">
		<text>You soulless fuck! Do you even know why you were sent to kill me? Do you even give a fuck? Sultan can burn in hell!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_bounty_3">
		<text>Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_bounty_4">
		<text>Just put me out of my god damn misery already! Do it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surrender_victim_answer_zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_bounty_5">
		<text>…</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Áðîêåðû -->
	<string id="st_drx_broker_finish_1">
		<text>I will buy this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drx_broker_finish_2">
		<text>Ok, i will take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drx_broker_finish_3">
		<text>Its alright, im buying it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_query">
		<text>I may have some information to sell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_query_more">
		<text>I have something else you may want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_query_pda">
		<text>I found a PDA. Might have something useful on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_query_pdas">
		<text>I found %s PDAs. Some of them might have useful information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_query_valuable">
		<text>I found something that may contain useful information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_trade_valuable">
		<text>%s… Very valuable. I'm interested, for sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_give_pda">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_start_1">
		<text>I'll be the judge of that. What do you have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_start_2">
		<text>You better hope so. Time is money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_start_3">
		<text>This better be worth my time. What do you have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_answer_pda_query">
		<text>Äàâàé ãëÿíåì, íàñêîëüêî âàæíàÿ èíôîðìàöèÿ òàì ñîäåðæèòñÿ.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_answer_info_query">
		<text>Õìì… Çà òàêîå ÿ ìîãó òåáå ïðåäëîæèòü %s RU.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_1">
		<text>Nothing useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_2">
		<text>A couple of stashes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_3">
		<text>Contacts on local drug dealers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_4">
		<text>A journal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_5">
		<text>Coordinates of a stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_6">
		<text>Just some more bullshit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_7">
		<text>Nothing useful on this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_8">
		<text>Some useful contact information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_9">
		<text>Useless, but someone might buy it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_10">
		<text>Mostly junk. I could find a buyer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_11">
		<text>Some useful information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_12">
		<text>A list of passwords.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_13">
		<text>There are some bank details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_14">
		<text>Ain't much on this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_15">
		<text>This one mentions a local meeting going down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_16">
		<text>Detailed observations regarding mutations on local flora.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_17">
		<text>Looks like an awesome game on this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_18">
		<text>Detailed observations regarding fleshes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_19">
		<text>Detailed observations regarding boars.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_common_20">
		<text>Detailed observations regarding Whirligig anomalies.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_1">
		<text>I know some people who will want this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_2">
		<text>Photos of a Freedomer trying to bone a bloodsucker…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_3">
		<text>A contact on a drug dealer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_4">
		<text>Encrypted. Might be valuable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_5">
		<text>This one mentions a stash location.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_6">
		<text>This one is encrypted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_7">
		<text>Crazy journal entries on this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_8">
		<text>Some useful contact information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_9">
		<text>Smuggling route information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_10">
		<text>I could find a buyer for this one here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_11">
		<text>Some useful information on this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_12">
		<text>Bank account information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_13">
		<text>This mentions a meeting between Duty and a local gang of thugs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_14">
		<text>There are coordinates here for a supply exchange point.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_15">
		<text>This one mentions a local meeting going down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_16">
		<text>Detailed information about rats and hamsters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_17">
		<text>Information on a short-cut through Red Forest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_18">
		<text>Porn… This one is full of porn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_19">
		<text>Detailed observations on a variety of anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_uncommon_20">
		<text>Lots of chat logs, might have something useful.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_1">
		<text>Fantastic. Some dirt on Beard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_2">
		<text>Mentions of a huge stash… I'll take this for sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_3">
		<text>Great! This mentions a drug smuggler making dealing with the military.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_4">
		<text>Encrypted. Might be valuable; I'll keep this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_5">
		<text>This one mentions a location of a stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_6">
		<text>Encrypted. If they have something to hide, it may be something I want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_7">
		<text>This one has detailed information about Duty… Freedom might want this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_8">
		<text>Bank account and credit card information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_9">
		<text>Alleged location of the Oasis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_10">
		<text>I could find a buyer for this one here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_11">
		<text>Some useful information on this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_12">
		<text>Unencrypted passwords and bank account information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_13">
		<text>This mentions a meeting between some mercs and local thugs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_14">
		<text>There are coordinates here for a supply exchange point.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_15">
		<text>This one mentions a local meeting going down in a few days.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_16">
		<text>Maps! A regular cartographer! This one is very useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_17">
		<text>Short-cut information through an anomaly field.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_18">
		<text>Upcoming supply exchange point here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_19">
		<text>Scientists might want this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_rare_20">
		<text>What the…? This one just says 'Kill Strelok'.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_broker_npc_about_pda_bonus_coords">
		<text>As a bonus, here are some coordinates to stashes I don't really care to get.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Tasks -->
	<string id="st_ordered_task_query">
		<text>Is there any work you want done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ordered_task_query_finished">
		<text>The job is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ordered_task_not_given_task">
		<text>What? I don't think you've finished what I've asked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ordered_task_accept">
		<text>I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ordered_task_next">
		<text>Have anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_accepted_task_1">
		<text>Good! Talk to me again when it's done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_accepted_task_2">
		<text>Come through for me and I'll come through for you. Get back to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_accepted_task_3">
		<text>Glad you can be of assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_accepted_task_4">
		<text>That’s great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_accepted_task_5">
		<text>Good luck!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_default_task_finished_1">
		<text>Thank you, stalker. Here is your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_default_task_finished_2">
		<text>I'm glad you’ve come through. Here is what I've promised.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_default_task_finished_3">
		<text>Okay, now for your payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_no_available_task">
		<text>Sorry, don't have anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_about_fetch_task_default">
		<text>I can't remember what I was going to say… Just go get it! You know what I want!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_return_for_reward">
		<text>Return for your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nevermind">
		<text>On second thought, never mind. Come back later.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Task cancelling -->
	<string id="dm_universal_actor_exit_sorry">
		<text>Sorry I couldn't help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ordered_task_query_cancel">
		<text>I couldn't complete the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_task_none_active">
		<text>What job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ordered_task_query_cancel_next_job">
		<text>No. I'm still working on that one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_task_default_excuse_cancel_job">
		<text>Yes. I'm busy with other work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_default_task_cancel_1">
		<text>I'm disappointed in you, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_default_task_cancel_2">
		<text>What? I had thought better of you, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_default_task_cancel_3">
		<text>I guess that is what I should have expected from a rookie.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Repair -->
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_1">
		<text>Your %s will be ready in %s minutes. Come back then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_2">
		<text>Soon, your %s will be ready. Come back in %s minutes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_3">
		<text>Urgh. Piss off. I'm not drunk yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_4">
		<text>Your bloody %s will be ready in an hour and %s minutes. I'll be drunk by then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_5">
		<text>It's not easy to repair something when you have the shakes… Come back in about an hour for your %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_6">
		<text>Hey, stal-oh, heck. I forgot I was repairing your equipment. Come back for your %s in an hour and %s minutes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_7">
		<text>Your %s will be ready in an hour and %s, so come back then, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_8">
		<text>Your %s will be ready in about %s hours and %s. Come back then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_inventory_upgrade_reply_9">
		<text>It's almost ready.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Quest Documents -->
	<string id="st_quest_doc_query">
		<text>I found some old documents, are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_npc_start">
		<text>Sure, let's see what you go there.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_base">
		<text>I'll take it for %s RU.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_base">
		<text>That's great.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_esc_2_12_stalker_trader"> <!-- revision -->
		<text>I will not even ask where you got it from. Such documents are exceptional, almost everyone will benefit from them… including me. I'm ready to buy them right now for %s RU, plus a container for artefacts. What do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_esc_2_12_stalker_trader">
		<text>Excellent! If you find something similar, bring it to me immediately. I will make sure that you get something nice in returns! Do you see that military armory behind me? It's looking right at you… Hehe.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh">
		<text>I guess these documents contain valuable information for our group. Unfortunately, things are not going so well currently, we have just gotten up on our feet. I can only offer you %s RU, forgive me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh">
		<text>Thank you! I understand that what I just gave you is not enough for such valuable information. I'll talk to our merchant, Dispute. Maybe he will save you some extra equipment the next time you bring more documents to us. When our situation improve, I can pay much more for such information, I promise!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_bar_dolg_leader">
		<text>So-so… The military, and the SSU in particular, are ready to pay huge amounts of money for this. Similar documents were discovered during the investigations after the failure of operation "Fairway", which was alarmed by the entire leadership. Let's proceed as follows… %s RU would be the correct price. Not to mention that "Duty" are going through a lot as of late, the current situation has exhausted our resources. However, thanks to these documents, we will be able to arrange the deliveries of the equipment we need. I think that you will get something from this, too. Do you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_bar_dolg_leader">
		<text>Today I will start negotiations with the military, I believe it won't take long enough to see some results. Next time you bring us such documents, I will pick up a more worthy reward for you. For now, take this, in gratitude from "Duty"!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski">
		<text>Interesting… Very interesting. I'll ignore to the fact that you, a simple stalker, suddenly found such documents. Anyway, I have a better idea, or rather: a business proposal. So, you pass these documents to me and forget that you have ever seen them. If you find more, bring them over here, to me personally, without any middlemen, understand? I, on my part, can offer the best army outfit available: weapons, armor, ammunition… Not to mention food and medicine. Not for free, of course, but at very, very affordable prices in our territories. Perhaps I can pay you in cash, but I will decide that later. So, are we agreed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski">
		<text>So, we agreed. For now, here is some money from my pocket, so as not to offend you at all.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_cit_killers_merc_trader_stalker">
		<text>Truly entertaining… Documents about experiments on the territory of the Zone… In times of breakthrough, some of our important clients would offer fabulous sums for them. Times are different now, and it's not that we need them especially in this poor state, but the information lays between these paper is still of sufficient value, hmmm… Let's do it. Now I'll take them for %s RU. You probably won't get more, but I'll try to resell. If they got a worthy buyer, I'll make an exception for you. As you can see, everything we have is coming from our finest providers, we do not live on state kopecks. An ordinary stalker can only droll over this. You can buy directly from our supplier and for the most democratic prices, deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_cit_killers_merc_trader_stalker">
		<text>That's fine. In a couple of days, there will be a decent assortment for you. If you find the same kind of documents. bring them, don't be shy.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_yan_stalker_sakharov">
		<text>Very interesting stuff indeed! Such documents are not our specialty, but their contents can shed light on many of our studies. In addition, I have no doubts that our sponsors will be extremely interested in having them, which will have a very positive impact on our funding in returns. Do you want to conclude a special deal with us on this occasion? For documents like these, you can receive a monetary reward from us. I can arrange %s for the documents you just gave me. If I still manage to persuade our sponsors, we will receive new research equipment soon enough, supply of provisions and scientific equipment improvements. I assure you that you will get a significant benefit from this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_yan_stalker_sakharov">
		<text>Thank you! I am very pleased with our new cooperation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_quest_doc_query_jup_a6_freedom_leader">
		<text>Ha, where did you get these paper? You know, this kind of info can flip the world around upside down! I definitely won't hide it, not after what happened to us at least. The monolith fanatics broke through the Barrier, and started an aggressive attack on the Warehouses. Our squads managed to repel the monolith wave, but at what cost?… Most of our fighters died, few made it alive, and the remnants have gathered here in Jupiter. We can't reach out without support from the "big earth" movement, and these documents will absolutely help on our way to recovery. Our goal is to discover and reveal any kind of informations about the Zone to the outside world, no matter how secret it might be. If some illegal experiments happened in the past, people must know the truth. And "this" in your hands is just the start. Unfortunately, all what I can offer you for now is %s RU. And before you refuse, you should think of it this way: Today you are doing a good job, and tomorrow it will return to you in triple size. Despite the disaster that stroke our forces, we still have access to the black market. You will have access to a better kind of weapons and equipment. Don't worry about "Dolgovtsi" and the rest of Duty either, those blockheads won't know that you are somehow dealing with us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_doc_finish_jup_a6_freedom_leader">
		<text>Perfect! If you find something else that can help us with, I will be very grateful.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
