<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_descr">
		<text>A compound of several hollow organic formations, this artifact emits a gaseous substance that can neutralize chemical or toxic particles inside the body without harming it. Apart from that Bubble, however, possesses numerous negative properties. For example, it greatly amplifies the effects of psy-waves as well as fields produced by mutants and anomalies. This disadvantage is not to be taken lightly: some stalkers have reported that psy influence was so potent when in possession of a Bubble that they felt their heads cracking from the inside and the only thing they could do was scream in pain and run as far as they could. The same mechanism seems to be at work in case of electro anomalies: the artifact will conduct electricity and increase amps of electric current. Moreover, many reports by stalkers indicate that Bubble needs a power source to be functional. This power source is the body itself: the artifact drains vitality and willpower from the user, often on such a scale that it induces dizziness and in extreme cases causes the user to faint. The only other positive aspect to this artifact is the fact that it speeds up healing process and closes up wounds, however it is so potent in this regard that its high price on the market and the demand for it are perfectly justified. Radiation output is highest on the artifact radiation scale. WARNING: Because of its organic nature and instability this artifact is well known to spontaneously combust more so than any other organic artifact and for this reason it is advised to abstain from wearing it in the vicinity of a fire or acid anomaly.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_name">
		<text>Bubble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blood_descr">
		<text>A reddish formation of compressed fossilized plants, soil and animal debris. Can partially neutralize chemical poisons by absorbing them and reducing overall toxicity level in user's bloodstream.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blood_name">
		<text>Stone Blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_descr">
		<text>This artifact is formed in anomalous zones with intense thermal activity. Actively consumes excessive heat and remains cool at all times. It will also protect the user against acids found in toxic and chemical anomalies. On the other hand, exposure to such environments makes the artifact increase the corrosivity of acids due to unknown as of now mechanism. For this reason, one is forced to weigh pros and cons of Crystal when in the vicinity of areas of high toxicity. It also acts as a conductor of electricity. Another positive effect possessed by this artifact is that it accelerates clotting if worn close to the body. (Side note: it is not recommended to keep this artifact in your possession for longer periods of time as blood clots can be hazardous to your health.) This artifact is also highly sought for by jewelers outside the Zone as its inner core is not radioactive and considered to be of exceptional beauty if polished and refined. Only the first 1 cm of its outer layer emits radiation. It is, however, highly advised to proceed with caution when planning to bring the artifact to the market as prolonged exposure to even minimal amounts of radioactive materials can result in death of the user. Covered with very hard layer. Relatively heavy due to high density. Radiation output is lowest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_descr">
		<text>This artifact resembles melted cheese interspersed with sapphire-like stones. Only yellow outer shell of the artifact appears to give off radiation and by careful processing it is possible to extract the non-radioactive blue parts for jewelery and other industrial purposes. This is due to the fact that if cleaned properly and polished, sapphire comparison becomes much more explicit: the stones are as hard and durable as this beautiful gem. This quality of theirs and their appearance make them perfect gemstones and jewelers all over the world strive to have them in stock. The usefulness of the artifact, however, is not limited to its industrial applications. There is scientific evidence suggesting that sapphire-like stones effectively protect from toxicity, whereas the outer shell slightly increases resistance to heat. Due to its density the weight of artifact has increased beyond normal standards, and thus it is one of the heaviest anomalous creations in the Zone. Radiation output is lowest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_name">
		<text>Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_name">
		<text>Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_descr">
		<text>This artifact offers slightly more psy-protection than its cousin, Moonlight. It comprises electrostatic elements, but scientists have yet to determine the exact physical conditions required for its formation. The artifact is quite popular in the Zone and is valued by its residents and visitors alike for its energizing properties, although it has an adverse effect on the body when used for prolonged periods of time. One should take note, however, that this artifact hinders blood clotting and increases bleeding rate of open wounds. On the other hand, being a powerful resistor, it is well known for its ability to shield its user from lethal doses of electricity. This artifact is also extremely light and very portable. Radiation output is low on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_name">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_descr">
		<text>Shell is composed of two disk of bluish color connected by semitransparent material of unknown nature. This strange artifact was considered devoid of any useful properties by many scientists for a long time. Only recently has it been discovered that it is indeed quite beneficial. It provides a high level of psy protection and absorbs electromagnetic interference, acting as a grounding material. When the artifact comes into contact with the body, it will make one feel rejuvenated and thus it increases stamina recovery. This effect has in case of some stalkers induced hyperactivity. One downside of this artifact, however, is that it reduces the number of platelets in blood, thus increasing bleeding rate. Shell is extremely light and very portable. Radiation output is very high on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_name">
		<text>Shell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_descr">
		<text>Shaped like a DNA helix, Mama's Beads are created in the Burner anomaly. One of their most characteristic features is that they constantly pulsate, generating emissions beneficial to the human body. These emissions increase the metabolism of any living creature, accelerating coagulation and healing of wounds. The mechanism behind the effects of this artifact is still unknown. Mama's Beads also possess potent protective qualities: they are able to shield the body and objects from extreme heat and acids. On the other hand, it should be noted that the presence of this artifact increases the corrosivity of acids, leading to accelerated deterioration of equipment and higher damage to tissues of any living organism. It is thus strongly advised to proceed with caution in acidic as well as in toxic environments when in possession of Mama's Beads. Another dangerous effect of this artifact is the fact that it will increase electrical conductivity, so the probability of electrocution while wearing this artifact is much higher, especially during storms and in the vicinity of electrical anomalies. The weight is also quite high for such a small artifact, which leads to a conclusion that is of extremely high density. Radiation output is low on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_name">
		<text>Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_descr">
		<text>This unique electrostatic artifact can resonate under the influence of psy-waves. Stalkers have learned to fine-tune the artifact so that it resonates in opposite phase to the main source of emissions, thus significantly neutralizing their effects. This orb of considerable beauty also increases electrical protection by reducing conductivity in the body when exposed to high levels of electricity. It also enhances energy and stamina recovery, allowing its user to feel energetic and refreshed. An unwanted side effect is that it decreases healing rate and coagulation. This artifact is also extremely light and very portable. Radiation output is low on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_name">
		<text>Moonlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_descr">
		<text>This artifact has the appearance of translucent spider webs. Just as proteinaceous spider silk, it is sticky and has properties of glue. It can be found most commonly in or near electro anomalies and it seems to have absorbed their certain characteristics: it is able to smooth fluctuations in electric field density and acts as a weak resistor, protecting the wearer from electricity and reducing its damaging effects. When worn, the artifact is also known to slightly counter the harmful effects of psy-anomalies or psy-waves of some mutants. Because of its electrical nature, it provides the body with additional albeit weak source of energy. It does not possess any beneficial healing properties, as the gluey fluid produced by the artifact is damaging to living tissue and will prevent blood clotting. It is extremely light. Radiation output is lowest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_name">
		<text>Sparkler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_descr"> <!-- revision -->
		<text>A translucent amorphous formation, esembles a plasma globe or a plasma lamp. It has the ability to increase the endurance of the wearer due to its nature and the way it affects the body. With prolonged use, it loses its charge and eventually "dies". Usually found in anomalies of an electrical nature. Distribution is ubiquitous. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers have shown interest in the artifact.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_name">
		<text>Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_descr">
		<text>This artifact, which resembles the human eye, considerably increases metabolism of the body, helping wounds heal quicker. Experienced stalkers say that Eye also brings luck. Irrespective of the validity of that statement, its positive effects are indeed quite potent. First of all, it reduces temperature of user's body and cools all objects in its vicinity. Secondly, it provides substantial protection against all types of acids by gradually increasing their pH to the level of water (pH of 7). Thirdly, this artifact soothes the pain and is extremely useful when treating wounds. These beneficial qualities, however, come at a price. This artifact is extremely dangerous when exposed to chemical anomalies as it amplifies their toxicity and increases their potency. It is hence highly recommended to keep the artifact in your backpack, never on the body, when exploring toxic areas unless you have a death wish. The artifact is also known colloquially as "copper eye" as it conducts electricity and amplifies its dangerous effects in the same way as copper does. Radiation output is very high on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_name">
		<text>Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_descr">
		<text>This artifact forms in areas of high thermal activity. Produces powerful infrared emissions which intensify metabolic processes, healing wounds before its bearer's very eyes. As this artifact is very rare, it is extremely valuable. As regards its effects, it is similar to the Eye in that it will reduce the temperature of user's body, which is especially useful when exposed to potent heat sources. It also acts as powerful resistor, and negates the effect of acids. Moreover, its healing capabilities are even stronger than in case of the Eye as stalkers in possession of this artifact are said to have survived being wounded by chimeras. Thanks to that, it has earned the reputation of a miraculous artifact. Many stalkers owe it their lives, and most veteran mutant hunters carry it in case they run into danger. However, it shares not only positive but also negative properties of its cousin: entering a toxic or chemical anomaly with this artifact on the belt is suicide. It will increase the corrosivity of chemical particles and enhance the adverse effect of the toxins within user's bloodstream. It can also be used as a reusable medkit of sorts since it heals wounds very quickly. Radiation output is highest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_name">
		<text>Flame</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_descr">
		<text>It is a spherical artifact made of red-colored crystal, created in the Burner anomaly. It has an unique property - it has a constant temperature of 75 degrees Fahrenheit/24 degrees Celsius, regardless of its surroundings. This allows it to absorb heat from its vicinity and to create a little pocket around the user which prevents the flames from damaging the body. Stability of temperature is the cause of another of its positive effects: it accelerates healing rate and stops bleeding. It will also protect the user from chemical burns. However, it is unrecommended to approach chemical and acid anomalies when in possession of the artifact as it will increase the adverse effects of acids and toxins in user's bloodstream. It also makes the user vulnerable to electrical currents. It is quite heavy due to high density of crystal-like material. Radiation output is lowest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_name">
		<text>Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_descr">
		<text>A relatively rare artifact forming in chemical areas, Kolobok is highly valued for its ability to heal most kinds of wounds and stop bleeding in a matter of minutes. For unknown reasons, scientists are spreading rumors among stalkers that the artifact modifies bearer's genetic code, which is unproven and should be regarded as conscious attempt at monopolizing the supply of the artifact by the scientific community. This does not, however, mean that it is completely harmless. One drawback of this artifact is the fact that it will increase electrical conductivity, so it is best to avoid electro anomalies when in possession of the artifact, especially since its negative effects are not balanced with positive ones. It will also reduce energy recovery, which is the result of its sharp needle-like appendages. The needles cause small and quickly healing wounds which bring constant pain and itch, thus reducing stamina. This artifact also weakens protection against psy-emissions produced by anomalies or mutants as well as from heat and acids due to its high flammability. Given its chemical origin, it is also well known for its ability to increase user's protection against toxicity. Lightweight and not too much of a burden to carry around. Radiation output is very high on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_name">
		<text>Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_descr">
		<text>Direct successor to and a superior version of Gravi artifact. As was the case with Gravi, it was scientist Sakharov at Yantar who discovered its unique properties after a massive blowout/emission hit the Zone. Thanks to meticulous research that followed, it was established that this new artifact is produced when three Gravi artifacts interact and get sucked into one another's singularity fields. This phenomenon is extremely rare, due to which the artifact is highly valued. It is rumored within Ukrainian Spetsnaz circles that in the Zone there are agents from the Ministry of Defense of the Russian Federation whose sole objective is acquiring and transporting Goldfish to specialized laboratories located outside of the Zone. The artifact creates a constant gravitational singularity field which affects only its closest vicinity. However, some stalkers have been known to disappear for no apparent reason leaving only a Goldfish behind. The artifact provides exceptional thermal and acid protection. Furthermore, it also forms a protective and almost greasy film around its user which has qualities of strong fire retardant and also protects the user against acid by breaking down elements comprising acids into simpler substances. It is extremely heavy and it is not recommended to use it on long excursions into the Zone, especially for extended periods of time. Radiation output is highest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_name">
		<text>Goldfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_descr">
		<text>Gravi is formed from metallic substances exposed to prolonged gravitation. This makes it capable of sustaining a gravitational field, which causes it to have various properties, among others increasing weight of all objects in its close proximity. For a long time, the artifact was a mystery, and it was scientist Sakharov at Yantar who first discovered that Gravi creates a minute singularity field of gravitational nature, the phenomenon which occurs in intervals of 30 minutes. This artifact may yield beneficial results in medicine or warfare if the mechanism behind its functioning is harnessed for the purposes of science. Suffice it to say, its positive properties completely outweigh its negative aspects. Namely, it increases weight of objects as a result of gravitational field and emits lethal doses of radiation. On the other hand, it will protect the user from harmful effects of fire anomalies found throughout the Zone and from acids of chemical/toxic anomalies. However, instead of absorbing deadly chemicals and toxins, Gravi causes chemical compounds to be broken down to simpler substances thanks to its singularity field. As noted above, it is extremely heavy and it is not recommended to use it on long excursions into the Zone, especially for extended periods of time. Radiation output is very high on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_name">
		<text>Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_descr">
		<text>Also colloquially known as "Radioactive Snowflake". At first glance, this artifact resembles a white Kolobok. Some claim that it actually is a form of Kolobok as it greatly increases resistance to electric currents by creating its own electric field and absorbing electricity that passes through user's body. Thanks to its unique properties, the artifact can significantly increase the bearer's muscle tone, thus greatly improving stamina recovery. Due to its high radioactivity, stalkers in possession of it are sometimes jokingly referred to as "Radioactive Snowflakes". When faced with the decision whether to carry it on the belt during a mission, you have to carefully weigh its pros and cons: does it pay to have greater endurance and high protection against electricity at the cost of being constantly exposed to its deadly radiation? Even if you are determined to take it with you, it should be noted that it is not to be used on long excursions to the Zone. Its usefulness in a fight is also debatable as it increases bleeding rate and prevents wounds from closing due to its very sharp appendages which sting the user and irritate the skin. It is, however, as light as a snowflake and very easy to carry around. Radiation output is highest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_name">
		<text>Snowflake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_medusa_descr">
		<text>This gravitational artifact attracts and absorbs toxic/chemical particles, reducing the effects of toxic poisoning on the body. Very common in the Zone and unofficially used outside the Zone for treating people who have been exposed to hazardous or deadly chemical and toxic agents. This artifact is quite heavy as the gravitational field seems to increase mass. It will slightly protect its user against extreme heat and acids produced respectively by fire and chemical anomalies. Radiation output is lowest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_medusa_name">
		<text>Jellyfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_descr">
		<text>This artifact has soft, porous, skin-like texture and is said to be able to compress. It resembles and acts like a sponge in this regard, but reveals its special characteristics only when exposed to certain external conditions. Firstly, when in the closest proximity of heat source it emits odor of burning flesh. Prolonged exposure may enhance its flammability and cause it to ignite. While this phenomenon leaves the artifact undamaged, it can cause objects in its vicinity to heat up and in extreme cases to ignite along with the artifact. For this reason, it is safe to conclude that it absorbs heat and is able to convey it to other objects. Secondly, to carry the sponge metaphor further, the pores on its surface are known to absorb small amounts of toxicity from environment. Thirdly, the artifact slightly amplifies the damaging effects of psy-fields to living organisms by absorbing psy energy and emitting it at a small rate. Fourthly, Meat Chunk is also known to be a conductor of electricity much like the skin of a living creature. Certain sources within stalker community indicate further that it makes one feel physically drained when used for even short periods of time. Fifthly, probably the most beneficial feature of this artifact is its ability to slowly close up wounds and heal damaged tissues. Radiation output is lowest on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_name">
		<text>Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_descr">
		<text>This glowing artifact can generate a locally directed gravity field which increases its mass. For this reason, Nightstar is extremely heavy. It provides protection against acids as well as heat. Due to its beautiful inner core it is highly sought after by jewelers all over the world, however it is best to proceed with caution as unskilled treatment can cause the artifact to explode with power sufficient to level a small building. It is thus highly advised to perform the polishing by means of specialized machinery, which minimizes the probability of explosion. Moreover, only the outer core of the artifact emits radiation. Nightstar will also absorb toxic and chemical agents from the environment, which makes it a valuable artifact for artifact hunters, although the amount of toxicity absorbed is negligible. It is, however, relatively cheap and even stalkers with pretty tight budgets can afford it if opportunity to buy it arises. Radiation output is low on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_name">
		<text>Nightstar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_descr">
		<text>Soul is a unique organic artifact with properties just as unique - it secretes slimy goo that dramatically increases recovery rate of wounds. Thanks to its reasonable price and attractive appearance, this artifact is a valuable collector's item. Because of its organic nature, Soul is highly flammable and should not be carried near a campfire or most heat sources. It is known to spontaneously combust when exposed to temperature exceeding 60∞C. The artifact provides a high level of toxic and chemical protection by absorbing chemical agents. It then uses them as basis for producing its gooey substance which, when applied to wounds, soothes the pain and speeds up healing process. On the other hand, Soul amplifies the effects of psy-waves and increases the damage of electricity to one's body. It is also known to drain power from its user. The artifact does not have high density and thus is not very heavy. Radiation output is low on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_name">
		<text>Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_descr">
		<text>This bizarrely-shaped artifact appears in places with increased gravitational activity. Acting as a kind of sponge that absorbs chemical and toxic elements, this artifact provides protection from external toxic agents as well as from chemical particles that have already made their way into the body. Although it appears almost organic, it is actually more similar to coral. Due to its non-organic nature, it is nonflammable. It provides protection against acids as well as heat. There is no particular faction that takes great interest in it, so it is mostly sold to scientists who study and experiment on the artifact in order to find the use for it. It has high density and is thus extremely heavy. Radiation output is low on the artifact radiation scale.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_name">
		<text>Wrenched</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass">
		<text>Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_descr">
		<text>A rare artifact - it's been several years since one was found. The artifact can locate gaps in anomaly fields. It is believed that it can help one traverse the most complex anomaly fields completely unharmed. However, very few know how to handle it properly.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_oasis_heart">
		<text>Heart of the Oasis</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_oasis_heart_descr">
		<text>This artifact was found at the center of the legendary Oasis. It appears that the Heart is a crystallized plant, which has acquired the healing properties of the Oasis. Unlike the Oasis itself, however, this artifact is extremely radioactive.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] highly valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_name">
		<text>Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_descr">
		<text>Formed by the "Fruit punch" anomaly. The negative qualities of this artefact are compensated by the fact that it heightens the coagulation quality of blood. It's not often that one runs into such an artefact, and they pay well for it too.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_name">
		<text>Mica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_descr">
		<text>Anomaly "Fruit punch" is able to create such an artefact at the rarest, most extreme collection of physical conditions. The result is a semi-transparent, hard object. A rare and expensive artefact.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_name">
		<text>Pellicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_descr">
		<text>This artefact is so rare that many researchers can't even imagine that such a substance can exist in a natural setting. Emits acidic chemical components.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thorn_name">
		<text>Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thorn_descr">
		<text>The result of the interaction between the anomaly Burnt Fuzz and the body of a careless stalker. The Thorn artefact pokes the body of its owner, no matter what. But it also helps clean the body of radionuclide. Quite widespread and cheap.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_name">
		<text>Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_descr">
		<text>Crystallizes in the anomaly Burnt Fuzz. Naturally takes out the radiation from the organism. That is, through the ears along with some amount of blood. Blood loss is possible also through over openings. Widespread and quite effective, which is the cause for the stable price in the artefact market.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_name">
		<text>Urchin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_descr">
		<text>The anomaly Burnt Fuzz very rarely gives rise to this artefact. Raise the blood pressure and so, the body gets rid of a large amount of red blood cells. But along with them the stored radiation leaves the body as well. In his fundamental work titled "Ionization and polarization of the components of rare artefacts", Sakharov noted that the content of this formation has a critical stability, and it's not realistic to create such an artefact in lab conditions in the next ten years.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Dead Air -->
	<string id="st_af_slime_descr">
		<text>јртефакт представл€ет собой полупрозрачное желеобразное вещество. ѕосле попадани€ в химическую аномалию живых существ, это вещество окутывает и скрепл€ет их останки, порожда€ впоследствии артефакты Ђ ровь камн€ї, ЂЋомоть м€саї и Ђƒушаї. ѕо данным последних исследований, "слизь" €вл€етс€ ничем иным, как колони€ми неизвестных науке бактерий (условное обозначение U-1), которые питаютс€ производными и останками жертв химических аномалий. ѕри ношении артефакт активно поглощает опасные химические испарени€, защища€ таким образом кожу, дыхательные пути и костюм хоз€ина. ѕорождаетс€ химическими аномали€ми всех видов. Ўироко распространЄн. ƒо сих пор неизвестно, насколько опасны новые бактерии, поэтому артефакты данного вида скупаютс€ учЄными в больших количествах в цел€х их срочного изучени€ в различных Ќ»» за пределами «оны отчуждени€.\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]’ј–ј “≈–»—“» »:\n%c[0,153,225,225] Х %c[0,140,140,140] высока€ ценность</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slime_name">
		<text>Ђ—лизьї</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thing_descr">
		<text>Ingot is a common name for artifacts of gravitational nature, which are small pieces of old rusty metal with various abnormal properties. Such properties can be summarized by reduction the weight of backpacks. All anomalies of the gravitational type can generate it. Usually found in radioactive waste landfill and, as a result, it's considerably radioactive. Scientific organizations are interested in the artifact.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thing_name">
		<text>Ingot</text>
	</string>
	<!-- doubled
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_descr">
		<text>ѕолупрозрачное аморфное образование, иногда генерирующее маленькие молнии-искры. ѕри ношении Ђподстегиваетї организм, повыша€ выносливость владельца за счЄт своей энергии. ѕри длительном использовани тер€ет зар€д и Ђумираетї. ќбнаружить можно р€дом с аномали€ми электрического типа. –аспространение повсеместное. »нтерес к артефакту про€вл€ют научные организации и коллекционеры.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_name">
		<text>Ђ»скровикї</text>
	</string>
	 -->
	<string id="st_af_drop_descr">
		<text>Tear-like shade artefact compound with a glossy surface. This artifact is formed in "Burner" anomaly at high temperatures. With this artifact, you can "burn" an open wound without doing harm to health. It showed side effects in form of causing fatigue to the body. With frequent use, it "cools" down and becomes unusable. scientific organizations and military have shown interest in this artifact.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,225,225] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_drop_name">
		<text>Droplet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_surge_name">
		<text>Surge regenerator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_surge_descr">
		<text>A small albeit advanced device that absorbs electrical energy from its closest surroundings. It serves as a protection of sorts as it limits the amount of electricity that comes into direct contact with the body by either blocking it or by shorting it to ground. As it is in fact a very sophisticated resistor circuit, the Surge Suppressor greatly increases electrical resistance of the body. The result is that the user is hit by a significantly lower voltage and is able to survive outbursts which would normally be lethal. It is thus of vital importance to have a surge suppressor on your belt when in proximity of electrical anomalies and other sources of electricity in the Zone. As with all metal objects, it can be used as a source of repair material as long as one has appropriate tools and enough skill.\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING:\n \n%c[default]It should be noted that this module won't be able to work properly or provide the required protection if your suit does not meet the requirements of having minimum protection against anomalous activities and abnormal fields.\n \n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+8%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_frames_name">
		<text>Aluminum frames</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_frames_descr">
		<text>Instead of simply carrying a backpack secured by a pair of shoulder straps, one can attach it to the suit by means of aluminum frames, which optimizes your carrying capabilities. The frames are made of aluminum which is the material of choice due to its light weight, and some external elements are made of plastic in order to attain desired flexibility while sprinting. The whole construction is equipped with a system of straps and webbing to provide a high degree of adjustability. This quality design allows the shoulder straps to be adjusted up or down so as to make wearing a backpack comfortable regardless of one's torso size. Single set of frames replaces only the main framework of your backpack, but it's possible to use more sets to further improve your carrying capabilities. Although the system is built of light aluminum, some parts can still prove useful for minor outfit repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+6%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_grid_name">
		<text>Titanium grid</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_grid_descr">
		<text>Instead of simply carrying a backpack secured by a pair of shoulder straps, one can attach it to the suit by means of titanium grid, which optimizes your carrying capabilities. The grid is made of titanium which is the material of choice due to its light weight and high durability, and some external elements are made of plastic in order to attain desired flexibility while sprinting. The whole construction is equipped with a system of straps and webbing to provide a high degree of adjustability. This quality design allows the shoulder straps to be adjusted up or down so as to make wearing a backpack comfortable regardless of one's torso size. A single grid replaces only the main framework of your backpack, but it's possible to use more grids to further improve your carrying capabilities. Grids are created from very high quality titanium, thus disassembled grid can be used as an effective combat outfit or helmet repair supplement.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high quality\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+10%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_freon_name">
		<text>Freon emission module</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_freon_descr">
		<text>The freon emission module is designed to maintain a constant temperature around the body at the level of 24 degrees Celsius. It is thus extremely useful in order to minimize the effects of extreme heat in situations requiring additional protection. It emits a thick layer of freon-cooled air particles which produce a miniscule vacuum absorbing any excess heat and slightly decreasing the temperature around the user. Another feature of the freon emission module is its ability to resist electricity to a moderate extent.\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING:\n \n%c[default]It should be noted that this module won't be able to work properly or provide the required protection if your suit does not meet the requirements of having minimum protection against anomalous activities and abnormal fields.\n \n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cooler_name">
		<text>Body cooler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cooler_descr">
		<text>The body cooler is an electric module designed to maintain a constant temperature around the body at the level of 15 degrees Celsius. It is thus extremely useful in order to minimize the effects of extreme heat in situations requiring additional protection. It emits quick electrical impulses which produce a miniscule vacuum absorbing any excess heat and slightly decreasing the temperature around the user. It does not require water to function. Another feature of the body cooler is its ability to resist electricity to a moderate extent. In case of disassembly of the unit using a toolkit, the metal casing can be reused as outfit repair material.\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING:\n \n%c[default]It should be noted that this module won't be able to work properly or provide the required protection if your suit does not meet the requirements of having minimum protection against anomalous activities and abnormal fields.\n \n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high quality\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+8%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kevlar_name">
		<text>Kevlar body plates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kevlar_descr">
		<text>Kevlar plates are widely known for their protective capabilities, and are highly valued because of this feature. They perform a wide variety of functions, the most important of which is absorbing the impact of firearm projectiles on the front and the back of the torso. They constitute a lightweight alternative to heavy steel plates. Additionally, any type of armor plating also helps maintain suits in good condition, preventing degradation through wear and tear. Used by military units the world over.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+12%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ironplate_name">
		<text>Iron plate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ironplate_descr"> <!-- revision -->
		<text>Homemade iron plates are very popular among rookies as a cheap alternative to body armor. Such plates cannot stop pistol bullets efficiently enough, but they can protect against fragments, cuts, bites and other severe mechanical damage. Every plate is a small iron sheet 20 ? 20 cm, wrapped with a rope attachment for wearing under clothing.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low-quality product\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+5%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_plates_name">
		<text>Carbon steel plates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_plates_descr">
		<text>These steel plates are specially crafted, heat treated and shaped for ballistic defeating properties, fitting a wide variety of protective applications. They are designed to withstand smaller ballistic impacts on the front and the back of the torso. This protection, however, comes at a price as the thick steel plates are very heavy, thus limiting freedom of movement. Additionally, any type of armor plating also helps maintain suits in good condition, preventing degradation through wear and tear. Used extensively by Spetsnaz forces.\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING:\n \n%c[default]Steel is a conductor and its proximity to the skin makes the body more vulnerable to electricity. For this reason, it is suggested to proceed with caution when near electrical anomalies or other sources of electricity.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] single layer of steel plate\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+20%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_camelbak_name">
		<text>Camelbak</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_camelbak_descr">
		<text>Borrowing its name from the myth that camels store water in their humps, camelbak is a pack worn on the back or around the waist of the user, containing a bladder that is filled with water to keep one hydrated. Flexible tube with a mouthpiece facilitates use even in most pressing situations. This model is camouflaged and integrated in the suit to protect the system from damage from any source, be it combat or anomaly. Because the container is made of a high-quality textile, experienced stalkers sometimes re-use scrapped camelbacks for quality materials to patch their field outfits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+6%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_iam_descr">
		<text>The Improvised Application Module (IAM) filters a small amount of radiation particles emitted from artefacts. This mechanical metal pouch is the cheapest device that allows the user to harness the power of less potent artefacts. Artefact filter is composed of multiple layers made primarily of lead which shield from radiation. A low-cost alternative to the more reliable AAC and AAM. In case of emergency or if no longer needed, the module can be utilized as a source of quality metal for use in outfit or helmet repairs. Currently unusable. To attach it to the belt, you have to put an artefact inside. The artefact will retain its characteristics with the exception of reduced radiation output.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] artefact storage device\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] maximum capacity:%c[0,170,170,170] 1\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] radiation intensity reduction:%c[0,170,170,170] 270 mSv / min\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] state:%c[0,170,170,170] empty\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+6%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_aac_descr">
		<text>The Artefact Application Container (AAC) filters a moderate amount of radiation particles emitted from artefacts. This mechanical aluminum container is the most cost-efficient and thus the most popular way of handling artefacts as it allows the user to harness the power of more potent artefacts. Artefact filter is composed of multiple layers made primarily of lead, with one layer of thorium which has strong radiation shielding properties. This device has been manufactured by scientists residing in military bunkers around the Zone. In case of emergency or if no longer needed, the module can be utilized as a source of quality metal for use in outfit or helmet repairs. Currently unusable. To attach it to the belt, you have to put an artefact inside. The artefact will retain its characteristics with the exception of reduced radiation output.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low UPD consumption\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] artefact storage device\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] maximum capacity:%c[0,170,170,170] 1\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] radiation intensity reduction:%c[0,170,170,170] 450 mSv / min\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] state:%c[0,170,170,170] empty\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+10%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_aam_descr">
		<text>The Artefact Application Module (AAM) filters a significant amount of radiation particles emitted from artefacts. This advanced mechanical module is the most effective way of harnessing the power of most potent artefacts. Artefact filter is composed of numerous layers made of nano-carbon. It is hence lightweight and has strongest radiation shielding properties of all devices. Regarded as a symbol of affluence in the Zone. Most commonly used by the scientists to minimize the harmful effects of artefacts. Designed and manufactured in Ukraine by a government institute which provides equipment for the scientists residing in the Zone of Alienation. In case of emergency or if no longer needed, the module can be utilized as a source of quality metal for use in outfit or helmet repairs. Currently unusable. To attach it to the belt, you have to put an artefact inside. The artefact will retain its characteristics with the exception of reduced radiation output.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high quality\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low UPD consumption\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] artefact storage device\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] maximum capacity:%c[0,170,170,170] 1\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] radiation intensity reduction:%c[0,170,170,170] 840 mSv / min\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] state:%c[0,170,170,170] empty\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+14%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lead_box_descr">
		<text>The lead-lined metal container (LLMC) is a simple metal box with thick walls and foam inserts as well as a heavy lid with pressure-sealing mechanism. Specifically designed for transporting radioactive materials, in the Zone LLMC is most commonly employed as artefact storage and transportation device. It stops all radiation from leaking, thus ensuring safety of the user when in possession of artefacts. However, the device cannot be attached to the belt, which means that both positive and negative properties of artefacts won't apply. The contents can be manipulated with an artefact handling tool.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] artefact storage device\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] maximum capacity:%c[0,170,170,170] 1\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] state:%c[0,170,170,170] empty\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING:\n \n%c[default]You have to remove artefacts from the container prior to selling them..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lead_box_closed_name">
		<text>LLMC (full)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lead_box_closed_descr">
		<text>The lead-lined metal container (LLMC) is a simple metal box with thick walls and foam inserts as well as a heavy lid with pressure-sealing mechanism. Specifically designed for transporting radioactive materials, in the Zone LLMC is most commonly employed as artefact storage and transportation device. It stops all radiation from leaking, thus ensuring safety of the user when in possession of artefacts. However, the device cannot be attached to the belt, which means that both positive and negative properties of artefacts won't apply. The contents can be manipulated with an artefact handling tool.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] artefact storage device\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] maximum capacity:%c[0,170,170,170] 1\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] state:%c[0,170,170,170] full\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING:\n \n%c[default]You have to remove artefacts from the container prior to selling them..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_flesh_name">
		<text>Flesh hide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_flesh_descr">
		<text>Hide removed from a breed of mutated pigs commonly referred to as fleshes. Its heavy weight (its main drawback) results from a thick layer of fat underneath the relatively soft and shallow skin. It offers low physical protection, but can be used only for minor repairs as the layer of fat is useless for the purposes of armor maintenance and must be cut off, leaving only a small patch of shallow skin tissue.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_boar_name">
		<text>Boar hide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_boar_descr">
		<text>A hide almost fully covered with a thick layer of fur, removed from one of wild boars found commonly in the Zone. The mutants themselves are quite resistant to damage and can take considerable punishment, and the reason for this is simple: big muscle mass and almost unbreakable bones. The skin, on the other hand, is quite thin (most probably to provide the creature with effective means of thermal regulation), making it a rather poor choice for armor enhancement. The fur in turn makes the hide a relatively potent thermal insulator. Can also be used for light repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_bloodsucker_name">
		<text>Bloodsucker skin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_bloodsucker_descr">
		<text>Bloodsuckers as a species evolved from humans and this affinity can still be seen in the texture of their skin. What is most characteristic, the skin is very soft and pleasant in touch, almost like the skin of a child. This applies, however, only to the outer layer - underneath, bloodsuckers boast well developed muscles which can be utilized to form a coat of sorts with considerable damage reducing potential, especially in regard to melee attacks. This makes bloodsucker skin a popular choice among experienced hunters who also wear it as a sign of their proficiency. The most unique property it holds is the high resistance to chemical substances and toxic wastes. The reason is that bloodsuckers often live in places with active chemical exposure (underground areas of former research laboratories for example). Bloodsuckers have adapted to aggressive environment.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+6%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_burer_name">
		<text>Burer skin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_burer_descr">
		<text>Skinning a burer is a lot like skinning a twisted dwarf. Add to it an almost unbearable stench of bad eggs and you get the idea why stalkers consider this quite a feat. Reports indicate that whereas the skin offers relatively low physical protection, but it can be used to provide good protection against thermal anomalies. Furthermore, due to the fact that burers are relatively rarely encountered in the Zone, the skin has significant research potential, making it a valuable trading commodity for the scientists.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] extraordinary scientific specimen\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_chimera_name">
		<text>Chimera hide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_chimera_descr">
		<text>Chimera, being one of the most dangerous mutants in the Zone, is not only a significant threat, but can also be regarded as a viable source of wealth. All parts that can be taken from chimera's corpse can be sold for a large amount of money, but it is the skin that is one of the most valued scientific specimens as well as one of the best armor enhancements available in the Exclusion Zone. It offers very good protection properties and, even more importantly, is relatively light-weight thanks to which it does not limit mobility. However, its most unique feature is that organic fibers found in the skin act as very effective electrical conductors. This fact to a large degree confirms reports of recon units (especially those scouting around the AMK Industrial Complex) concerning sightings of chimeras surrounded in what looked like an electrical anomaly, producing discharges on contact with any hostile living organism. Unfortunately, no unit was able to make it back, so there is no evidence confirming the existence of such a creature.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] extraordinary scientific specimen\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+8%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_pseudogiant_name">
		<text>Pseudogiant hide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_pseudogiant_descr">
		<text>The skin of a pseudogiant in many ways resembles the skin of an elephant. It's thick and hard in touch, its texture is very irregular and full of folds which act as the creature's cooling mechanism. The average thickness of pseudogiant's skin is around 2 cm, which makes it very durable and capable of withstanding significant damage. This is, however, at the cost of increased weight. Since pseudogiants are known to often live in areas of high toxicity and radioactivity, the hide naturally adapted to such conditions, which further increases its usefulness. It can also be used to patch even the heaviest of outfits but this process requires the most durable and expensive tools available. It is valued not only for its practical qualities, but can also serve as a prestigious hunting trophy and a rare specimen for the scientists in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] extraordinary scientific specimen\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+9%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_controller_name">
		<text>Controller scalp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_controller_descr">
		<text>As is the case with other humanoid mutants, it's quite an emotional challenge to scalp a controller and it proves to be even more difficult as the face of a controller retains certain characteristics of the person it once was. Confidential sources within the military also revealed that fingerprints of the person who turned into a controller can sometimes be found in the database. Recent analysis shows that not only the hand of the controller is capable of producing psy waves - the whole body is the source of emissions. For this reason, the scalp - when prepared properly - has the ability to absorb and filter psy energy, but for this effect to take place it is necessary to cover your head with multiple scalps. The skin is also electrically conductive. As regards its physical properties, it is light and can only be used for minor outfit repairs. As is the case with all humanoid psy creatures, the skin of a controller is electrically conductive.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] extraordinary scientific specimen\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_pseudodog_name">
		<text>Pseudodog fur</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_pseudodog_descr">
		<text>Densely covered with short and stiff fur, the pelt of pseudodog remains one of the most useful, widespread and versatile mutant pelts available in the Zone. It can be easily attached to armor with even lightest of tools, and yet it's quite durable, which makes it suitable for medium-grade outfit repairs. When used as a blanket, it offers considerable protection against radiation exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+5%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_psy_dog_name">
		<text>Psy-dog fur</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hide_psy_dog_descr">
		<text>The fur of a psy dog is undoubtedly one of the most beautiful and rare clothing materials in the world. Usually snow white or grey, it is in great demand and can be sold for a hefty sum of money. It's probably made its way into fashion industry thanks to smugglers some of whom have recently turned to hunting mutants. For those in the Zone, it can serve as a blanket, especially during cold nights. It offers protection against radiation exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelt\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] effectiveness of mult. units is stackable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+7%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_powder_poltergeist">
		<text>'Diamond powder'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_powder_poltergeist_descr">
		<text>"Diamond powder" is a common name given to crystal-like substance found sometimes in the belly of all species of psy creatures. It is not known what metabolic processes lead to its emergence and for this reason scientists are eager to pay large sums of money to lay their hands on it. Practical use is limited but some stalkers are known to sprinkle their most cherished hunting knives with it as it makes sharpening significantly easier. It also makes blades look shiny and well-kept.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] psy mutant metabolism product\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] very rare scientific specimen\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] blade sharpening (+28%)</text>
	</string>





	<string id="st_af_medusa_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Jellyfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Nightstar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Wrenched</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Goldfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Flame</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blood_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Stone Blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Bubble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Firefly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Sparkler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Moonlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Shell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Snowflake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_oasis_heart_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Heart of the Oasis</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_b1_half_artifact_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Altered Insulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_quest_b14_twisted_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Altered Wheel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thing_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Ingot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slime_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Slime</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Mica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Pellicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thorn_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Urchin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_drop_af_iam_name">
		<text>IAM w/ Droplet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_medusa_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Jellyfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Nightstar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Wrenched</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Goldfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Flame</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blood_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Stone Blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Bubble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Firefly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Sparkler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Moonlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Shell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Snowflake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_oasis_heart_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Heart of the Oasis</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_b1_half_artifact_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Altered Insulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_quest_b14_twisted_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Altered Wheel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thing_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Ingot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slime_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Slime</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Mica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Pellicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thorn_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Urchin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_drop_af_aac_name">
		<text>AAC w/ Droplet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_medusa_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Jellyfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Nightstar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Wrenched</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Goldfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Flame</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blood_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Stone Blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Bubble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Firefly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Sparkler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Moonlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Shell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Snowflake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_oasis_heart_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Heart of the Oasis</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_b1_half_artifact_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Altered Insulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_quest_b14_twisted_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Altered Wheel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thing_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Ingot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slime_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Slime</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Mica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Pellicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thorn_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Urchin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_drop_af_aam_name">
		<text>AAM w/ Droplet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_medusa_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Jellyfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Nightstar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Wrenched</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Goldfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Flame</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blood_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Stone Blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Bubble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Firefly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Sparkler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Moonlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Shell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Snowflake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_oasis_heart_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Heart of the Oasis</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_b1_half_artifact_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Altered Insulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_quest_b14_twisted_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Altered Wheel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thing_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Ingot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slime_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Slime</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Mica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Pellicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thorn_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Urchin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_drop_lead_box_name">
		<text>LLMC w/ Droplet</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
