<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_antirad">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_descr">
		<text>Mexaminum radiation protection drugs are common in the Zone. When used, this drug induces contraction of peripheral blood vessels and oxygen deprivation, which serve to treat and prevent radiation exposure. The drug does not have severe side effects, although isolated cases of mild nausea, dizziness, cramps and stomach pain have been reported.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage_descr">
		<text>A normal elastic bandage used to stop bleeding and prevent infection of wounds. For regular bleeding, carefully apply the bandage to the wound. For arterial bleeding, urgently tie the bandage around the affected area.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] first-aid item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (adhesive plaster)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_descr">
		<text>The Russian-made BPOs 10x42 binoculars (the letter S in the title indicates the presence of a rangefinder grid) is suitable for observing distant areas during travelling and hunting. The binoculars are produced by the Kazan Optical-Mechanical Plant, and, based on the standard Porro prism system, provide good resolution within the entire field of view. The imaging of the binoculars is bright and clean without distortion and with preservation of natural colors.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_name">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread_descr">
		<text>A roll of fresh bread of average quality. It mainly enters the Zone through the military, who happily exchange provisions for loot and supplies. It is a rare delicacy in the Zone, like any other qualitative food.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_breadold">
		<text>Old bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_breadold_descr">
		<text>An old piece of bread that has long since dried. It is partially covered by mold. Consumption is difficult but possible.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_porn">
		<text>Russian PLAYBOY</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_porn_descr">
		<text>100-pages worth of prime nude Russian girls. Probably the best way to travel to a better place, at least mentally. Westerners often joke about it saying СFrom Russia with loveТ, whereas practiced Zoners say it's hot indeed when put in a stove.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon lubrication and cleaning (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_joint">
		<text>Cannabis joint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_joint_descr">
		<text>A joint calms you and lets you relax for a little while. Via a distinct sedative effect, it briefly СdisconnectsТ and СrestartsТ the brain, allowing it to stay in healthy condition and avoid irreversible damaging consequences.\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking helps to stabilise your mental condition after any psionic attacks.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong alleviation against psy-damage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigarettes">
		<text>Marlboro cigarettes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigarettes_descr">
		<text>Cigarettes, imported from the West. Someone's already had a few, not a surprise since they're rare in the Zone.\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking helps to stabilise your mental condition after any psionic attacks.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] average alleviation against psy-damage\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_survivalguide">
		<text>Ukrainian Special Forces Survival Guide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_survivalguide_descr">
		<text>A mini-textbook published by the Armed Forces of Ukraine for survival in extreme situations. Contains content useful to all newcomers to the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon lubrication and cleaning (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_protein">
		<text>Chocolate protein bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_protein_descr">
		<text>This bar provides the body with necessary proteins and sugars which give you a welcome boost. Useful on longer trips when you're on the go and need to eat something fast. Such chocolate bars are, however, very rare in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rebirth">
		<text>Unknown drug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rebirth_descr">
		<text>A syringe filled with a substance of unknown contents. The print on the surface indicates recommended use only when faced with life-threatening wounds.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva">
		<text>Can of tuna</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva_descr">
		<text>The best before date at the back of the tin can indicates that you shouldn't expect delicacies.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tushonka">
		<text>Beef tushonka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tushonka_descr">
		<text>Tushonkas are known for their high nutrition value (mostly owing to high fat content) and a relatively good taste. The Chernobyl Exclusion Zone has seen hundreds of types and tastes of tushonkas. In the spring of 2013, СAbakanТ minced-meat brand remains the unquestionable king, and certainly the Zone has seen worse than that.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_rat">
		<text>Fried rat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_rat_descr">
		<text>A well-roasted rat carcass with a crispy crust; the basis of the diet of a novice stalker. Appears appetising, though its taste is like rubber. It is a good choice in conditions of deficiency so as not to die of hunger.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_tushkano">
		<text>Rat skewers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_tushkano_descr">
		<text>2 small skewered tushkanos, grilled and seasoned with salt and chili pepper. The cheapest hot meal available in the Zone. Wrapped in thick brown paper to prevent the fat from dripping.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_dog">
		<text>Dog chops</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_dog_descr">
		<text>A small hot meal of grilled dog chops mixed with garlic, peppers and mushrooms. Served in an old tin box. A cheap alternative to the more popular boar chops.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_pseudodog">
		<text>Pseudodog chops</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_pseudodog_descr">
		<text>A portion of grilled pseudodog meat chops. Good nutrition value due to the thick muscles of the animal.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_flesh">
		<text>Fat bacon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_flesh_descr">
		<text>2 slices of fat and greasy bacon made from mutated pigs commonly known as flesh. Wrapped in thick brown paper to prevent the fat from dripping.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_boar">
		<text>Boar chops</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_boar_descr">
		<text>>A small portion of boar meat, grilled and seasoned with salt and mixed with peppers. The most popular warm meal among stalkers. Wrapped in brown paper.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_bloodsucker">
		<text>Bloodsucker goulash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_bloodsucker_descr">
		<text>A small hot meal made from bloodsucker meat spiced with chilies and mixed with mushrooms. Served in a tin box.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_snork">
		<text>Grilled snork hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_snork_descr">
		<text>Grilled snork hand. Imagining any type of worse food is difficult. It is also worth noting that eating snorks is a true sign of cannibalism.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_chimera">
		<text>The Masculine Meal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_chimera_descr">
		<text> portion of grilled chimera meat, served with mushrooms and spices. An expensive meal, eaten most commonly by veteran stalkers to celebrate accomplishment of difficult missions.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector0">
		<text>Homemade detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector0_descr">
		<text>A very simple home-made device. It was assembled from the most common parts by skilled craftsmen amongst the stalker community, most of which are available in any radio receiver. Powered by a built-in battery. Reacts to the presence of artefacts with distinct sounds. Unfortunately, the chance of receiving the frequencies of radio stations available in the Zone has been lost.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1">
		<text>Echo detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1_descr">
		<text>This dated anomalous activity detector produces an alarm signal when anomalous particles enter a special chamber as you approach an anomaly. It can also register the presence of artifacts and measure the distance to the nearest one. The distance is indicated by the frequency of the sound the detector emits. To switch to artifact search mode, open the device's front cover. Due to its simple design, Echo can only be used to locate the most common artifacts.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low UPD consumption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2">
		<text>Bear detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3">
		<text>Veles detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3_descr">
		<text>A next generation scientific detection scanner. Thanks to three modernized detection chambers, the position of artifacts is shown on a special display screen. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artifact search mode, open the front LED display. When in search mode, the detector is capable of locating all artifacts known to science.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high UPD consumption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4">
		<text>Svarog detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4_descr">
		<text>A prototype of an expanded functionality anomalous frequency scanner. This device comes with a program used to identify static areas of anomalous activity stored in its database, while retaining the ability to locate artifacts. The position of anomalous areas and artifacts is displayed on a special screen. The artifact search mode, which can be activated by opening the front LED display, has been modified to detect anomalous formations currently unknown to science. With a little luck, you can also salvage the batteries powering the device.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high UPD consumption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_descr">
		<text>A standard head-mounted flashlight in fully working order. Useful for stalkers who find themselves out and about after dark, but may attract trouble if used unwisely.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] moderate UPD consumption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_name">
		<text>Head lamp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
		<text>Anabiotics</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_antidot">
		<text>Antidote</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_antidot_descr">
		<text>The IP2 antitoxin is a complex drug comprising several antidotes, including metoclopramidum, pyridoxine, thiamine, riboxin and other pharmaceuticals. The drug is used to inject a range of antibiotics to neutralize natural poisons, together with synthetic poison absorbers, into the bloodstream. IP2 is not particularly popular in the Zone as most stalkers rely on a gas mask and a protective suit. However, there are still those who have a few units of this antidote stashed for emergency situations. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] eliminates toxins in the body\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_booster">
		<text>Hercules</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant">
		<text>Vinca</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
		<text>Tablets containing a complex of the most necessary vitamins for a human being, primarily to maintain immunity. When consuming the meat of mutants, it is strongly recommended to take a tablet after each meal.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] prolonged body recovery time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
		<text>Psy-block</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
		<text>A drug that blocks avalanche-like nerve impulses. Consumption induces short-term loss of all emotion. Used exclusively in the Zone to counteract the effects of anomalous psy-fields. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight side effects\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight sleepiness increase</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector">
		<text>Radioprotectant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_water_drink">
		<text>Sparkling water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_water_drink_descr">
		<text>Sparkling water for thirsty stalkers. It has an exhilarating effect when you're tired.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mild alcohol sobering effect\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drink_crow">
		<text>СThe BeakТ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drink_crow_descr">
		<text>СThe BeakТ is a powerful mixture of Zone-produced vodka and the pulverized beak of a black crow. The rumour has it that such beaks contain a form of enriched protein that cleanses moderate amounts of radiation from the body. Some even say that drinking Сthe BeakТ makes you feel like you have wings for a few seconds. On the downside, however, the taste itself is awful.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong, low quality alcohol\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight sleepiness decrease</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink">
		<text>Energy drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_descr">
		<text>Often used by stalkers on long trips due to its exhilarating effect when you're tired. The drink also sobers you up a bit if you're drunk as well as induces the release of adrenaline into the bloodstream. To avoid an overdose, it is recommended not to abuse drinking.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] сильное уменьшение сонливости</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_descr">
		<text>Guitar is a string instrument widely used by stalkers of all factions throughout the Zone in order to raise spirits and fraternize. Stalkers can often be seen playing the guitar in camps, outposts or other places of relative safety - usually by the fire.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_name">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa">
		<text>Pack of old meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa_descr">
		<text>A package containing a meal of old bread and some smelly meat of unknown origin wrapped in brown paper. The look and smell suggest that some of it is mouldy.\n \n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unhealthy food\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low quality</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit">
		<text>First-aid kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_descr">
		<text>A standard single-use medical kit. Handy for treating injuries, wounds, chemical and thermal burns and various types of poisoning.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slow usage (field kit)\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army">
		<text>Army medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army_descr">
		<text>A specialized medical kit for providing first aid to combat casualties. The kit includes blood coagulants based on menadione, painkillers, antibiotics and immunostimulants, as well as a kit for removing bullets and fragments from the body. This medkit is issued primarily to army personnel such as Spetsnaz units venturing deep into the Zone and is popular among Duty forces.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slow usage (field kit)\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science">
		<text>Scientific medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science_descr">
		<text>A specialized medical kit for providing first aid to combat casualties. The kit includes blood coagulants based on menadione, painkillers, antibiotics and immunostimulants, as well as a kit for removing bullets and fragments from the body. This medkit is issued primarily to army personnel such as Spetsnaz units venturing deep into the Zone and is popular among Duty forces.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slow usage (field kit)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] eliminates toxins in the body\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] no side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glucose_s">
		<text>Small glucose shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glucose_s_descr">
		<text>Glucose shots are used in cases of severe diabetic hypoglycemia, but can also be employed as a stimulant. Instant induction of carbohydrates entails a rapid boost of energy, thus allowing the user to undertake increased physical effort and withstand stress.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight sleepiness decrease</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glucose">
		<text>Large glucose shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glucose_descr">
		<text>Glucose shots are used in cases of severe diabetic hypoglycemia, but can also be employed as a stimulant. Instant induction of carbohydrates entails a rapid boost of energy, thus allowing the user to undertake increased physical effort and withstand stress. Contains a large dose of the drug.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] moderate sleepiness decrease</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_impro">
		<text>Improvised stimpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_impro_descr">
		<text>Improvised stimpacks are popular among novice Zoners as they are easy to obtain and inexpensive; though their strong side effects, which affect many users, are nothing to scoff at. Produced in the Zone from commonly available ingredients, without proper equipment and purification. This is the cause of many side effects which include headache, paraesthesia, and considerable increase in nutrition demand. Injected in the thigh.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] moderate body recovery time\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] very strong side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_military">
		<text>Military stimpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_military_descr">
		<text>Military stims constitute a part of standard-issue soldier equipment for field operations in the Zone. Easily available on the market and can be acquired for a moderate price. Popular among experienced Zoners. They are significantly more potent and faster working than their improvised counterparts, which makes them perfect for use in life-threatening situations. Produced from raw agents of high density which can take their toll on the body. Side effects include shock, extreme dizziness and increased hunger.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast body recovery time\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_scientic">
		<text>Scientific stimpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_scientic_descr">
		<text>It is produced by the same chemical department, which developed the famous SEVA suit. This stimpack is the most powerful health stabilizer available in the Zone. The best and highest quality ingredients, as well as the improved formula, allow to restore health almost instantly, neutralize all the toxins accumulated in the body, and reduce the feeling of hunger.  There are no side effects. It is very expensive, hence only few very lucky stalkers got to use it.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast body recovery time\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] eliminates toxins in the body\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high health improvement </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_charcoal">
		<text>Activated carbon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_charcoal_descr">
		<text>A small package of activated carbon which can absorb all sorts of toxins, gases, salts and heavy metals. Recommended to use after eating harmful food, strong medicine or alcohol.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] eliminates toxins in the body\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] health improvement</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_descr">
		<text>A common sight among all stalkers. Contains digital logs and maps of zones, places and anomalies, if you give it to the right trader it's worth a good amount of money\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low UPD consumption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_name">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka">
		<text>"Cossacks" vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka_descr">
		<text>Popular among everyone in the Zone. It goes down well and removes the effects of radiation. Shouldn't be abused however tempting it might be.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong alcohol\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2_descr">
		<text>A last generation anomaly detector. Equipped with a locator of abnormal formations and LED displays for showing the path to the artifact. Other than that it can also show the distance to the artifact. To initiate the artifact search mode, raise the antenna on the front side of the device. Since its the last generation, it has a somewhat outdated list of artifacts.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] average energy consumption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
		<text>An experimental drug developed by Professor Ozersky for scientific research teams working in the Zone. At its core, the drug contains tetrodotoxin, known colloquially as "zombie powder," which causes a complete shutdown of the body's central nervous system that may allow people to survive emissions outside cover. The drug has not undergone clinical or field testing, which puts its effectiveness in doubt and raises the issue of possible side effects.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] causes temporary blackout\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] average sleepiness increase\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bolt">
		<text>Bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_booster_descr">
		<text>The main component of this product is an anabolic androgen, an artificial steroid, the chemical composition of which resembles testosterone. Often used by stalkers during long raids to reduce muscle fatigue. Significantly increases weight-carrying capacity. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight sleepiness decrease</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector_descr">
		<text>B190 Indraline radioprotectant, included in medkits issued to nuclear power plant personnel. Used in the Zone instead of the excessively toxic PC1 cysteamine hydrochloride, repeated use of which often caused death. Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on live tissue. Best consumed before exposure, as effects are not instant, but the drug lasts a long time. Take one capsule at a time.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_harmonica_name">
		<text>Harmonica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_harmonica_descr">
		<text>For blues and prison romance lovers.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_itm_deployable_mgun_name">
		<text>RP-74 "Scorpion"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_deployable_mgun_desc">
		<text>This machine gunfighting system is a portable device with a complex system of two-stage delivery of cartridges directly from the backpack to the weapon with a use of a flexible sleeve. Despite its weight and low accuracy, this weapon found its admirers in the Zone. It is used mainly to fight superior enemy forces in faction wars and cleansing mutant lairs.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_memory_stick_name">
		<text>Memory stick</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosinka_descr">
		<text>A kerosene lamp, not very practical to travel with due to its large size but its a good light source in a camp.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require seasoning</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_batteries">
		<text>Battery pack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_batteries_descr">
		<text>An already used set of batteries, designed for flashlights and PDA's amongst other electronic devices, don't forget to replace these constantly.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] зар€дка +52%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tea">
		<text>Beard's tea</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tea_descr">
		<text>Beard's popular hot tea made from a mixture of sugar, edible dried mushrooms and boiled water that is said to be radiation-free. Stalkers who can afford to buy the drink often take it for long trips in the Zone. It's a good and healthy way to stay on your toes when you're getting tired or when you're out exploring on cold nights.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] мощный отрезвл€ющий эффект\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] moderate sleepiness decrease</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_textile_patch_b">
		<text>Light sheet of fabric</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_textile_patch_b_descr">
		<text>Simple cloth sheet, commonly used both to patch clothing and spread oils and cleaning solvents onto firearm mechanisms. Can be applied by any needle or glue.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair, weapon maintenance (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_textile_patch_m">
		<text>Sheet of tarpaulin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_textile_patch_m_descr">
		<text>Sheet of military-grade textile that can be used for field repairs of clothing and light armor. Valued for its relatively low price and high versatility, this material is commonly used by the Zoners. Medium-grade sewing equipment and advanced glue required for use. It can also be used to improve spread of liquids during weapon maintenance.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair, weapon maintenance (+4%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_textile_patch_e">
		<text>Reinforced canvas sheet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_textile_patch_e_descr">
		<text>Thick textile patch reinforced with kevlar padding. Can be used to repair medium and heavy armors. Large enough to cover multiple damaged areas. High quality sewing kits and adhesives are required to make use of it. Its alternative usage is weapon lubrication and cleaning - due to increased hardness it's able reach even less accessible areas of firearm parts.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair, weapon maintenance (+6%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_steel_wool">
		<text>Steel wool</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_steel_wool_descr">
		<text>Steel wool, also known as wire wool or wire sponge, is a bundle of strands of very fine soft steel filaments. It is used as an abrasive in finishing and repair work for polishing wood or metal objects, cleaning household cookware, and sanding in light painting. Steel wool is made from low-carbon steel (carbon content is low enough to be close to plain iron). It is not made by drawing "steel wool wire" through a tapered die, but rather by a process more like broaching where a heavy steel wire is pulled through a toothed die that removes a thin wire shaving. Bundles of steel wool can be used in precision equipment cleaning and to improve spreading of lubricants and cleaning solvents.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+6%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grease">
		<text>Industrial grease</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grease_descr">
		<text>Grease is a semisolid lubricant. It generally consists of a soap emulsified with mineral or vegetable oil. Greases are applied to mechanisms that cannot be lubricated constantly or where typical lubricating oil would not stay in position. They also act as sealants to prevent ingress of water and incompressible materials. Grease-lubricated bearings have greater frictional characteristics due to their high viscosity.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-quality product\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+6%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sharpening_stones">
		<text>Knife sharpening kit "3:1"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sharpening_stones_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] made for knives\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]If you've got a blunt knife or blade, don't leave them like that, this universal set will help fix things. It has three components: a grinding bar, sharpening tool and a tool for later cleaning the blade.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] рем. комплект\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-quality product\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]10%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]20%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] стальна€ пр€жа %c[0,170,170,170]+5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] чист€щий растворитель %c[0,170,170,170]+3-7%\n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cleaning_kit_p">
		<text>Cleaning Kit "Progress"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cleaning_kit_p_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for 5.7 mm, 7.85 mm, 9 mm, .45 and .357 caliber weaponry\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]A set of brushes made for cleaning weaponry. It is used all around the Zone by any stalker, can be used with a general purpose tools for more detialed cleaning or it can be used with cleaning solutions for more effective grease removal. This kit is suitable for most guns found in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]чистки %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]75%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]5%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] оружейные смазки %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] инструменты дл€ тонкой работы %c[0,170,170,170]+2-5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] чист€щие растворители %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] промышленна€ смазка %c[0,170,170,170]+5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] стальна€ пр€жа %c[0,170,170,170]+5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] алкоголь %c[0,170,170,170]+2-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] животный жир %c[0,170,170,170]+1-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] чиста€ вода %c[0,170,170,170]+1%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cleaning_kit_s">
		<text>Cleaning kit "Aurora A108 / 12"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cleaning_kit_s_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for  12 gauge calibers\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]A special set of brushes for cleaning weaponry. This set is suitable for twelve gauge caliber weapons. Can be used with a general purpose tools for more detialed cleaning or it can be used with cleaning solutions for more effective grease removal.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]чистки %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]75%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]5%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] оружейные смазки %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] инструменты дл€ тонкой работы %c[0,170,170,170]+2-5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] чист€щие растворители %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] промышленна€ смазка %c[0,170,170,170]+5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] стальна€ пр€жа %c[0,170,170,170]+5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] алкоголь %c[0,170,170,170]+2-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] животный жир %c[0,170,170,170]+1-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] чиста€ вода %c[0,170,170,170]+1%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cleaning_kit_r">
		<text>Rifle cleaning kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cleaning_kit_r_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for 5.45, 5.56, 7.62, 7.92, .338, 12.7 and 9x39 weapon calibers\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]A special set of brushes for cleaning weaponry. Can be used with a general purpose tools for more detialed cleaning or it can be used with cleaning solutions for more effective grease removal. This kit is suitable for long and medium caliber weaponry.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]чистки %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]75%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]5%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] оружейные смазки %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] инструменты дл€ тонкой работы %c[0,170,170,170]+2-5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] чист€щие растворители %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] промышленна€ смазка %c[0,170,170,170]+5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] стальна€ пр€жа %c[0,170,170,170]+5%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] алкоголь %c[0,170,170,170]+2-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] животный жир %c[0,170,170,170]+1-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] чиста€ вода %c[0,170,170,170]+1%</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_toolkit_p">
		<text>Pistol toolkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_p_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for 5.7 мм, 7.85мм, 9 мм, .45 and .357 weapon calibers\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]This kit contains tools for the disassembly and reassembly of weaponry. Ideal for eliminating basic faults but it cant do much for completely destroyed parts. This kit can only be used for pistols, but it can be combined with other materials or additional kits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[255,238,153,26]
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]исправлени€ дефектов %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]50%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]15%\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_p_empty">
		<text>Pistol tool set (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_p_empty_descr">
		<text>An empty metal box which used to have tools for disassembling 9 mm, .45 and .357 caliber weapons. Although empty, but can be useful when repairing metal parts of equipment. Not particularly in demand, so it has no real value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+4%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_s">
		<text>Shotgun toolkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_s_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140 suitable for 12 gauge weapon calibers\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]This kit contains tools for the disassembly and reassembly of weaponry. Ideal for eliminating basic faults but it cant do much for completely destroyed parts. This kit can only be used for 12 gauge shotguns. It can also be combined with other materials and additional kits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] технологическое приспособление\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]исправлени€ дефектов %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]50%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]15%\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_s_empty">
		<text>Ќабор инструментов дл€ дробовиков (пустой)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_s_empty_descr">
		<text>An empty metal box which used to have tools for disassembling 12 gauge caliber weapons. Although empty, but can be useful when repairing metal parts of equipment. Not particularly in demand, so it has no real value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+4%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_r">
		<text>Rifle toolkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_r_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for 5.45, 5.56, 7.62, 7.92, .338, 12.7 and 9x39 weapon calibers\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This kit contains tools for the disassembly and reassembly of weaponry. Ideal for eliminating basic faults but it cant do much for completely destroyed parts. This kit can only be used for 12 gauge shotguns. It can also be combined with other materials and addtional kits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]исправлени€ дефектов %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]50%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]15%\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_r_empty">
		<text>Rifle toolkit (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_toolkit_r_empty_descr">
		<text>An empty metal box which used to have tools for disassembling rifles of any caliber. Although empty, but can be useful when repairing metal parts of equipment. Not particularly in demand, so it has no real value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+4%)</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_repair_kit_p">
		<text>Pistol repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_p_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for 5.7 mm, 7.85mm, 9 mm, .45 and .357 weapon calibers\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This kit contains tools and spare parts for disassembling weapons and replacing various parts of its mechanisms. Everything that is necessary for weapon repair is here. It's quite heavy, but required for long trips around the Zone. This kit can only be used for the repair of pistols, but it can also be combined with additional materials or kits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]исправлени€ поломок %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]10%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]25%\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_p_empty">
		<text>Pistol repair kit (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_p_empty_descr">
		<text>An empty metal box which used to have tools for disassembling  9mm, .45 and .357 weapon calibers. Although empty, but can be useful when repairing metal parts of equipment. Not particularly in demand, so it has no real value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+4%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_s">
		<text>Shotgun repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_s_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for 12 gauge weapon calibers\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This kit contains tools and spare parts for disassembling weapons and replacing various parts of its mechanisms. Everything that is necessary for weapon repair is here. It's quite heavy, but required for long trips around the Zone. This kit can only be used for the repair of 12 gauge shotguns, but it can also be combined with additional materials or kits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]исправлени€ поломок %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]10%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]25%\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_s_empty">
		<text>Shotgun repair kit (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_s_empty_descr">
		<text>An empty metal box which used to have tools for disassembling 12 gauge shotgun calibers. Although empty, but can be useful when repairing metal parts of equipment. Not particularly in demand, so it has no real value..\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+4%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_r">
		<text>Rifle repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_r_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] suitable for  5.45, 5.56, 7.62, 7.92, .338, 12.7 and 9x39 weapon calibers\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This kit contains tools for the disassembly and reassembly of weaponry. Ideal for eliminating basic faults but it cant do much for completely destroyed parts. This kit can only be used for rifles of any caliber. It can also be combined with other materials and addtional kits..\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] valuable\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] предназначено дл€ %c[0,170,170,170]исправлени€ поломок %c[0,140,140,140]оружи€\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]10%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]25%\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_r_empty">
		<text>Rifle repair kit (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_r_empty_descr">
		<text>An empty metal box which used to have tools for disassembling all rifle weapon calibers. Although empty, but can be useful when repairing metal parts of equipment. Not particularly in demand, so it has no real value..\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+4%)</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_sewing_kit_b">
		<text>Simple sewing kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sewing_kit_b_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] any equipment and light helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]A simple sewing kit consisting of a thread, several steel needles and scissors. Used for sewing holes from bullets or simple torn patches on equipment, the needles and thread are of poor quality so the kit cannot be used many times.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]85%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]6%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] outfit repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelts (medium) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-6%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sewing_kit_a">
		<text>Universal sewing kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sewing_kit_a_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all equipment and light helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]An improved sewing kit consisting of a higher quality thread, several steel needles and scissors. Used for working with thick and hard materials, including skins of mutants and complex fabrics.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]70%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]9%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] outfit repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional outfit and headgear sets (light) %c[0,170,170,170]+11-32\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelts (medium) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sewing_kit_h">
		<text>Advanced sewing kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sewing_kit_h_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all equipment and light helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]An advanced military sewing kit, its designed to work with the highest quality bulletproof vests and protective plates so it contains a large amount of high quality needles, threads and scissors. It's also capable of sewing together heavy mutant skins. This is the best quality sewing kit within the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]55%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]12%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] outfit repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional outfit and headgear sets (light) %c[0,170,170,170]+11-32\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelts (heavy) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-14%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glue_b">
		<text>Tube of glue "Moment"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glue_b_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all equipment and light helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]The cheapest synthetic glue in the Zone. It's useful for patching up small holes within equipment but its powerless against significantly greater damage. It's popular with stalkers for its cheap price. It's recommended to use it with other materials and it can also accelerate the sewing process.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]90%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]2%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] outfit repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glue_a">
		<text>Tube of glue "Tur"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glue_a_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all equipment and light helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Advanced glue, one of the better ones in the Zone. Stalkers choose it for its ease of use and versatility, especially when there are no other materials at hand. This glue easily binds lightweight fabrics and protective materials like Kevlar, but its useless when trying to bond metals.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]75%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]4%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] outfit repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] kevlar plates %c[0,170,170,170]+12%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glue_e">
		<text>Tube of glue "M17"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_glue_e_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all equipment and helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]The M17 is a soviet military level glue, its an extremely powerful adhesive that can be used in any situation and any material. There is virtually no such damage that this product cannot handle.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]60%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]6%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] outfit repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] kevlar plates %c[0,170,170,170]+12%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] steel plates %c[0,170,170,170]+18%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_armor_repair_fa">
		<text>Emergency armour repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_armor_repair_fa_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all kinds of equipment and light helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This emergency repair kit will allow you to perform urgent repairs on the field, it includes adhesive tape and ready-to-use sheets of fabric like tarpaulin in various shapes and sizes. Due to the low quality of the materials, this kit can only be used for minor repairs and is useless when applied to heavy armor.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (adhesive tape)\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]85%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]6%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_armor_repair_pro">
		<text>Field armour repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_armor_repair_pro_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all equipment and helmets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This is the field version of the universal kit for equipment repair, its weight and application are perfect for all sorts of trips. It consists of a few military grade tools and materials to carry out maintenance of most modern suits and helmets. Additional tools and materials like mutant skin can improve the repair of equipment.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]40%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]14%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] kevlar plates %c[0,170,170,170]+12%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] steel plates %c[0,170,170,170]+18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional outfit and headgear sets (all) %c[0,170,170,170]+11-32\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelts (all) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-14%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_armor_repair_pro_empty">
		<text>Field armour repair kit (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_armor_repair_pro_empty_descr">
		<text>Empty textile bag which previously contained tools and spare parts usable for maintaining combat armors. Even in its current state it can prove useful in repairing parts of outfits. A low-value trading commodity.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_repair_kit">
		<text>Combat helmet repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_repair_kit_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medium and heavy headgear sets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This kit contains everything that is needed to perform effective repair of modern combat helmets. It features heavy tools that will allow you to work on hard materials such as kevlar, steel or titanium, as well as a very strong, methacrylate-based adhesive. As the kit does not contain any sewing equipment, it cannot be effectively utilized for reparation of flexible materials of armors, but it can be used to disassemble headgear sets to greatly improve the effectiveness of repair.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]45%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]12%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] kevlar plates %c[0,170,170,170]+12%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] steel plates %c[0,170,170,170]+18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional headgear sets (all) %c[0,170,170,170]+11-20%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_repair_kit_empty">
		<text>Combat helmet repair kit (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_repair_kit_empty_descr">
		<text>Empty textile bag which previously contained tools and spare parts usable for maintaining combat helmets. Even in its current state it can prove useful in repairing parts of outfits. A low-value trading commodity.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit">
		<text>Professional armour repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] all outfits and headgear sets\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This complex and heavy set includes everything necessary - from ultra-durable threads and needles to polymer-based patches - to conduct a complete repair of any armor or headgear. Can be used regardless of materials involved, be it heavy cloth, military-grade kevlar sheets, or heavy mutant pelts. Additional tools and kits increase effectiveness of repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for repairing equipment\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] not usable below condition level: %c[0,170,170,170]30%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] base condition gain: %c[0,170,170,170]22%\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED MATERIALS:\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional repair kits %c[0,170,170,170]+6-18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] sewing kits %c[0,170,170,170]+3-9%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] adhesives %c[0,170,170,170]+2-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] reinforced textile (sheets) %c[0,170,170,170]+5-6%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] textile %c[0,170,170,170]+3-4%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] cloth %c[0,170,170,170]+2-3%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] kevlar plates %c[0,170,170,170]+12%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] steel plates %c[0,170,170,170]+18%\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] additional outfit and headgear sets (all) %c[0,170,170,170]+11-32\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] mutant pelts (all) %c[0,170,170,170]+3-14%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_empty">
		<text>Professional armour repair kit (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_kit_empty_descr">
		<text>Empty reinforced metal box which previously contained tools and spare parts usable for complex maintenance of combat armors. Even in its current state it can prove useful in repairing metal parts of outfits. A low-value trading commodity.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,140,140,140] outfit repairs (+5%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_identity_card_descr">
		<text>This is your personal ID card which reveals your true identity. Keep it hidden. As a USS Assaulter, you are specialized in assault rifles and heavy weapons. You are also specialized in the control of weapon recoil. Slow sprinting speed.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] personal belongings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_roubles">
		<text>Old coins</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_roubles_descr">
		<text>Trade in the Zone is conducted mainly by means of electronic transactions for safety and managing reasons. But many stalkers keep at least a few coins in their pockets in case they want to buy smaller things like cigarettes. This makes life easier and conserves battery life.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_flask">
		<text>Purified water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_flask_descr">
		<text>Military flasks are intended for storing small amounts of water. Prepared by medics and scientists. First, the water - combined with a special type of alcohol - is boiled at a very high temperature for purification and disinfection. Afterwards, it is cooled in refrigerators, to which it owes its refreshing "spark." The end result is water that is completely radiation-free. If in spite of the above, you still have doubts concerning its purity, you can always use akvatab. Due to the cost of production, military flasks are in a limited supply and are sold at a moderate price. Medics also have them in stock, but they're slightly more expensive as they include the cost of transportation.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] незначительное health improvement\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_akvatab">
		<text>Akvatabs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_akvatab_descr">
		<text>Small plastic bag with pills intended for disinfecting water containing harmful bacteria and viruses. Use two tablets at a time.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slow usage (dispersible tablets)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] eliminates toxins in the body</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_old_book">
		<text>Old book</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_old_book_descr">
		<text>ќбычна€ ничем не примечательна€ книга. Ќа некоторых страницах можно заметить жирные п€тна или загнутые уголки, что указывает на то, что ей когда-то активно пользовались.   сожалению, долгое хранение в отвратительных услови€х сказалось самым негативным образом - многие листы оказались вырваны или испорчены, а переплЄт держитс€ на одном лишь честном слове. ѕусть целесообразность ее чтени€ и стоит под большим вопросом, однако дл€ такой бумаги можно найти и иное применение. \n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] personal belongings\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jar">
		<text>Plastic jar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jar_descr">
		<text>A handful of gold teeth in a small plastic jar filled with sand and leaves to minimize the noise while running. Liberating a fallen stalker of his teeth is a favored practice among bandits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low value</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grooming">
		<text>Grooming kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grooming_descr">
		<text>Grooming kit that packs a ballistic nylon travel case with a beard and moustache comb and detail facial scissors, featuring man-sized finger rings, ultra-sharp cutting blades of stainless steel, non-slip rubberized grip, and a precision trimming tip.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_journal">
		<text>Personal diary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_journal_descr">
		<text>Personal journal with a number of primitive maps and notations. In a leather binding. Simple survival tips for the common man and nothing of much value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] personal belongings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maps_kit">
		<text>Cartography kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maps_kit_descr">
		<text>Mapmaking kit containing a set of pens and measurement instruments. All in a waterproof and camouflaged cover of high quality. Used by and issued to Ukrainian artillery personnel. Some maps have not yet been completed. Your PDA is much more useful than any of this.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] открывает расположение аномальных зон при использовании</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bottle_metal">
		<text>"Moonshine" bottle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bottle_metal_descr">
		<text>Metal bottle containing a portion of what seems to be Zone-produced vodka. It doesn't smell right and the fumes are strong.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong, low quality alcohol\n%c[255PROPERTIES:%c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_geiger">
		<text>Geiger counter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_geiger_descr">
		<text>A Geiger counter measures ionizing (radioactive) radiation. It detects the emission of alpha particles, beta particles and gamma particles. Invented in 1908, Geiger counters remain popular technological object used for measurements in health, physics, industry, geology and other fields of activity. Made of simple electronic circuits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item \n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] измер€ет уровень радиоактивного заражени€</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_welding_goggles">
		<text>Welding goggles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_welding_goggles_descr">
		<text>Old and corroded welding goggles with a broken leather band. Welding goggles are designed to provide eye protection while welding or cutting. Useless in their current state and of no to little value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_survival_kit">
		<text>Survival kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_survival_kit_descr">
		<text>Survival kit containing fabric, sewing needles and a few leather strips. Primarily used as a means to stop the bleeding and treat lacerations, in the hands of a skilled user this small survival kit may prove essential during prolonged excursions in the Zone. It can also be utilized for outfit repairs of even most severe damage.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slow usage (field kit)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] сильное уменьшение сонливости\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+7%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jewelry_box">
		<text>Jewelry box</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jewelry_box_descr">
		<text>A small box full of woman jewelry. It seems quite valuable but Zoners generally don't wear jewelry, except for bloodsucker teeth, so it's not likely to fetch a good price.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cooking">
		<text>Cooking set</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cooking_descr">
		<text>A field cooking travel kit. Contains cooking accessories and utensils for use when camping and travelling. Produces a lot of noise and is unwieldy due to its heavy weight. Very popular among larger groups of stalkers.\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]NOTES:\n%c[0,170,170,170]Although charcoal is available in the Zone at relatively cheap prices, you need to use a significant amount of it in order to prepare a single meal. For this reason, charcoal is not as cost effective as it would seem. On the other hand, it is relatively light, which makes it perfect for longer trips deep in the Zone.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Mutant meats that do not require high temperature to be prepared are referred to as 'low-tier', whereas those that require high temperature - 'high-tier'.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low-tier field cooking equipment\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] требует:%c[0,170,170,170] источник огн€\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for cooking meats of lesser mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_book1">
		<text>Mechanics manual</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_book1_descr">
		<text>Manual of mechanical engineering. Some people read such books to expand their expertise and learn more about the facilities and factories in the Zone. Low sale value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_book2">
		<text>Technical manual</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_book2_descr">
		<text>Manual of industrial engineering. Some people read such books to expand their expertise and learn more about the facilities and factories in the Zone. Low sale value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drugnotes">
		<text>Supply journal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drugnotes_descr">
		<text>This notebook describes various drug deals in detail. Specific nicknames, locations and time of meets. Some deals are executed through equipment exchanges and others are paid in large amounts of rubles. When browsing the pages, it becomes clear that Freedom is the main distributor of natural drugs such as marijuana. Bandits are producers and distributors of the more powerful (and dangerous) synthetic drugs like salicylic acid and cocaine. Apparently, every faction in the Zone takes part in these deals. In particular, Monolith seems to be taking in large amounts drugs in exchange for more expensive types of ammunition and equipment.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] personal belongings\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_picture_woman">
		<text>Picture of a woman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_picture_woman_descr">
		<text>A small picture of a beautiful woman with blond hair. The name at the bottom of the picture has been crossed out. Wrapped in plastic.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] personal belongings\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_name">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_descr">
		<text>A light sleeping bag that will keep you warm and dry when you need to rest. Be sure to pick a safe spot with a possible escape route. The bag is automatically picked up after sleeping or if hit "cancel" button.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255]WARNING:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Sleeping in the open may attract predators. Does not protect from radiation.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] разворачивает спальный мешок\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unlimited usages\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sleep_itm_warning_blowout">
		<text>It's not safe to sleep here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kit_hunt">
		<text>Hunting kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kit_hunt_descr">
		<text>A whole bag full of hooks, knives and other equipment used for skinning and gutting animals and mutants. Few stalkers carry professional equipment for mutant hunting. That is probably the reason why so many Zoners suffer from indigestion after eating mutant meat. Thanks to the variety of tools, the kit can effectively improve weapon and armor maintenance.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] элемент экипировки\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] possession increases number of body parts obtained from mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_porn2"> <!-- wip -->
		<text>Newspaper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_porn2_descr">
		<text>Ќемного пожелтевша€ газета. ¬ыпуск, кажетс€, еще мес€чной давности, если не больше. „тение газет - нар€дy с играми в карты, чтением книг, игрой на гитаре или гyбной гармони - €вл€етс€ одним из распространенных способов досyга в «оне. “акже газета позвол€ет оставатьс€ в кyрсе происход€щего за пределами „«ќ, пyсть и с большим запозданием. ѕомимо новостей в газетах встречаютс€ интересные статьи на самые разные темы, позвол€ющие на врем€ отвлечьс€ от окyжающего yжаса и переместить сознание на более при€тные и отстраненные вещи вроде истории или рецепта засолки огyрцов. ¬ слyчае нехватки бyмаги, в газеты заворачивают кyски м€са мyтантов дл€ хранени€.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_boots">
		<text>Reinforced boots</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_boots_descr">
		<text>Everyone is aware of the importance of good gear. An extra pair of boots can prove extremely useful and may be the object of envy of other stalkers since it is such a rarity.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] personal belongings\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+5%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tobacco">
		<text>Russian tobacco</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tobacco_descr">
		<text>Cigarettes are expensive and rare in the Zone, and having raw tobacco enables you to produce your own cigs at a lower cost. This tin is sealed, which ensures that the tobacco will stay fresh for days or weeks depending on the conditions it's kept in.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] average alleviation against psy-damage\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_batteries_dead">
		<text>Dead batteries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_batteries_dead_descr">
		<text>Only one out of ten batteries found in Zaton and Jupiter still carries some juice. Stalkers seem to throw them out when they're depleted since it's almost impossible to find a battery recharger. Their outer layer is corroded and covered in dirt, which is a strong indication that these are almost dead. Still, like everything in the Zone they also have their purpose and may prove useful for frequent UPD recharges.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] зар€дка:%c[0,170,170,170] +14%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_marijuana">
		<text>Marijuana</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_marijuana_descr">
		<text>Self-grown cannabis. Smoking it is a popular pastime, especially in Freedom. Marijuana bags can be bought here and there in the Zone. Some believe that the drug helps retain a balance of the mind.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong alleviation against psy-damage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_flashlight">
		<text>Handheld flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_flashlight_descr">
		<text>An old-school and very durable flashlight showing signs of intense use. By twisting the back for a few seconds, the power flow is reversed and stored in internal cells of the flashlight. It is an essential tool for exploration for extended periods of time. Unfortunately, it cannot be used along most of the weaponry since it requires a free hand. Thus is can be simultaneously used only with pistols and other single-handed equipment.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require UPD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_flashlight_broken">
		<text>Army lantern KSF-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_flashlight_broken_descr">
		<text>Broken pocket signal light in a scratched metal case, painted in black. Presumably it has been unchanged for a long period from the fifties to the nineties of the twentieth century. Designed for military use, powered by a battery size 3336L, has a lock inside the body to store a spare lamp. It is equipped with a device for fastening to the belt, a push button switch, a slide lock for the latter, and two filters (red and green) built into the front cover, which are guided by means of levers to the glass for the output of the light flux.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] broken beyond repair\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unusable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_underwear">
		<text>Underwear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_underwear_descr">
		<text>An extra pair of socks, a shirt and pants could substantially increase your comfort. Unfortunately, this set is completely soaked. There is little chance any stalker will pay for this garbage. Although they might seem worthless, the material the underwear is made of can be used in armor and weapon maintenance.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] personal belongings\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair, weapon maintenance (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts">
		<text>Weapon spare parts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_descr">
		<text>Spare parts for what looks to be an AKM assault rifle. The wooden parts are not in a very good condition, and the same can be said of metal elements. Only novices would be interested in buying them. However, it seems that they may be useful for equipment repairs. Certain Zoners replace some parts when finding a new weapon out in the open in order to avoid being hunted for stealing from someone's stash.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair, weapon maintenance (+10%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beadspread">
		<text>Bedspread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beadspread_descr">
		<text>Luxury item in the Zone. It gives you extra 10 percent chance of a good night's sleep. Since there are only a few beds in safehouses in Zaton and Jupiter, having a sleeping bag and a bed spread may prove essential if you don't want to hit the wall in most inappropriate of circumstances. Bed spreads are included in the equipment of some military units.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unlimited usages\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tent">
		<text>Tent</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tent_descr">
		<text>Ѕрезентова€ палатка €вл€етс€ широко известным временным сооружением, способным предоставить укрытие от ветра, дожд€ или пыли. »спользуемый материал был подвергнут огнеупорной, водоотталкивающей и противогнилостной пропиткам.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_walkie">
		<text>Radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_walkie_descr">
		<text>The display is dead and there is a constant hiss from the speaker indicating that this is of no use. Has what appears to be mutant teeth marks on it.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] broken beyond repair\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unusable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cards">
		<text>Deck of cards</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cards_descr">
		<text>It is important to divert your mind from suffering in this hellhole and focus on other, more pleasant things. Playing cards is a popular pastime, but a deck of cards can also be used for sorting special trades. The cover depicts the proud architectural design of the Moscow Metro.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka_quality">
		<text>"Stolichnaya" vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka_quality_descr">
		<text>A favorite amongst Russians and many people the world over. A Russian vodka of high quality. Highly popular in the Zone and widely available most probably owing to an outside connection of one of the traders. In order to avoid detection by the military units stationing around the Zone, it is usually shipped in army containers or metal barrels, and then distributed in sturdy metal bottles.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,14PROPERTIES:ул€тор\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong alcohol\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_bad">
		<text>Damaged ammo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_bad_descr">
		<text>Every stalker is aware of the importance of reliable weaponry. That's the reason a daily and thorough examination of your shooter is vital to your survival. Stalkers often count their ammo and clean it to minimize the risk of a weapon jam in the heat of battle. This ammo is in a bad condition and should be discarded.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] возможно перебрать дл€ получени€ пригодных дл€ стрельбы патронов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mili_maps">
		<text>Military maps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mili_maps_descr">
		<text>Maps showing the location of military camps around the Zone. Each PDA comes with these maps installed, so this item is of little use to anyone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] открывает расположение аномальных зон при использовании</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_swiss">
		<text>Swiss knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_swiss_descr">
		<text>Want to open cans of food, keep your mechanical gear tight, cut ropes or sharpen your best bullets? Use the universal and elegant Swiss knife. Packed in a small box. Commonly found in the Zone, so it is of little value. However, it can be utilized as a supportive material in both weapon and outfit repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair, weapon maintenance (+2%)\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unlimited usages</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_headlamp">
		<text>Broken headlamp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_headlamp_descr">
		<text>Although few dare to explore the Zone during the night, there are circumstances where a head lamp is crucial. And another source of light won't hurt, because you never know when you'll have to move from place to place. Unfortunately, this particular unit has long seen its working days and can now only serve as a source of cheap spare parts.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] broken beyond repair\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unusable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mirror">
		<text>Telescopic mirror</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mirror_descr">
		<text>Small mirror mounted on a telescopic iron tube. A handy item used by fighters versed in the arts of urban combat as it allows to peek around corners without getting shot.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_batteries_ccell">
		<text>Military battery pack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_batteries_ccell_descr">
		<text>A pack of fully charged military batteries. Very valuable and in high demand due to the relative scarcity of batteries in the Zone. Used by all factions and Zoners of all levels, from rookies to master stalkers. Supplied to traders by corrupt military officers trying to earn some extra dough in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] зар€дка:%c[0,170,170,170] +93%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cocaine">
		<text>Cocaine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cocaine_descr">
		<text>Small aluminum case containing cocaine and the tools facilitating use. Cocaine is a powerful nervous system stimulant. Its effects can last from 15-30 minutes to an hour, depending on the route of administration. Cocaine increases alertness, induces feelings of well-being, competence and sexuality. Anxiety, paranoia and restlessness are common side effects. With excessive dosage, tremors, convulsions and increased body temperature are observed. Bandits are known for sniffing this drug right before launching an assault or ambush.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] среднее health improvement\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] сильное уменьшение сонливости</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tetanus"> <!-- wrong? -->
		<text>Antibiotic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tetanus_descr">
		<text>»нъекци€ быстродействующего антибиотика. ѕоказани€ к применению - т€жЄлые отравлени€ и высокий уровень интоксикации организма. ¬ услови€х «оны рекомендуетс€ использование инъекции после каждого приЄма в пищу 1кг местной фауны, м€со которой крайне богато разичными возбудител€ми болезней даже после термической обработки. ¬ состав этого препарата также вход€т вещества, снимающие посталкогольный синдром.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] medicine\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] eliminates toxins in the body</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tarpaulin">
		<text>Camouflaged tarpaulin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tarpaulin_descr">
		<text>A tarpaulin (or hootch) is a large sheet of strong, flexible, water-resistant or waterproof material, often cloth such as canvas or polyester coated with urethane, or made of plastics such as polyethylene. It has reinforced grommets at the corners and along the sides to form attachment points for rope, allowing them to be tied down or suspended. Serves many purposes, but is mainly used to create small and simple tent-like hideouts. Trading value is low due to easily found alternatives.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair, weapon maintenance (+5%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rope">
		<text>Rope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rope_descr">
		<text>A good rope serves many purposes, especially in a place like the Zone. Many stalkers can put it to good use, which generates a rather high trading value. About 10-meters long.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_synthrope">
		<text>Dense synthetic rope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_synthrope_descr">
		<text>Synthetic ropes are commonly found in military warehouses. But for some reason few military stalkers actually carry them. A good rope serves many purposes, especially in a place like the Zone. Many stalkers can put this to good use, which generates a rather high trading value. Each is about 5 meters long.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+4%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cutlery">
		<text>Cutlery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cutlery_descr">
		<text>A spoon, a knife and a fork made of heavy steel. A robust and reasonably light cutlery set, ideal for backpacking and field exploration. The cutlery is held together by a copper cord. If cleaned properly and derusted, it would be safe to use.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon lubrication and cleaning (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_adrenalin">
		<text>Epinephrine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_adrenalin_descr">
		<text>Epinephrine (also known as adrenalin) is a hormone and a neurotransmitter. Epinephrine has many functions in the body, instantly regulating heart rate, blood vessel and air passage diameters, and metabolic shifts. Epinephrine release is a crucial component of the fight-or-flight response of the sympathetic nervous system. The effects lead to increased blood glucose and fatty acids, providing substrates for instant energy production within cells throughout the body.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high health improvement \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] сильное уменьшение сонливости</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_radio">
		<text>Portable radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_radio_descr">
		<text>Music is a good way to calm your nerves. But with a broken antenna this radio is of little use. Moisture and dirt have also damaged this item.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] broken beyond repair\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unusable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_radio2">
		<text>Broken radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_radio2_descr">
		<text>A small radio in a poor condition. Dirty and damaged by moisture. The interior seems to be in quite a bad shape as the radio rattles when moved around. No to little value.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] broken beyond repair\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] unusable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sleep_itm_warning_blowout">
		<text>It's not safe to sleep here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_qr_name">
		<text>Quick release system (QRS)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_qr_descr">
		<text>ќдна из худших вещей в «оне, которые могут случитьс€ с вами - это если вас застанут врасплох. ’оть QR-система не поможет вам избежать таких ситуаций, но, безусловно, поможет выпутатьс€ из сложившихс€ обсто€тельств! ‘ункци€ такой системы весьма проста: она отцепл€ет л€мки рюкзака практически мгновенно и позвол€ет отбежать на безопасное рассто€ние налегке, без т€жести рюкзака. „тобы воспользоватьс€ QR-системой, переместите еЄ на одну из Ђ√ор€чих клавишї (F1-F4 или альтернативные). Ќажмите Ђ√ор€чую клавишуї дл€ активации системы быстрого сброса, котора€ мгновенно сбросит ваш рюкзак (и всЄ, что находитс€ внутри него). ¬аше снар€жЄнное оружие, боеприпасы, брон€ и технологические предметы останутс€ при вас, так что вы будете готовы к обороне. –юкзак вы сможете забрать позднее.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] поставл€етс€ с GPS-модулем\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] мгновенное использование (отстегнуть застЄжки)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] экипированное снар€жение не сбрасываетс€</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_backpack_stash_name">
		<text>A backpack with GPS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_backpack_stash_desc">
		<text>An extremely durable backpack with implemented GPS devices. Automatically synchronized with your PDA once dropped to generate a stash that is marked on your PDA. The backpack is made of strong and durable materials that will keep your equipment safe and dry regardless of environmental conditions. The camouflaged design assures that it doesn't stand out from the surroundings.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] built-in GPS\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] single usage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_compression_bag">
		<text>Compression bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_compression_bag_descr">
		<text>Holds a small sleeping bag or a small number of clothes\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] use near unrolled sleeping bag to pack it up\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_identity_card">
		<text>Personal indentification SBU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_identity_card_assaulter_descr">
		<text>As a USS Assaulter you have unique strengths and weaknesses.\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]EQUIPMENT\n
		%c[default]Heavy armor agility: %c[255,230,150,30]A+\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Closed breathing agility: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Artifact handling: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]WEAPONS\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Knife fighting: %c[255,230,150,30]A+\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Handling speciality: %c[255,230,150,30]High recoils\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Maintenance speciality: %c[255,230,150,30]Heavy weapons\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]MEDICINE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Bandages/medkits dexterity: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Medic skills: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Drug handling skills: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]ATHLETICS\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Endurance: %c[255,230,150,30]very high\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Sprinting speed: %c[255,230,150,30]slow\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Jump height: %c[255,230,150,30]low\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Fall/jump agility: %c[255,230,150,30]low\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Base stamina: %c[255,230,150,30]low\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Maximum carry weight: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]HEALTH PROFILE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Food consumption rate: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Need for sleep: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]IMMMUNE SYSTEM RESISTANCE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Drugs/alcohol:%c[255,230,150,30]A+\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Unhealthy food: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Artifacts: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Radiation: %c[255,230,150,30]C</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_identity_card_recon_descr">
		<text>As a USS Recon you have unique strengths and weaknesses.\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]EQUIPMENT\n
		%c[default]Heavy armor agility: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Closed breathing agility: %c[255,230,150,30]A+\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Artifact handling: %c[255,230,150,30]A+\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]WEAPONS\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Knife fighting: %c[255,230,150,30]A\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Handling speciality: %c[255,230,150,30]SMG's\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Maintenance speciality: %c[255,230,150,30]SMG's\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]MEDICINE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Bandages/medkits dexterity: %c[255,230,150,30]A+\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Medic skills: %c[255,230,150,30]A\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Drug handling skills: %c[255,230,150,30]A\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]ATHLETICS\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Endurance: %c[255,230,150,30]low\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Sprinting speed: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Jump height: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Fall/jump agility: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Base stamina: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Maximum carry weight: %c[255,230,150,30]low\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]HEALTH PROFILE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Food consumption rate: %c[255,230,150,30]slow\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Need for sleep: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]IMMMUNE SYSTEM RESISTANCE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Drugs/alcohol: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Unhealthy food: %c[255,230,150,30]C\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Artifacts: %c[255,230,150,30]A\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Radiation: %c[255,230,150,30]A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_identity_card_sniper_descr">
		<text>As a USS Sniper your attributes are extremely well balanced.\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]EQUIPMENT\n
		%c[default]Heavy armor agility: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Closed breathing agility: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Artifact handling: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]WEAPONS\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Knife fighting: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Handling speciality: %c[255,230,150,30]sniper rifles\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Maintenance speciality: %c[255,230,150,30]sniper rifles \n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]MEDICINE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Bandages/medkits dexterity: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Medic skills: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Drug handling skills: %c[255,230,150,30]B+\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]ATHLETICS\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Endurance: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Sprinting speed: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Jump height: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Fall/jump agility: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Stamina running: %c[255,230,150,30]high\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Stamina sprinting: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Maximum carry weight: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]HEALTH PROFILE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Food consumption rate: %c[255,230,150,30]medium\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Need for sleep: %c[255,230,150,30]low\n\n
		%c[0,153,255,255]IMMMUNE SYSTEM RESISTANCE\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Drugs/alcohol: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Unhealthy food: %c[255,230,150,30]A+\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Artifacts: %c[255,230,150,30]B\n%c[0,153,255,255]
		%c[default]Radiation: %c[255,230,150,30]B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_morphine">
		<text>Ampoule of morphine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_morphine_descr">
		<text>An iron ampoule designed as field equipment for military field personnel for instant pain reduction. This ampoule contains a powerful dose of morphine. In clinical medicine, morphine is regarded as the gold standard of opioid analgesics used to relieve severe or agonizing pain and suffering. Like other opioids, such as oxycodone, hydromorphone, and diacetylmorphine (heroin), morphine acts directly on the central nervous system (CNS) to relieve pain. Injected into an arm or a thigh.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] больша€ стойкость к физическим повреждени€м\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] небольшое восстановление здоровь€ после использовани€\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_salicidic_acid">
		<text>Ampoule of salicylic acid</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_salicidic_acid_descr">
		<text>An iron ampoule designed as field equipment for military field personnel for instant pain reduction. It contains a powerful dose of metamizole mixed with an antihemorrhagic drug. Metamizole is one of the strongest Non-Steroidal Anti-Inflammatory Drugs (NSAIDs), especially effective at easing aches and pains as well as reducing fevers. It is also useful as anti-inflammatory drug when used in higher doses. May cause some delayed side effects such as leucopenia or agranulocytosis, so it should be used with moderation. Injected into an arm or a thigh. Its availability in the Zone is limited due to the difficulty of smuggling the medicine across military cordons.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fast usage (syringe)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] больша€ стойкость к физическим повреждени€м\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] небольшое восстановление здоровь€ после использовани€\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] быстрое заживление ран\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] slight side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tomato">
		<text>Canned tomatoes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tomato_descr">
		<text>Canned, sliced and diced tomatoes are imported to the Zone on a regular basis. The best before date on the bottom suggests they're still fresh.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sausage">
		<text>Smoked sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sausage_descr">
		<text>Made of beef and pork. Smoked and vacuum packaged, it can be preserved for long periods of time. This particular piece has been imported from the Russian Federation. Famous among certain Russian mafia leaders for its exceptional flavor and taste.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_corn">
		<text>Canned corn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_corn_descr">
		<text>Canned sweet corn imported from the outside. Can be eaten as it is, but there are some who use it as a soup ingredient.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mineral_water">
		<text>Mineral water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mineral_water_descr">
		<text>Mineral water from Ukrainian springs. Carbonated and with additional calcium.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+1%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hand_rolling_tobacco">
		<text>Hand-rolling tobacco</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hand_rolling_tobacco_descr">
		<text>Precious hand-rolling tobacco, imported from the West. With no additional ingredients, so it's possible to enjoy the original taste of tobacco leaf itself.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong alleviation against psy-damage\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beer">
		<text>Ukranian beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beer_descr">
		<text>Ukrainian beer. Another - beside vodka - popular beverage in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] drink\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] слабый алкоголь</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beans">
		<text>Baked beans</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beans_descr">
		<text>Canned baked beans brought from the West. The kidney beans with tomato sauce may bring back nice memories for some people.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_chili">
		<text>Chili beans</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_chili_descr">
		<text>Canned chili beans imported from the West. Popular as an ingredient in some dishes in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_salmon">
		<text>Smoked salmon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_salmon_descr">
		<text>Ukrainian smoked salmon. As soon as it's brought to the Zone, the fish changes hands until it finds its way to the highest bidder. Very valuable.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_raisins">
		<text>Raisins</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_raisins_descr">
		<text>A pack of raisins. Rich in nutrients, balances sugar in the blood.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_chocolate">
		<text>Chocolate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_chocolate_descr">
		<text>Russian chocolate. Very rare in the Zone and quite valuable even though its taste is nothing special. Brings back many fond childhood memories, which may help soothe the pain of living in the harsh and unforgiving conditions of the Zone.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mint">
		<text>Mints "Altoids"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mint_descr">
		<text>Mint-flavored altoids imported from the West. They are highly refreshing and remove radiation particles from the mouth. They also seem to reduce sleepiness for a short while. You can take as many as 10 mints at a time but that's only because your mouth isn't able to fit any more.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caffeine">
		<text>Caffeine pills </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caffeine_descr">
		<text>Caffeine and sodium benzoate which cause central nervous to work with highest effectiveness possible at a given time. Reduce sleepiness to a large degree. Take two tablets at one time.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] health improvement\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] сильное уменьшение сонливости</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cuban_cigar">
		<text>Cuban cigar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cuban_cigar_descr">
		<text>This valuable Cuban cigar can bring you bliss for a short while, especially when you're admiring a nice sunset. Some stalkers noticed that smoking strong tobacco repels mosquitoes. Cuban cigars are considered the finest in the world. A rare commodity.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] strong alleviation against psy-damage\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigarettes_lucky">
		<text>Cigarettes "Lucky Strike</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigarettes_lucky_descr">
		<text>Cigarettes imported from the West. Some stalkers trade them for a few rounds of ammo within their faction.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] average alleviation against psy-damage\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigarettes_russian">
		<text>Cigarettes "Peter I"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigarettes_russian_descr">
		<text>The cheapest pack of cigarettes in the Zone. Russian budget brand.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] слабое облегчение последствий пси-облучени€\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigar1">
		<text>Cigarettes "Spark"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigar1_descr">
		<text>A pack of budget, strong and very low quality cigarettes. Someone must have smoked most of them since there are only a few left. Genuine USSR flavor has been carefully preserved.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] слабое облегчение последствий пси-облучени€\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigar2">
		<text>Cigarettes "Glory"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigar2_descr">
		<text>A pack of budget, strong and very low quality cigarettes. Someone must have smoked most of them since there are only a few left. Genuine USSR flavor has been carefully preserved.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] слабое облегчение последствий пси-облучени€\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigar3">
		<text>Cigarettes "Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cigar3_descr">
		<text>A pack of budget, strong and very low quality cigarettes. Someone must have smoked most of them since there are only a few left. Genuine USSR flavor has been carefully preserved.\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]NOTE:\n%c[0,170,170,170]Smoking will help stabilizing the mental state after psi exposure.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] stimulant\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] слабое облегчение последствий пси-облучени€\n%c[0,204,0,51] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] damages health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nuts">
		<text>Assorted nuts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nuts_descr">
		<text>Assorted peanuts, hazelnuts, cashews and almonds in a nice and popular blend. Nutrition value is quite high. Imported from South Africa.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] food\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_upd">
		<text>Universal Power Device (UPD)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_upd_descr">
		<text>Cold War era power unit about the size of a small walkie talkie. Accepts almost any type of batteries. Utilizes every bit of energy from inserted batteries and supplies electronic devices with power in an enhanced stream through a set of micro wires. These can be connected to any piece of equipment, regardless of its complexity or age. Allows stalkers to use and handle numerous electronic devices even if they have only one battery.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] портативный источник питани€\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] поддерживает большинство современных устройств\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] поддерживает все типы батареек\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] Ємкость %c[0,170,170,170]3 јч (ампер-часа)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy">
		<text>No</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_descr">
		<text>Energy reserves are determined by the Amper-hours (Ah).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mre">
		<text>MRE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mre_descr">
		<text>The Meal, Ready-to-Eat (commonly known as the MRE) is a self-contained, individual field ration in lightweight packaging, developed by the United States military for its service members for use in combat or other field conditions where organized food facilities are not available. One MRE can be used as one meal. The packaging of an MRE is designed to withstand rough conditions and exposure to the elements. Contains one course along with a variety of other food and drink items. While it can be eaten cold, it usually tastes much better when heated up with the included flameless ration heater (FRH, a water-activated exothermic reaction device that emits heat).\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] военный рацион\n\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] 3 порции в одной упаковке. 1398 к ал в суmmе</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ration_ru">
		<text>Russian food ration IRP-B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ration_ru_descr">
		<text>Breakfast, dinner and supper all in one package. Includes various food items whose function is to provide the body with all minerals and microelements essential for your health as well as cooking equipment (small metal frame, fuel tablets, matches, striker) and other items (e.g. napkins) facilitating use in field conditions. Comes with a polymeric box that protects the ingredients from hazardous environmental conditions. The polymeric box has 3 sections, each respectively for breakfast, dinner and supper.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] военный рацион\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] 7 порций в одной упаковке. 3661 к ал в суmmе</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ration_ukr">
		<text>Ukrainian food ration</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ration_ukr_descr">
		<text>This Ukrainian combat ration is based on a previous Russian version, and comprises commercially available cans and dried food items packed together in a sectioned box (resembling a takeout tray) made of very thin green plastic. Contains all that is necessary to provide a healthy adult with all calories and minerals needed during a single day.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] военный рацион\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] clean nutrition source\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] 6 порций в одном пакете. 3186 к ал в суmmе</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mine_name">
		<text>PFM-1 Fragmentaion anti-personnel mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mine_descr">
		<text>PFM-1 (short for противопехотна€ фугасна€ мина; NATO name: "Green parrot") used to be a standard-issue anti-personnel mine of the Red Army, employed mainly during the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan. Its widespread utilization during the conflict led to high civilian casualties, especially among children, since randomly scattered mines were often mistaken for toys due to their familiar shape and color. For this reason, the PFM-1 earned a sinister nickname: "Child killer." Since then, the mine has been replaced by newer models. However, as was the case with a variety of other 'retired' weaponry, a large number of these mines has somehow made its way into the Zone, becoming its primary booby-trap explosive. The mine is highly valued mainly for its functionality, user-friendliness, compact size and low weight, while its main drawback is a relatively small amount of explosive material: its power is often insufficient to kill a heavily armored stalker with a single blast. For this reason, the mine should be used in combination with other explosive materials and it acts as an igniter. If it is not armed, the mine will not detonate, even when hit with a gun.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] противопехотна€ мина\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]нажатие\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]небольша€\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]2.2 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]нет\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]нет\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]нет</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ied_rpg">
		<text>Improvised Explosive Device (RPG-7)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ied_rpg_descr">
		<text>Improvised explosive device based on OG-7V warhead and parts of a car battery. It looks like it has been carried around for quite some time and could go off any second. Fortunately, the triggering mechanism ensures that it won't unless the explosive is directly hit by a bullet or subjected to other potent physical force. In the Zone, IEDs are quite popular and Zoners use them for a variety of purposes, from gaining access to closed areas to ambushes. They are also often placed next to mines to greatly amplify the power of explosion. IED can be effectively concealed making it virtually invisible to everyone else.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140]  unnoticeable when placed on ground\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]ближнего действи€\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]7.8 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]56 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]440 (shrapnels)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]нет</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ied">
		<text>Improvised Explosive Device (chemical)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ied_descr">
		<text>Improvised explosive device produced from various chemical substances, with a broken electrical igniter and in steel ball container. Chemicals used in the device produce intense odor and are heavily toxic. This IED is significantly more powerful than a more common OG-7V version. In the Zone, IEDs are quite popular and Zoners use them for a variety of purposes, from gaining access to closed areas to ambushes. They are also often placed next to mines to greatly amplify the explosion's power. IED can be effectively concealed making it virtually invisible to everyone else.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140]  unnoticeable when placed on ground\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]ближнего действи€\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]very high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]12.9 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]74 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]580 (steel balls)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]нет</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mine_wire"> <!-- wip -->
		<text>Booby trap</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mine_wire_descr">
		<text>—амодельное взрывное устройство на основе боеголовки от снар€да –ѕ√-7 и взрывател€ из аккумул€торной батареи. ѕохоже, что уже весьма потрЄпанна€, так что может рвануть в любую секунду.   счастью, отсутствие спускного механизма внушает какую-то надежду, что она не сдетонирует пр€мо у вас в руках, если, конечно, какой-то придурок не станет стрел€ть по вам и не попадЄт в боеголовку. ¬ «оне самодельные взрывные устройства весьма попул€рны и часто используютс€ сталкерами, например, чтобы забратьс€ в недоступное место или при организации засады. “акже зачастую размещаютс€ р€дом с минами, чтобы усилить мощность взрыва. —нар€д очень легко спр€тать, поэтому можно организовать весьма неприметную ловушку.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] military item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140]  unnoticeable when placed on ground\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]ближнего действи€\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]low\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]2.1 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]120 (shrapnels)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]нет</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas">
		<text>Gas tank (8 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]very high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]6.4 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]36 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas2">
		<text>Gas tank(7 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas2_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]very high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]5.6 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]31.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas3">
		<text>Gas tank (6 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas3_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]4.8 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]27 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas4">
		<text>Gas tank (5 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas4_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]4 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]22.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas5">
		<text>Gas tank (4 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas5_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]medium\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]3.2 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]18 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas6">
		<text>Gas tank (3 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas6_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]medium\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]2.4 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]13.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas7">
		<text>Gas tank (2 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas7_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]low\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]1.6 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]9 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas8">
		<text>Gas tank (1 litre)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas8_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]Heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. Upon direct gunfire, the canister may ignite and after a short while a rapid release of a considerable amount of energy may follow, causing the gas in the balloon to expand instantly and resulting in a delayed but powerful explosion with metal shrapnels going in every direction. Such canisters have been utilized as a weapon in the feuds between factions in the Zone killing many and crippling even more. If emptied, the balloon can be utilized for armor repairs.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] refined natural gas\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]low\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]0.8 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]4.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]28 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~2 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas_empty">
		<text>Gas tank (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_balon_gas_empty_descr">
		<text>Emptied heavy metal gas balloon impregnated with compatible polymer on the inside and on the outside with Hypalon for weather abrasion and UV resistance. This gas holder balloon is a collapsible, intermediated storage tank for any industrial gas, prior to bottling under pressure. In the Zone such canisters most often contain a composition of methane, propane, ethane and butane, and can be used for cooking or heating as well as for combat purposes. It is empty now, but you can still put it to good use in outfit maintenance.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_metalcan_powder">
		<text>Can of powder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_metalcan_powder_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A small and moderately heavy metal can filled with a mixture of explosive industrial chemicals, metal bolts and nuts as well as black gunpowder retrieved from old ammunition. A notorious death trap designed by a group of Russian bandits known as "the Swireksters" and sold to various bandit groups operating in Zaton and Jupiter. Upon direct gunfire, the can will instantly explode with metal bolts and corrosive chemicals bursting in every direction. No one in their right mind should drop their guard when planning to make use of this deadly weapon. You can also use the metal parts of the can for emergency maintenance of outfits.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+1%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]low\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]1.8 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]14 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]77 (мелкие металлические части)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]нет</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_item">
		<text>Jerrycan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel">
		<text>Jerrycan (8 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]5.6 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]28 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel2">
		<text>Jerrycan (7 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel2_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]high\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]4.9 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]24.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel3">
		<text>Jerrycan (6 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel3_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]medium\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]4.2 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]21 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel4">
		<text>Jerrycan (5 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel4_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]medium\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]3.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]17.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel5">
		<text>Jerrycan (4 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel5_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]medium\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]2.8 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]14 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel6">
		<text>Jerrycan (3 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel6_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]low\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]2.1 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]10.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel7">
		<text>Jerrycan (2 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel7_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]low\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]1.4 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]7 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel8">
		<text>Jerrycan (1 litre)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel8_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]WARNING: Explodes upon impact\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]A large metal can filled with E95 gasoline. Jerrycans were brought to the Zone in large quantities by the Ukrainian military for their armored vehicles. Initially, they served their purpose, but after the second Chernobyl Disaster vehicles for reasons still unknown were no longer operational. While some Zoners are still trying to make the wrecks work again, others have found alternate ways of utilizing the jerrycans, namely, as improvised explosives. Upon direct hit, the canister will catch fire and explode after a slight delay. Although heavy and cumbersome, it is extremely powerful, and a well-placed jerrycan can be lethal even if the target wears the heaviest of body armors. On the other hand, the explosion is often so potent that the killer becomes the victim himself, so it's best to use these canisters with caution. There are rumors that a veteran stalker named Yuya once saved his skin by luring a pseudogiant into a jerrycan trap. He emptied his last Makarov magazine and the giant burst into flames with a roar that was heard throughout the Jupiter.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] contains: %c[0,170,170,170] E95 gasoline\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+4%)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] triggering mechanism: %c[0,170,170,170]bullet impact or explosion\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast power: %c[0,170,170,170]low\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] blast radius: %c[0,170,170,170]0.7 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fragments' radius: %c[0,170,170,170]3.5 m\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] av. number of fragments: %c[0,170,170,170]39 (heavy metal fragments)\n%c[0,93,0,116] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosion delay: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel_empty">
		<text>Jerrycan (empty)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jerrycan_fuel_empty_descr">
		<text>Empty metal can. It can only be used as material for the purposes of basic outfit repairs or sold to traders.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] explosive\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] outfit repairs (+2%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wood_stove">
		<text>Homemade camping stove</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wood_stove_descr">
		<text>This compact foldable oven is intended for cooking single entree meals with dry wood. However, since wood found within the Zone is far too contaminated to be used for that purpose, stalkers rely on imported charcoal as the cheapest and most widely available burnable material. The stove can produce temperatures sufficient to grill less poisoned mutant meat, but preparing more toxic meat requires the utilization of more advanced equipment. Basic fire skills are needed. Made of stainless steel and ultralight titanium.\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]NOTES:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Although charcoal is available in the Zone at relatively cheap prices, you need to use a significant amount of it in order to prepare a single meal. For this reason, charcoal is not as cost effective as it would seem. On the other hand, it is relatively light, which makes it perfect for longer trips deep in the Zone.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Mutant meats that do not require high temperature to be prepared are referred to as 'low-tier', whereas those that require high temperature - 'high-tier'.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] low-tier field cooking equipment\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fuel:%c[0,170,170,170] charcoal\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for cooking meats of lesser mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_fieldcooker">
		<text>Field cooker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_fieldcooker_descr">
		<text>The stove has been tested extensively over many years and has been used on countless expeditions. It is extremely robust, reliable and powerful and was designed to handle demanding situations, extreme altitudes and both low and high temperatures. It has a very high output and can be used with virtually any kind of fuel, including butane, gasoline / petrol, diesel, kerosene / paraffin, and even aviation fuel. Using the separate control knob, you can adjust the flame to the heat you want, even if you are wearing gloves.\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]NOTES:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Since fuels used in the multi-fuel stove are much more efficient energy-carriers than the wood or coal, the multi-fuel stove is - in the long run - significantly more cost-effective than traditional wood or coal stoves. On the other hand, these fuels are usually carried in heavy metal containers, which makes them more suited for use at bases, rather than in field operations.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Mutant meats that do not require high temperature to be prepared are referred to as 'low-tier', whereas those that require high temperature - 'high-tier'.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier field cooking equipment\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fuel:%c[0,170,170,170] gasoline, natural gas, kerosene\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for cooking meats of all mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosene">
		<text>Kerosene (1 litre)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosene_4">
		<text>Kerosene (4 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosene_3">
		<text>Kerosene (3 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosene_2">
		<text>Kerosene (2 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosene_5">
		<text>Kerosene (5 litres)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosene_descr">
		<text>Kerosene is used widely, for example in aviation as rocket fuel, and as firing in glass products, household lighting and heating devices. Being an excellent solvent, it easily reaches internal mechanisms and is therefore widely used in the cleaning and repair of various components.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high-tier cooking fuel\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] usable for:%c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+3%)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_charcoal">
		<text>Charcoal (1 kg)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_charcoal_2">
		<text>Charcoal (2 kg)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_charcoal_3">
		<text>Charcoal (3 kg)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_charcoal_descr">
		<text>Charcoal from hardwood timber for cooking meat, fish, vegetables in the brazier and barbecue.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,0,255,30] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] fuel for low-tier field cooking equipments</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_matches">
		<text>A box of matches</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_matches_descr">
		<text>A simple set of sticks of pine wood impregnated with resin. Anyone who has ever tried to light a fire in the open air knows that random gusts of wind can extinguish the flames very quickly. The firstarter set allows you to create a small but steady hearth fire, the temperature of which is significantly higher than that of paper or wax. An indispensable thing in any campaign, because it easy to light up even in the wet.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] используетс€ дл€ розжига костра</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- new - dead air -->
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_acetone">
		<text>Can of rosin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_acetone_descr">
		<text>Ѕанка канифоли, используемой при пайке. –едка€ вещь в «оне: как правило, фрагменты сломавшихс€ предметов здесь соедин€ют при помощи изоленты.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_capacitor">
		<text>A pack of capacitors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_capacitor_descr">
		<text>Ёлектрические конденсаторы служат дл€ накоплени€ электроэнергии. ѕростейший конденсатор состоит из двух металлических пластин-обкладок и диэлектрика, наход€щегос€ между ними. —ами по себе довольно редки в «оне, но весьма полезны.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_textolite">
		<text>Textolite base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_textolite_descr">
		<text>ѕредставл€ет собой слоистый пластик на основе ткани из волокон и полимерного св€зующего вещества (бакелита, полиэфирной смолы, эпоксидной смолы). ѕри должной сноровке может здорово помочь в починке.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_transistor">
		<text>A box of transistors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_transistor_descr">
		<text> оробка качественных транзисторов - полупроводниковых деталей, способных генерировать, преобразовать и усиливать электрические колебани€. ѕредел мечтаний радиотехника, если такого чудом занесЄт в «ону.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_wire">
		<text>A coil of copper wire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_wire_descr">
		<text>Ёлектротехническа€ медна€ проволока используетс€ практически во всех приборах, устройствах, аппаратах, установках, машинах, где происходит производство, передача или использование электрической энергии. ¬ «оне встречаетс€ относительно часто, €вл€€сь незаменимым элементом при работе с радиотехникой. ¬ чистом виде встречаетс€ редко, но при необходимости ее можно легко извлечь из распространенных старых радиоприемников, раций и прочей электроники.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_artefact_container_name">
		<text>Artefact container</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_backpack_light">
		<text>Camping backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_backpack_light_desc">
		<text>ќбычный рюкзак со множеством подсумков и отделений, при помощи которого переноситс€ снар€жение, личные вещи, продукты и охотничьи принадлежности. ќдно из первых об€зательных приобретений сталкера-новичка.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] элемент экипировки</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_backpack_heavy">
		<text>Travel backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_backpack_heavy_desc">
		<text> рупный рюкзак дл€ дальних путешествий. Ѕлагодар€ системе равномерного распределени€ веса, позвол€ет переносить достаточно припасов и снар€жени€ дл€ продолжительного похода до п€ти дней.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] элемент экипировки</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_airtank">
		<text>Oxygen tank</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_airtank_desc">
		<text>—тандартна€ часть сталкерской экипировки дл€ дальних вылазок. ѕозвол€ет выжить в местности с высоким уровнем радиационного и химического заражени€. ¬ комплекте имеетс€ простейша€ дыхательна€ маска, позвол€юща€ пользоватьс€ баллоном без дополнительной экипировки.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] элемент экипировки\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require seasoning</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_exobackpack_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_exobackpack_descr">
		<text>\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Ёкспериментальный образец военного экзоскелета. ¬ серийное производство не пошЄл ввиду чрезвычайно высокой себестоимости и некоторых огрехов в проектировании. Ќесмотр€ на это, из-за возможности значительно увеличивать мобильность носител€ пользуетс€ спросом и потому негласно выпускаетс€ малыми парти€ми за пределами ”краины. «аметным недостатком устройства €вл€етс€ его металлическа€ основа, котора€ пусть и предоставл€ет некоторую физическую защиту, но в значительной степени подвержена воздействию радиации, электричества и высоких температур.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] элемент экипировки</text>
	</string>
	

	<string id="st_itm_backpack_name">
		<text>Field backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_backpack_desc">
		<text>–юкзак из прочного материала, способный выдержать самые суровые погодные услови€. \n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] everyday item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] закладывает тайник при использовании</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_name">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_desc">
		<text>ѕоходный спальный мешок, достаточно тЄплый, чтобы пережить ночь в «оне.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_repairkit_tier_1_name">
		<text>Tools for basic work</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_repairkit_tier_1_descr">
		<text>Ќабор инструментов Ђёный техникї. ¬ наличии все необходимые дл€ слесарной работы инструменты. ƒл€ опытного техника такой набор необходим дл€ проведени€ самых простых апгрейдов брони и оружи€. ƒл€ обычного сталкера станет удобным инструментом при создании самых простых вещей, вроде угольной печи.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] используетс€ при создании и ремонте предметов </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_repairkit_tier_2_name">
		<text>Tools for fine work</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_repairkit_tier_2_descr">
		<text>Ќеплохой набор инструментов дл€ радиомонтажа. —одержит в себе отвЄртки, па€льник и прочие, необходиые при работе с радиоаппаратурой, инструменты. Ќезаменима€ вещь в случае поломки рации или  ѕ . Ќесмотр€ на своЄ пр€мое предназначение, в умелых руках может быть полезен при самых различных видах работ.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] используетс€ при создании и ремонте предметов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_repairkit_tier_3_name">
		<text>Calibration tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_repairkit_tier_3_descr">
		<text>ѕрофессиональный набор инструментов дл€ тонкой доводки оборудовани€. Ќадпись на €щике гласит, что набор произведЄн в √ƒ–. “ого, что включено в комплект, достаточно дл€ проведени€ почти любых работ по настройке и калибровке.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] используетс€ при создании и ремонте предметов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drugs_kit">
		<text>Drug making kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drugs_kit_descr">
		<text>Ќебольшой футл€р с различными металлическими издели€ми, предназначенными дл€ изготовлени€ наркотических препаратов. Ќекоторые пластиковые упаковки содержат таблетки и непон€тные травы.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] high value\n%c[255,238,153,26] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] используетс€ при создании предметов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_stash">
		<text>Stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_stash_of_character">
		<text>Stalker's stash: %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kerosinka">
		<text>Kerosene lamp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_glowstick_descr">
		<text>√енерирует свет при протекании химической реакции. ’имические источники света широко примен€ютс€ сталкерами в качестве автономных источников света при различных чрезвычайных ситуаци€х и прочих случа€х, когда нет доступа к другим осветител€м. Ѕудучи полностью автономными, прочными, пожаробезопасными, водонепроницаемыми и пригодными дл€ долгого хранени€, их диапазон применени€ оказываетс€ крайне высок.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] неограниченное врем€ работы</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_glowstick">
		<text>Glowstick</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_lighter_descr">
		<text>ћеталлическа€ бензинова€ ветрозащищЄнна€ зажигалка, котора€ производитс€ компанией Zippo Manufacturing Company в Ѕрэдфорде. ћодельный р€д зажигалок Zippo представл€ет собой тыс€чи разных моделей и разновидностей, производимых компанией с 1933 года, которые отличаютс€ металлом, способом его обработки, оформлением и рисунками, наносимыми на зажигалки. ƒовольно попул€рна здесь, в силу своей надЄжности, но встретить в «оне оригинал — больша€ удача, чаще всего попадаютс€ дешЄвые подделки.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] does not require seasoning</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_lighter">
		<text>Lighter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dynamo_hand_descr">
		<text>—амодельные динамо-машинки редко встретишь - сталкеры предпочитают носить пару компактных запасных батареек. Ќо в лагере, когда вопрос объЄма и массы экипировки не стоит так остро, така€ штука здорово выручает, позвол€€ подзар€дить аккумул€торы всей электроники, не растрачива€сь на батарейки.\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]PROPERTIES:\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] technological item\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		Х %c[0,140,140,140] требует регул€рного обслуживани€</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dynamo_hand_name">
		<text>Dynamo-machine</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
