<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<!-- PART 1: Ask player to join --> 

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_task_name">
		<text>Help Gonta protect the camp.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_task_text1">
		<text>Wait for night to come.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_task_text2">
		<text>Join the detachment.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_task_text3">
		<text>Empty out the bandit camp.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_task_text4">
		<text>Talk to Gonta.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_actor0A">
		<text>Hello, guys. Why the serious mood?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_actor0B">
		<text>Well, whats the mood like?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_text1A">
		<text>Try and have some fun here… We’ve been here for a long time, helped other in peace, helped newcomers to the Zone to survive.. all was fine until the bandits came around. I think its time to finally rid ourselves of this mess. But.. there is only three of us and I am very worried, we cannot do this on our own. Will you be willing to join us? We need to act quickly before they gather more people.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_text1B">
		<text>Have you decided to go with us while we still have the chance?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_actor1A">
		<text>Yes, no matter what, I’m with you!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_actor1B">
		<text>No, I can’t now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_text2A">
		<text>Here’s our man! Excellent! Now, let us prepare slowly - rest, check our equipment. We shall strike when it’s dark, it would be best by midnight. We’ll give them a taste of their own medicine..</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_text2B">
		<text>I understand. Come with us if you decide to.</text>
	</string>


	<!-- PART 2: Ready, set, go! -->

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_text3A">
		<text>Well, will we get going?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_text3B">
		<text>My hands are itching.. But its early, we must wait.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_text3C">
		<text>Now is not the time to chat!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_actor3A">
		<text>Ready? GO!</text>
	</string>


	<!-- PART 3A: Grand Finale -->

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_complete1">
		<text>This is great! I’ve just gotten information that there’s no more bandits in the camp! How many of them were there? A dozen.. more? And they all fell? For such a miracle, take this gift from me, its not every day that something like this happens in the Zone!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_complete2">
		<text>Thank you for your support, next time they’ll think before crossing us. Here, for your soul.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_complete3">
		<text>Go on, in peace.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_complete4">
		<text>You ran off and snitched, huh? Do you think we wouldn’t notice how the bandits behaved after your arrival? You’re a rat! </text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_gonta_quest_actor4Ñ">
		<text>So did I…</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_task_name">
		<text>Help the bandits.</text>
	</string>


	<!-- PART 3B: TOP 10 ANIME BETRAYALS -->

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_task_text">
		<text>Kill Gonta.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_task_complete">
		<text>You’re a serial killer! All I can say is well done. If you need to lay down or relax you can head down to our base not far from here, I’ll tell our boys not to touch you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_actor0">
		<text>Hey, bro, here, this info is interesting.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest01">
		<text>Well, come on, interested in the info?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest011">
		<text>In short, I heard that there were problems with the nearby stalkers, so they decided to gather people for a raid.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest012">
		<text>You know, its not that important, forget it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest0111">
		<text>Here’s the fucking bitch! I talked to them, no need to wait - just kick them over. And here, for you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest0121">
		<text>Get out of here, clown!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest01111">
		<text>Maybe you need some help?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest01112">
		<text>No problem, I was happy to help.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds2_antigonta_quest_quest011111">
		<text>Oh so we have a saboteur? That’s just it, a light on the crossing, and get there quickly and we’ll talk.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
