<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>

	<string id="st_loadout1_caption">
		<text>Points used:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout2_caption">
		<text>Points available:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_points">
		<text>%c[0,93,0,116] • %c[0,170,170,170] Points required: </text>
	</string>


	<string id="st_loadout_1">
		<text>Basic equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_1_descr">
		<text>\n \nA simple leather jacket and an old shotgun is the bare minimum required to protect oneself from the surrounding reality. By examining the contents in the jacket, one may find a rag mask, a torch, and a pack of cigarettes. Barebones, but better than nothing.\n \n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_2">
		<text>Additional weapon set</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_2_descr">
		<text>\n \nA good old-fashioned AKS-74U with magazines, several grenades, and a high-quality knife; all constituting a versatile set of weaponry against any living, breathing threat.\n \n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_3">
		<text>Provisional and medicinal set</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_3_descr">
		<text>\n \nA small supply of food and medicine, designed for surviving in and adapting to the first few days in a health-threatening environment. Includes several cans of food, a first aid kit, bandages, anti-radiation pills, a pack of activated carbon, and a bottle of home-brewed beverage.\n \n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_4">
		<text>Artefact hunting kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_4_descr">
		<text>\n \nAn equipment kit necessary for exploring anomalous areas: a gas mask, a geiger counter, an artefact detector, a lead container, and, of course, a capacious backpack. The rest depends on the skill and ingenuity of the wearer themselves.\n \n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_5">
		<text>Beginner technician’s kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_5_descr">
		<text>\n \nA kit for those who regret any time spent without having repaired or dismantled something. A basic set of tools, a tube of quality glue, a little oil, and blue electrical tape; a set for any self-respecting technician.\n \n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_6">
		<text>Experienced stalker kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_6_descr">
		<text>\n \nA strong outfit with excellently balanced properties. The death of the suit’s two previous owners has, fortunately, not affected its appearance or condition, and for your lack of disgust and any prejudice, the local trader has offered a capable flashlight.\n \n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_7">
		<text>Mercenary equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_7_descr">
		<text>\n \nA favorable suit of armor with different kinds of pockets and pouches for storing a variety of small objects. Sowing batteries, silenced pistol, radio components, a torn page from a magazine, and an old lighter; it is unclear how keeping all this garbage to yourself would be of any use. On the other hand, something could come in handy for the future.\n \n</text>
	</string>


	<!-- 20 -->

	<string id="st_loadout_8">
		<text>Skill: Master of the blade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_8_descr">
		<text>\n \nThe arme blanche has always attracted you; its even, metallic gloss has a calming effect. Firearms are a convenient option, of course, but with a knife in your hand, you feel complete.\n \n</text><!--Урон от быстрого удара ножом существенно увеличен.\n \n-->
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_9">
		<text>Skill: Inventor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_9_descr">
		<text>\n \nAs a child, you assembled a radio from old parts in your father’s toolbox. In your youth, you repaired your motorcycle with spare parts from a flea market. Now, you feel that you will find some use in the technical debris lying in the Exclusion Zone.\n \n</text><!--Количество доступных для создания предметов увеличено.\n \n-->
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_10">
		<text>Skill: Strong stomach</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_10_descr">
		<text>\n \nTasty, high-quality food in the Zone is a rarity, and what stalkers usually eat is hard to consider healthy, but you are able to consume and digest what any other person in their right mind wouldn’t even consider having a bite of.\n \n</text><!--Меньший вред здоровью при употреблении вредной пищи.\n \n-->
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_11">
		<text>Skill: Lead backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_11_descr">
		<text>\n \nThe gifts of the Zone are alluring but extremely dangerous. Not so long ago, you acquired a special backpack, which should be able to neutralize some of their radiation. The time has come to put it to use.\n \n</text><!--Снижено радиактивное излучение артефактов, находящихся в рюкзаке.\n \n-->
	</string>


	<!-- 30 -->

	<string id="st_loadout_12">
		<text>Skill: Steady hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_12_descr">
		<text>\n \nIn whatever condition you find yourself in, whether it be in emotional shock, a wild hangover, or a small earthquake while traveling on public transport, your hand never falters. The grip on your weapon is strong enough to leave dents on the handguard and stock.\n \n</text>
		<!--
		Пугливый взгляд, трясущиеся руки, странная осанка
		
		Вид человека, крепко удерживающего взведнённое оружие, может произвести неизгладимое впечатление. Новички с трясущимися руками могут попасть куда угодно, кроме цели. Бесхребетные трусы готовы бросить всё и бежать, в надежде спасти свою шкуру, лишь бы не услышать звука ответного выстрела.
		
		Вы же никогда не выроните Ваше оружие. Ваши руки никогда не дрогнут от выстрела. Люди никогда не перестанут удивляться вмятинам на цевье и прикладе.
		
		
		
		В моменты эмоциональных потрясений, во время движения в общественном транспорте, в похмельные периоды после самых громких гулянок - ваши руки никогда не дрожат. 
		Пусть за вмятины на цевье и прикладе над вами немного подшучивают, но в бою ваша особенность 
		-->
		<!--Отдача при стрельбе из стрелкового оружия ощутимо снижена.\n \n-->
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_13">
		<text>Skill: Butcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_13_descr">
		<text>\n \nYour presence instils fear into the creatures of the Zone; to little surprise, because you are the last thing they see in their life in the vast majority of cases. Having learned how to deal with the carcass of a mutant after an encounter, people begin to fear you.\n \n</text><!--Более быстрое и эффективное использование ножа при разделке дичи.\n \n-->
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_14">
		<text>Skill: Authority</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_14_descr">
		<text>\n \nWhether through charm, a natural ability to socialize, or perhaps a subtle knowledge of human psychology; it does not matter. You easily win the hearts of any person, whether it be a greedy huckster or an outspoken psychopath.\n \n</text><!--Количество напарников увеличено, более эффективная методика допросов, репутация копится значительно быстрее, больше возможностей в диалогах.\n \n-->
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_15">
		<text>Skill: Mindfulness</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_15_descr">
		<text>\n \nYou have learned to notice the most insignificant details not only in the behavior of people, but also in the surrounding environment. During searches, not a single kopeck, bolt, or person manages hides from you…\n \n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_loadout_16">
		<text>Skill: Geologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_16_descr">
		<text>\n \nHumming, hissing, spitting; no types of anomalies are capable of intimidating you any longer, and your urge for exploration encourages you to travel to areas filled with them.\n \n</text>
	</string>

	<!--
	<string id="st_loadout_9">
		<text>Skill: Механик</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_9_descr">
		<text>\n \nописание st_loadout_9_descr</text>
	</string>
	-->

	<!--
	<string id="st_loadout_12">
		<text>Skill: Гурман</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loadout_12_descr">
		<text>\n \nВы не любите есть, вы любите чувствовать вкус. Чувство насыщения придёт быстрее, если пищу употребить правильным образом. Вы же способны превратить этот процесс в тонкое искусство, даже если на вашей тарелке лежит лишь кусок сухаря.</text>
	</string>
	-->

</string_table>