<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="not_enough_money_actor">
		<text>Not enough money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="not_enough_money_partner">
		<text>The character does not have enough money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quick_use_str_1">
		<text>$$ACTION_QUICK_USE_1$$</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quick_use_str_2">
		<text>$$ACTION_QUICK_USE_2$$</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quick_use_str_3">
		<text>$$ACTION_QUICK_USE_3$$</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quick_use_str_4">
		<text>$$ACTION_QUICK_USE_4$$</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_activate_artefact">
		<text>activate artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_attach_gl_to_rifle">
		<text>attach grenade launcher to</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_attach_scope_to_pistol">
		<text>attach scope to</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_attach_silencer_to_pistol">
		<text>attach suppressor to</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_base_cost">
		<text>Price</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_community">
		<text>Group:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition">
		<text>Condition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detach_gl">
		<text>detach grenade launcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detach_scope">
		<text>detach scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detach_silencer">
		<text>detach suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dress_outfit">
		<text>wear suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drop">
		<text>drop</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drop_all">
		<text>drop all</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_eat">
		<text>eat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perc">
		<text>%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_perc_min">
		<text>%/min</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kg">
		<text>kg</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_g">
		<text>g</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kcal">
		<text>kcal eq.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kcal_sec">
		<text>kcal / sec eq.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_msv">
		<text>mSv</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_msv_sec">
		<text>mSv / sec</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_microg">
		<text>Âµg of adren.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_microg_sec">
		<text>Âµg of adren. / sec</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ml_min">
		<text>ml / min</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kw_m2">
		<text>kW/m2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kv">
		<text>kV</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mt">
		<text>mT</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ppm">
		<text>C1 ppm eq.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_j">
		<text>H/mm2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_move_on_belt">
		<text>attach to belt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_move_to_bag">
		<text>move to bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_unequip">
		<text>unequip</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_move_to_slot">
		<text>equip</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_no_trade_tip_1">
		<text>The trader is not interested in items like this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_no_trade_tip_2">
		<text>The item is too damaged to be traded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_play">
		<text>play</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sell_item">
		<text>sell item</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_armor_static">
		<text>Armour condition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_main_sensor">
		<text>Ionizing radiation poisoning\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Exposure to ionizing radiation poses an extremely high risk to the USS operative. For this reason, every member of USS personnel is required to undergo training which provides them with the ability to adequately measure radiation levels. This skill becomes a key factor in their effectiveness within the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone. The basic unit in the scale of ionizing radiation is millisievert %c[0,210,210,210](mSv)%c[0,170,170,170]. Level of approximately %c[0,210,210,210]8000 mSv %c[0,170,170,170]is usually lethal without a chance of recovery. Radiation levels above the threshold of 1000 mSv (see below) may gradually negatively impact USS operative's performance. In case of exposure, it is thus strongly advised to administer anti-radiation drugs of appropriate potency as soon as possible. Table 3.2 presents radiation levels with typical symptoms:\n \n%c[0,102,255,0]250 - 1500 mSv: %c[0,140,140,140]Symptoms are unnoticeable. Long term consequences are negligible.\n \n%c[0,255,255,0]1500 - 3000 mSv: %c[0,140,140,140]Noticeable moderate to strong sickness, light-headedness, skin stains. Long-term symptoms are mild. Full recovery is possible if treated promptly.\n \n%c[0,255,122,0]3000 - 4500 mSv: %c[0,140,140,140]Very strong sickness, confusion and dizziness leading to premature death if not treated in relatively short time. Complete cease of hunger and thirst, taint, diarrhoea, peeling of skin and hair loss. High risk of permanent loss of reproduction ability. Restoration of bodily functions is feasible with extensive use of cleansing agents.\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]4500 - 6000 mSv: %c[0,140,140,140]Intensification of the above symptoms. Additionally, permanent damage to central nervous system. Death highly probable.\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]6000 mSv and above: %c[0,140,140,140]Imminent death. Often after rapid loss of consciousness.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] unit: %c[0,170,170,170]mSv (milisivert)\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] imminent lethal radiation: %c[0,170,170,170]~6000+ mSv\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] av. outside rad. hot-spots potency: %c[0,170,170,170]~900 mSv / min\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_undress_outfit">
		<text>remove suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_unload_magazine">
		<text>unload</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_use">
		<text>use</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_item_place">
		<text>place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_item_pour"> 
		<text>pour</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_item_sort">
		<text>sort</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_item_dismantle">
		<text>disassemble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b32_scanner_place">
		<text>place scanner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_weight">
		<text>Wgt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_ammo_count">
		<text>Mag. size</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_accuracy">
		<text>Accuracy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_ammo_pistol">
		<text>Buy basic ammo for pistol (Q)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_ammo_rifle">
		<text>Buy rifle ammo (W)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_bleeding">
		<text>Bleeding control</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_cancel">
		<text>Cancel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_cant_buy_item">
		<text>Cannot buy weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_count_restr">
		<text>Amount restrictions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_damage">
		<text>Damage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_default(F5)">
		<text>Default (F5)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_exit">
		<text>Back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_granadelauncher_rifle">
		<text>Buy under-barrel grenade launcher for rifle (D)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_granades_rifle">
		<text>Buy under-barrel grenade launcher grenades (E)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_reliablility">
		<text>Reliability</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_handling">
		<text>Handling</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_condition">
		<text>Condition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_has">
		<text>Now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_health">
		<text>Health restoration</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_heavy_weapons">
		<text>Heavy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_last_buy">
		<text>Buy last purchased loadout</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_last_buy(F4)">
		<text>Previous (F4)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_money">
		<text>Money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_need">
		<text>Required</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_not_enought_money">
		<text>Not enough money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_ok">
		<text>Okay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_additional_weight">
		<text>Weight carried</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_burn_protection">
		<text>Thermal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_chemical_burn_protection">
		<text>Chemical</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_fire_wound_protection">
		<text>Armour</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_radiation_protection">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_shock_protection">
		<text>Shock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_telepatic_protection">
		<text>Psionic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_wound_protection">
		<text>Wound</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_burn_protection">
		<text>Protection against thermal radiation\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]A typical fire anomaly in the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone is composed of two separate elements: %c[0,170,170,170]hemisphere-shaped thermal radiation field %c[0,170,170,170]- producing constant flux of density up to %c[0,210,210,210]50 kW / m2%c[0,170,170,170], inducing temperatures of up to %c[0,210,210,210]430 Â°C%c[0,170,170,170], and %c[0,210,210,210]'burner anomalies' -%c[0,170,170,170] destructive emissions of flames of up to %c[0,210,210,210]1000 Â°C%c[0,170,170,170] launching upwards from a single point usually located approx. 10 cm above the ground. For the purposes of assessment of Exclusion Zone's fire anomalies and in order to indicate available counter-measures a %c[0,210,210,210]kW/m2%c[0,170,170,170] (kilowatts per square meter equivalents) scale is used. This unit indicates a density of heat flux generated by the anomaly and thus the volume of energy.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] inside an average campfire: %c[0,170,170,170]500 Â°C or 29 kW/m2\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] average thermal rad. field flux: %c[0,170,170,170]620 Â°C or 51,5 kW/m2\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] average burner outburst: %c[0,170,170,170]1000 Â°C or 212 kW/m2\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] approx. unprotected survival time: %c[0,170,170,170]RF: 1,5 min / BU: 0,5 sec\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] approx. complete armor degr. time: %c[0,170,170,170]RF: 10 min / BU: 6 sec\n \n
		%c[0,140,140,140]RF = radiation field ; BU = 'burner anomaly'\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]2. Acid\n \n
		%c[0,170,170,170]It is common knowledge that potent pools of acid (called 'fruit punch anomalies') can be found within Exclusion Zone's areas of high toxicity ('toxic anomalies'). These gravitationally sustained 'tanks' are extremely unstable and lose their form the moment they come in contact with solid matter. Any such occurrence produces a powerful outburst equivalent to the use of up to %c[0,210,210,210]0,5 liters%c[0,170,170,170] of potent oxidizing agents / sulphuric acid of %c[0,210,210,210]50%%c[0,170,170,170] condensation. These outbursts entail the eruption of liquid solution which spreads in a form of droplets launching upwards in approximately %c[0,210,210,210]2-meter%c[0,170,170,170] radius. In order to facilitate comparison, the potency of acids is usually measured in thermal radiation scale of %c[0,210,210,210]kW / m2%c[0,170,170,170] equivalents.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] average potency of 'fruit punch' droplet: %c[0,170,170,170]270 Â°C or 70 kW/m2 eq.\n \n \n</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_chemical_burn_protection">
		<text>Protection against toxicity\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Due to the not yet fully grasped nature of substances found inside the so called %c[0,210,210,210]'toxic anomalies'%c[0,170,170,170], danger assessment has to be performed in compliance with universal %c[0,210,210,210]LC50 (human)%c[0,170,170,170] standard.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]This standard measures overall toxicity of gaseous agents based on their level of concentration and indicates the dose which is required to kill %c[0,210,210,210]50%%c[0,170,170,170] of any random human 'test group' during exposure lasting %c[0,210,210,210]1 hour%c[0,170,170,170].\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]As in most cases it only takes 10 parts per million %c[0,210,210,210](ppm)%c[0,170,170,170] condensation for Exclusion Zone's anomalous, bio-chemical agents to exceed %c[0,210,210,210]50% / 1 h%c[0,170,170,170] fatality rate, it is justified to include them in %c[0,210,210,210]Class I (C1) group%c[0,170,170,170] which comprises most potent toxic substances known to science. Exclusion Zone's anomalous toxic areas have been proven to have average concentration of as much as %c[0,210,210,210]C1 200 ppm%c[0,170,170,170] (parts per million), whereas '200' denotes the number of 'parts' (particles) of typical Class I substance diluted in 1,000,000 parts of the solution. This level of toxicity makes the Exclusion Zone's anomalies one of the most hazardous environments on the planet, strong enough to kill an average human being not protected with scientific equipment in about %c[0,210,210,210]3 minutes%c[0,170,170,170].\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]For this reason and for assessment purposes, potency of anomalous areas and effectiveness of protective gear is graded based on the amount of parts of Class I %c[0,210,210,210](C1)%c[0,170,170,170] toxic substance per million parts %c[0,210,210,210](ppm)%c[0,170,170,170] of the solution. This approach results in an universal 'anomalous' toxicity unit of %c[0,210,210,210]C1 ppm equivalent%c[0,170,170,170]. In case of equipment, this value indicates the C1 ppm toxicity concentration which a certain item is able to protect from.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] av. toxic anomaly potency: %c[0,170,170,170]~200 C1 ppm eq.\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] max. registered toxic anomaly potency: %c[0,170,170,170]~600 C1 ppm eq.\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] av. unprot. survival time: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 min \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] av. time for compl. suit degr.: %c[0,170,170,170]~25 min.\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_fire_wound_protection">
		<text>Armor protection level\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Armor protection level indicates %c[0,210,210,210]anti-ballistic%c[0,170,170,170] properties of a certain piece of body armor. For assessment purposes, we use an internationally-recognized, American National Institute of Justice (NIJ) system of graduation of protective clothing based on a level of firearm projectile energy a certain piece is able to withstand.\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]ARMOR GRADATION CHART:\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]CLASS I:%c[0,170,170,170] 12x70 shot, grenade shrapnel\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]CLASS IIA and II:%c[0,170,170,170] 9x18 mm, 9x18 mm +P+, 9x19 mm FMJ, 9x19 JHP, 45 ACP\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]CLASS IIIA:%c[0,170,170,170] 357 HP, 45 Hydro, 5.56x45 mm FNJ\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]CLASS III%c[0,170,170,170] 9x18 mm AP, 9x19 mm AP, 7.62x39 mm FMJ, 7.92x33 mm FMJ, 5.45x39 mm FNJ, 12x76 slug\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]CLASS IV:%c[0,170,170,170] 9x39 mm SP-5, 7.62x51 mm NATO, .300 Win Mag, 45 AP, 7.92x33 mm AP\n \n
		%c[0,210,210,210]CLASS V (exoskeleton):%c[0,170,170,170] 5.45x39 AP, 5.56x45 AP, 7.62x39 mm AP, 7.62x51 mm NATO AP, 7.62x54 PP, 9x39 mm SP-6, 7.62x54 mm 7H1\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]IMPORTANT:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]The above-mentioned protection levels only relate to counter-penetration properties of armor. Bullet impact, even if it does not manage to pierce the armor, is still capable of inflicting damage by means of %c[0,210,210,210]blunt trauma%c[0,170,170,170] due to pure kinetic energy of the bullet. Most commonly the effect of the impact is only edema of soft tissues, but in certain cases and if the force is strong enough it can lead to open %c[0,210,210,210]bone fractures%c[0,170,170,170] causing a bleeding wound which, if untreated, can result in death. Suits augmented with %c[0,210,210,210]metal%c[0,170,170,170] (especially titanium or steel) significantly reduce the probability of open bone fractures and overall negative effects of bullet impact.\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_radiation_protection">
		<text>Protection from external radiation sources\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Current readings indicate that radiation most commonly encountered in the Exclusion Zone travels by means of solid %c[0,210,210,210]alpha %c[0,170,170,170]particles which are present in dirt, sand, water and other objects and thus in all organisms living in the area for prolonged periods of time. Such radiation cannot penetrate the skin and is harmful only if charged particles come into direct contact with tissues and make their way into the bloodstream - for example through the inhalation of air polluted with dust or by eating contaminated food. For this reason, it is strongly advised to wear a filtered breathing apparatus in the Exclusion Zone at all times and avoid reliance on local food and water sources.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]As for penetrating %c[0,210,210,210]beta%c[0,170,170,170] radiation - our data confirm that it is still mostly concentrated around the CPP Unit 4 sarcophagus. However, it has been recently found that certain species within the Exclusion Zone emit penetrating ionizing radiation field at close range. For reasons unknown, effects of this field cease as soon as the creature dies.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]The final and the most dangerous source of ionizing radiation within the Exclusion Zone are surge emissions during which gamma blasts of various potency have been detected. Due to the amount of pure energy released and the penetrating power of gamma radiation, it is highly recommended to take cover in safe locations whenever an emission occurs.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140]cloth mask protection rate: %c[0,170,170,170]45%\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140]breathing filters protection rate: %c[0,170,170,170]90%\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140]environmental suit protection rate: %c[0,170,170,170]100%\n \n
		%c[0,204,0,51]IMPORTANT:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]All suits and headgear have undergone heavy field testing against all types of radiation. Results of these tests have been included in the manual, but should be regarded as incomplete and provide only rough guidelines.\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_shock_protection">
		<text>Protection against electric shock\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Electrical anomalies of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone are undoubtedly one of its potentially most beneficial creations. Powerful and constant electric arcs stretched in what appears to be a simple composition of gases could, if harnessed, provide enormous amounts of pure energy. Unfortunately, all attempts to obtain electricity from these anomalies were to no avail since they are extremely unstable and any contact with solid matter results in massive outbursts of energy. Such phenomena are unheard of in modern science as our sensors have registered a sudden rise in both voltage and current that would cause any capacitors currently produced to overheat due to the erratic nature of the anomaly.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Voltage peaks produced during such outbursts amount to %c[0,210,210,210]4,0 megavolts (MV)%c[0,170,170,170], which allows the current to reach as high as %c[0,210,210,210]3,5 meters%c[0,170,170,170] above the ground. Since the outbursts last around %c[0,210,210,210]50 milliseconds%c[0,170,170,170], energy produced inside the anomaly per one outburst is often not enough to kill a healthy grown man. However, extensive health damage and severe trauma should be expected and the second outburst (which is very likely to occur if one does not exit the field promptly) is in most cases fatal.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]As is the case with all static electrical discharges, the best means of protection is increasing electrical resistance of the body. This can be achieved in several ways, primarily by wearing protective, non-conductive clothing.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]For the purposes of USS operations in the Exclusion Zone, effectiveness of all means of electrical resistance and combat armors is measured in the number of kilovolts %c[0,210,210,210](kV)%c[0,170,170,170] a given piece of equipment is able to resist during a single %c[0,210,210,210]3000 kV%c[0,170,170,170] / %c[0,210,210,210]50 ms%c[0,170,170,170] outburst of an electrical anomaly.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] av. electrical anomaly power: %c[0,170,170,170]~3 MV\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] single outburst dam. rate to unprot. body: %c[0,170,170,170]95%\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_telepatic_protection">
		<text>Protection against psy-influence\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Scientific data regarding the origin and nature of so called 'psy fields' found quite commonly inside the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone is %c[0,204,0,51]classified%c[0,170,170,170] and not relevant to this mission.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]It is, however, essential for any USS operative to be aware of the fact that these forces pose an extreme danger to any human being and should be avoided at all costs. Such fields ordinarily take a hemispherical shape with the source at their centre. Of note is that they are able to either immediately kill or induce an unrecoverable coma within seconds of exposure (this applies to any human being not protected with additional equipment). The potency of psy field varies depending on the distance from the source: the weakest being at the edges of the field and increasing at a geometric rate the closer to the source.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]It has been established that beside the main 'psy radiation', each field also produces a faint, low frequency %c[0,210,210,210](50-60 Hz)%c[0,170,170,170] magnetic field which seems completely harmless; this field can be easily detected and measured for the purposes of assessment of the psy field's main strength. Potency of psy fields (and effectiveness of counter-measures) is given in milliteslas %c[0,210,210,210](mT)%c[0,170,170,170] which indicate the intensity of an accompanying magnetic field.\n \n%c[0,210,210,210]KNOWN SOURCES:\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] surge emission: %c[0,170,170,170]35 mT (constant flux) ; 660 mT (blowout wave) \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] average psy anomaly: %c[0,170,170,170]E 3mT ; C 45 mT\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] controller mutant: %c[0,170,170,170]E 5 mT ; C 75 mT ; R 33 m\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] poltergeist mutant: %c[0,170,170,170]E 8 mT ; C 90 mT ; R 52 m\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] burer mutant: %c[0,170,170,170]E 2 mT ; C 50 mT ; R 26 m\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] psy-dog mutant: %c[0,170,170,170]E 0.1 mT ; C 15 mT ; R 23 m\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] Yantar complex (inactive): %c[0,170,170,170]E 0.001 mT ; C 1800 mT (est.) ; R ~3,5 km\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] 'Brain scorcher' (inactive): %c[0,170,170,170]E 0.001 mT ; C 6500 mT (est.) ; R ~20 km\n \n%c[0,140,140,140]E = edge of the field\n%c[0,140,140,140]C = epicenter of the field\n%c[0,140,140,140]R = range\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_wound_protection">
		<text>Rupture protection\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Rupture protection level remains a significant factor when operating within the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone and must not be underestimated. This is due to often extremely aggressive and carnivorous fauna which has mutated excessively owing to the special characteristics of the Exclusion Zone.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]The collective term %c[0,210,210,210]'mutants'%c[0,170,170,170] refers to beings of animal and possibly human origin which are the outcome of this abnormal evolution. They can take a variety of shapes and forms depending on their progenitor and the extent of mutation - and have at their disposal several means of inflicting damage and killing their prey. Common types of attacks include biting, cutting the skin and clothing with sharp claws, stabbing with protruding fangs, charging at the prey, as well as kicks and punches.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]The most popular means of protection against this threat is using clothing manufactured in such a way so as to make it virtually impenetrable by animal attacks. Although normally even a thin layer of protective material can keep you out of harm's way, in the Exclusion Zone it is advisable to use only specially designed anti-laceration fibers.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Rupture protection values of a certain armor piece are in direct connection to its anti-ballistic protection class. This is especially true of any NIJ %c[0,210,210,210]Class AIII%c[0,170,170,170] and above which have a large number of integrated %c[0,210,210,210]metal plates%c[0,170,170,170].\n \n%c[0,204,0,51]IMPORTANT:\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Even though clothing of high durability and thickness can significantly reduce damage inflicted by firearm projectiles and animal attacks of all kinds, the materials the clothing is made of are not indestructible and will slowly degrade, gradually decreasing its environmental and physical protection values. The rate at which armor degrades %c[0,210,210,210]is not a constant value%c[0,170,170,170] and depends on the condition of the unit, which means that %c[0,210,210,210]the condition of equipment will deteriorate the faster the more damaged the equipment is.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]For this reason, it is %c[0,210,210,210]strongly advised%c[0,170,170,170] to undertake maintenance of suits and headgear as frequently as possible and to avoid taking severe, structural damage.\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_power">
		<text>Energy recovery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_power_restore">
		<text>Energy recovery\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Your energy/stamina level represents available physical energy stored in the body. This energy is used for a variety of purposes, most notably running, and severe loss of stamina may make you unable to move. It is thus vital to eat, drink and sleep to regain your energy, and to check the weight of your backpack, as the amount you carry influences the rate at which you get tired. Drugs and artefacts can provide a boost to energy recovery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_preset1(F1)">
		<text>Loadout 1 (F1)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_preset2(F2)">
		<text>Loadout 2 (F2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_preset3(F3)">
		<text>Loadout 3 (F3)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_radiation">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_rank_restr">
		<text>Rank restriction</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_rate_of_fire">
		<text>Fire rate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_reset_items(C)">
		<text>Clear (C)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_rifles">
		<text>Assault rifles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_satiety">
		<text>Hunger elimination</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_scope_rifle">
		<text>Buy optical scope for rifle (S)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_sell_items(X)">
		<text>Sell all items in backpack (X)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_shotguns">
		<text>Rifles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_silencer_pistol">
		<text>Buy suppressor for pistol (A)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_silencer_rifle">
		<text>Buy suppressor for rifle (F)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_sniper_rifles">
		<text>Sniper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_time">
		<text>Time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_you_already_have">
		<text>Already got one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_err_gs_not_available">
		<text>Online S.T.A.L.K.E.R. services are not accessible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_err_sb_master_server_conn_fail">
		<text>Cannot connect to master server.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_outfit_protect">
		<text>Protection:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_preset_def">
		<text>Default</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_preset_stored_to">
		<text>Purchased loadout saved as</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_total_weight">
		<text>Total weight:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drink">
		<text>drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_power_restore">
		<text>Energy recovery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_bleeding_sensor">
		<text>Bleeding\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Bleeding can drain vital power at a very fast rate if not treated promptly. Bleeding wounds are most often the result of external physical force of any type penetrating the body armor and rupturing the skin, and are sometimes accompanied by damage to internal organs. Bleeding can also be the effect of open bone fractures caused by blunt trauma.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]The average USS operator can withstand blood loss of up to approximately %c[0,210,210,210]2.7 liters %c[0,170,170,170]without losing consciousness. Extremely serious (or a large number of smaller) wounds can cause blood loss of this magnitude in %c[0,210,210,210]5 to 10 minutes%c[0,170,170,170]. Bandages or field wound sewing kits can effectively stop the bleeding, while drugs increasing blood density or coagulating agents can be used to reduce the overall rate of bleeding.\n \n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] body blood volume: %c[0,170,170,170]~5,5 liters\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] deadly blood loss: %c[0,170,170,170]~2,7 liters\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] 5.45 cal. shot to unprot. torso: %c[0,170,170,170]~320 ml / min\n%c[0,153,255,255] 
		• %c[0,140,140,140] bandage effectiveness: %c[0,170,170,170]~270 ml / min \n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Chart:\n \n%c[0,102,255,0]0 - 100 ml / min: %c[0,140,140,140] mild\n%c[0,255,255,0]100 - 200 ml / min: %c[0,140,140,140]significant\n%c[0,255,122,0]200 - 300 ml / min: %c[0,140,140,140] severe\n%c[0,204,0,51]300+ ml / min: %c[0,140,140,140]critical\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_weight">
		<text>Maximum weight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_health_sensor">
		<text>Health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_health_sensor_inv">
		<text>Health\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]What is known as overall health could be better described as the %c[0,210,210,210]ability and will %c[0,170,170,170]to live and keep moving forward no matter the circumstances. The Zone is an unforgiving place. Although the saying "abandon all hope you who enter here" does not quite apply here, you should never expect anyone to offer you a helping hand. You're on your own and if you fail, chances are you'll die a miserable death. Thank the mutants, the weather, emissions or the Zone itself for that, but remember: it's your fault, you're to blame, and it's up to you survive. No matter how you look at it, it's the law of nature: survival of the fittest. Those who aren't cut out for this line of work will without a doubt die, and those with more perseverance will live to see another day.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]While a superficial gunshot wound won't immobilize you completely, it certainly causes %c[0,210,210,210]pain%c[0,170,170,170], and pain is dangerous: it may make your body %c[0,210,210,210]stop functioning%c[0,170,170,170]. Shock, loss of consciousness and physical burnout may follow and then you're as good as dead, so tread carefully.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Neither armor and equipment can protect you from all dangers nor are items the most important factor in your survival. It's the mind. It's precisely the mind that gives you willpower to withstand the pressure of the Zone and determination to pursue your goals. However, mind is not a constant, it's a variable. It changes depending on the circumstances. Psychological trauma makes you weak and drains your health. This is especially true of occurrences of immense potency like emissions or anomalies. On the other hand, you can strengthen your mind by eating, drinking, sleeping, in a word: %c[0,210,210,210]by taking care of yourself%c[0,170,170,170]. You can also engage in certain activities to keep your spirit alive, and take various performance-enhancing substances if things go that far.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Even if you fail, you can at least be sure you did all you could, as small as a consolation that may be. You're just a corpse after all, a feast for crows, worms and mutants. All that remains for you is to have faith in your comrades, in those who didn't commit the same mistakes, in those who are still alive.\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_stamina_sensor_inv"> 
		<text>Satiety\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]Hunger is the state of the body that occurs in the long absence of food as a result of the excitation of the lateral nuclei of the hypothalamus. Satisfaction gives the opposite feeling, a feeling of satiety. The body obtains the greatest efficiency when it preserves the right amount of energy, thus allowing you to withstand numerous physical activities with minimal endurance. An empty stomach will lead to a gradual depletion of the reserve of forces. The decline of sustaining substances will lead to a gradual deterioration in health, and prolonged fasting will lead to the outcome known as "starvation", and later: death.\n \n%c[0,170,170,170]\n \n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_ammo_types">
		<text>Ammo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_effect_time">
		<text>Duration</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_seconds_short">
		<text>sec</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_seconds">
		<text>seconds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_survive_surge">
		<text>Protects you from an emission or psi-storm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dress_helmet">
		<text>wear helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_undress_helmet">
		<text>remove helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_containers">
		<text>Containers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_artifacts">
		<text>Artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_container_remove">
		<text>Remove from container</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ui_container_place">
		<text>Put in container</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Call of Chernobyl -->
	<string id="st_donate">
		<text>Donate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_af_condition">
		<text>Efficiency</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_explosion_protection">
		<text>Explosion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_hit_fraction_actor">
		<text>Impenetrable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_outfit_strike_protection">
		<text>Impact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_repairable_equipment">
		<text>Repairable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_usable_parts">
		<text>Parts</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- DEAD AIR -->
	<string id="trade_dont_make">
		<text>Trading is not possible.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
